Chapter 1: Decease and Desist

"Avada Kedavra!"

Milo had just long enough to think, oh dear gods I'm going to die as his eyes reflexively slammed shut in response to the blinding green blast.

Milo waited for the inevitable.

This is what you get, he thought to himself. This is what you get for splitting the party. None of this would have happened if you'd just brought Hermione and Harry and Ron along with you, but nooooo, you had to be a hero. Of course, it wasn't entirely his fault. Sure, he'd made a few mistakes, but perhaps the fact that he'd been possessed by the memory of the most evil dark wizard the world had ever known was excuse enough. Perhaps.

Well, the gig was up now. Now that he knew he had Voldemort's teenaged spirit living in his noggin, he could take steps. Steps like preparing Protection from Evil every day, or maybe even steps like checking himself into a prison for the time being, where the guards could keep an eye on him.

He wondered what Azkaban was like this time of year. Or, really, what Azkaban was like at all. He'd only ever heard passing remarks to it, usually fearful whispers.

Milo had been waiting for quite some time before he was struck by a rather curious thought:

Hey. Shouldn't I be dead now? What gives?

"Oy!" he said. "Let's get this over with, already!"

It was the distinct lack of response that clued Milo off to the fact that something was awry. Potentially extremely awry.

Milo opened his eyes.

"Ahhhh, crap."

Milo saw something worse than Voldemort, worse than the basilisk, worse than the mad, haunted eyes of Quirrell, worse than a Redcap in the forest, worse even than the Mirror of Erised. Okay, well maybe not quite worse than the Mirror. But still pretty bad.

It was the sky.

It was a perfectly ordinary sky, as far as skies go. A few clouds drifted lazily by, but they were thin and sparse, providing little shelter from the sun beating down onto the baked earth.

No, that was wrong. What he was lying on was definitely dirt.

But it wasn't remotely Earth.

For one thing, the horizon was wrong. Really, incredibly, weirdly wrong. It took him a moment, and an Intelligence check, to figure out what exactly was going on there.

When you live your entire life on what is essentially a giant ball of rock and water, you get used to a certain convex shape to your horizon. You usually don't even notice it, unless you're in an enormous prairie or looking out over the ocean. You get used to it, and treat it as the next best thing to flat.

But this place was flat. Completely flat. The result was an extremely disorienting, almost-concave sort of effect that made Milo feel a little nauseated when he looked too closely at it.

That alone was a pretty good clue as to Milo's present location.

The other thing, the thing that Milo was avoiding looking at, was also fairly definitive. It was the only thing of its kind in existence.

Milo sighed and stood up. He was wearing a plain Hogwarts uniform, but his magic gear was missing.

Best get this over with.

Milo turned around to face the truth.

Behind him was the Spire, capital 'S'. It was big on an astronomical scale. It was impossible to determine how far away it was from him, because the Spire was, near as anyone could figure, infinitely tall. This made it somewhat difficult to get any real sense of scale. Somewhere near the top—and, yes, somehow the infinitely-tall Spire had a 'top'—was Sigil, the City of Doors.

The Spire was a lot of things to a lot of people. To explorers, it was a waypoint, a sort-of compass direction. To the inhabitants of Sigil, it was home. To those who lived on the ground, it was That Great Big Eyesore Blocking My Sunrise/Sunset, Dammit.

To Milo, it was a cosmologically-big nail in his coffin.

The Spire was at the centre of the infinite expanse known as the Concordant Domain of the Outlands, the hub of the Great Wheel, the fulcrum of the Outer Planes. Surrounding the infinitely-sized disc that is the Outlands are the various heavens, hells, and in-betweens that make up the Outer Planes, i.e., the afterlifes. Afterlives? Whatever.

There were only two ways to get here: powerful magic, and...

Well.

You can probably guess what the other way is.

Milo sighed. Which afterlife you wound up in was determined by your beliefs, your actions in life, and, primarily, your alignment. Clearly, Milo must have screwed something up pretty badly to end up here in the very-Neutral Outlands rather than one of the various Good-aligned heavens.

Milo took a good look around. There really wasn't anything in view beyond rolling fields of yellowed grass, the occasional dry shrub, and, in the distance, some dead-looking mountains.

When it came down to it, there was really only one place worth going here: Sigil, City of Doors. It was said that, in Sigil, anything and everything could be a portal to anywhere—and sometimes even anywhen—provided you had the proper key. Maybe Milo could find a mortal there travelling to his particular Material Plane to get word to his old party members. If they could scrounge up enough for a True Resurrection, he could be back in action in no time. From there, he could get back to Hogwarts... somehow. He'd figure that part out, later.

Milo turned his back on the Spire and walked directly away from it, which was the fastest way to get to Sigil, ironically. As you walked further from the centre of the Outlands, you always—always—encounter a portal town, sooner or later. From the portal towns, it was a simple enough matter to reach Sigil. So Milo had read, anyway. He'd never actually been here before, thankfully.

The trick was to avoid encountering any wandering demons roaming a little far from home along the way. Or any roaming amnesiac immortals, trying to rediscover their pasts. The Outer Planes could be a little weird that way.

Milo walked on, the hot sun beating down on him as he went. In a way, this was nice. Peaceful. It had been quite some time since he'd had to cross great distances like this, except, of course, for those times he'd had to hike, half-dead, into Hogsmeade.

As the minutes turned into hours, Milo realized something: he felt great. No random aches or sores, no burn from the searing hot sun, no fatigue or exhaustion. I guess such 'perks' are reserved for the living.

As Milo walked across the cracked dirt, something seemed to loom in the distance. Specifically, something loomed ahead of him—he still hadn't quite gotten used to what was looming behind him.

It was hard to tell what it was, exactly, but there wasn't a whole heck of a lot in this Plane to encounter, so Milo assumed it to be a Portal Town of one sort or another. Hopefully one of the Good sorts.

It seemed to be miles and miles away, but whenever Milo took his eyes off of it, it appeared far, far closer, as if he had walked for hours.

Milo narrowed his eyes for a moment, thinking. Then he closed them entirely, took one step forward and—

Stubbed his toe.

He cursed and opened his eyes.

And then he gasped. If he wasn't... living-impaired, he might have forgotten to breathe. As it was, breathing was largely cosmetic, in any case.

What he'd stubbed his toe on was a staircase. The staircase was the most impressive he had ever seen, all narrow, crumbly, windy, and decidedly lacking in common safety features such as railings. On another day, Milo would have admired the sheer engineering chutzpah it displayed.

But as it was, the staircase got barely a glance.

The staircase led up a tall, sheer hill. At the top was the sort of castle that was best viewed in the night, lit up by lightning. It was a sprawling mass of towers, outbuildings, and halls that seemed to have been constructed with no particular plan in mind, but, when taken all together, and squinted at from just the right angle, still seemed completely haphazard.

It was decidedly not a Portal Town.

It was, however, very, very familiar.

That said, there wasn't anywhere else to go. Milo resolutely began climbing the staircase to a castle that could have been Hogwarts' twin brother.

If that twin had the architectural equivalent of a waxed goatee, an eyepatch, and a wicked scar, that is.

Maybe an hour later, Milo reached the point that he judged was the halfway marker. The staircase had narrowed to be barely a foot across, and any shorter, he would start having to make Balance checks to avoid falling to his... what? Doom? He wasn't entirely certain he could take damage.

Milo frowned. He was pretty sure that a staircase like this—especially this staircase, if it lead to what he suspected—shouldn't normally be left unguarded.

Milo carried on, more cautiously now.

The outer gates were wide open. Milo recognized the dull grey metal as adamantine, one of the strongest materials in the multiverse. Carved onto each of the massive double doors was a tiny pentagon, barely bigger than Milo's palm, each with an identical, highly stylized eye inscribed in it. The eyes seemed to watch him suspiciously as he passed.

Milo swallowed.

At least now he had a pretty good idea of why he hadn't wound up on one of the various heavens. A suspicion of who was responsible, at least.

The gates lead into a colossal 'courtyard' that could have swallowed most cities that Milo had seen without needing so much as a glass of water. Maybe not the cities from Harry's world. There was a winding path that led to the castle proper, and to the side, Milo could see a large lake that, like everything else here, looked suspiciously familiar. He wondered if this lake had a giant squid, too.

Milo approached the castle itself. Unlike the outer gates, these appeared to be of ordinary wood—but Milo doubted that the physical form of the gates was all that defended this castle. These were closed, but a light tap swung the perfectly-balanced gate open. The gate made no noise whatsoever as it moved on its hinges, revealing the castle inside.

The floor tiles inside the castle were all perfectly regular pentagons that—somehow—tessellated flawlessly. Staring at the join between tiles was quickly headache-inducing.

Behind him, the doors closed silently.

There was no clear source of light, but the broad, tall hallway was lit at a continuous, sleepy, just-before-sunset level of light regardless.

Just to test a hypothesis, Milo turned around and pulled on one of the door's handles. It wouldn't budge.

"Figures," he muttered.

"Shhhh!" a voice hissed. Milo nearly jumped out of his skin, whirling around, hands free of his sleeves for spellslinging.

Behind him, floating about two inches above the ground, was... a librarian. Well, an ex-librarian, Milo supposed, but he was really nobody to judge, now being an ex-Wizard. Judging by the translucency and the monochrome blue-green look, she was also a ghost, which brought up a whole slew of afterlife-related questions, primarily, how the heck could there be a ghost in the afterlife? What did it mean to be undead when the people around you were, well, dead? Between Milo and the ghost, who was more dead?

Oh, also, in addition to the bifocals, the tidy hair bun, and the immaculate robes, her fingers ended in inch-long claws.

Milo swallowed, and decided that maybe he should follow the scary librarian lady's request to be quiet.

She beckoned him with her hands, and started floating backwards down the hallway, never taking her eyes off of him.

On the one hand, she's terrifying, and this place is weird. On the other hand, I'm already dead, so... ehhh. What could possibly happen?

Milo decided to follow her. She led him through a series of twisty, windy hallways. Every here and there were doors leading into rooms, both large and small, piled high with bookshelves. Some of them contained people, and sentient beings that resembled people, and sentient beings that did not resemble people, who were diligently researching various topics. Some of the rooms had bronze plaques with labels written in Draconic, such as "Biography, Gnome, 569th-972nd Centuries After Glittergold, Prime Material #45967.2/Walnut" or "Psychometabolism, Commentary, Levels 1 through 4."

Some rooms had no books, but simply a neat, marble pedestal in the centre with an object of one variety or another. Many held weapons or pieces of armour, but it wasn't until Milo spotted one—a large bowl fashioned from a blue-green semiprecious stone—that Milo realized what they were. Each of those rooms contained a single magic item, ranging from the minor (one contained what Milo recognized as a single Quaal's Feather Token) to the epic (a ring of Univesal Energy Immunity, worth more than the combined value of Azel's capital city, Myra (City of light! City of magic!)). Milo itched to ditch the spectral librarian and make a grab for a Headband of +12 Intelligence, but decided against it when he realized the decorative suits of armour lining the halls were silently turning their helmets to watch him.

Well, thank goodness that wasn't too creepy or anything.

Instead, Milo followed the spectral librarian, trying to make as little noise as possible. Fortunately, that wasn't hard—despite being a cavernous hallway of solid stone, his boots made little to no noise against the tiled floor. Likely another enchantment, he thought.

Eventually, the spectre led him to an obsidian statue in an alcove. It had wicked, serrated horns, fangs longer than some of Milo's fingers, from which ran what looked suspiciously like real blood. The spectre gave the gargoyle statue a long look, and the statue raised into the ceiling, revealing a spiral staircase. The entire process, like everything else, was completely silent.

At the top of the staircase was a heavy wooden door. Milo reached up to knock, but it swung open just before his knuckles touched the wood.

"Hello?" Milo asked nervously.

"Come in," said a voice. It was an old voice, but old in the way that a great oak tree is old. The years added strength and wisdom like rings on a trunk.

Milo was already through the door before the speaker had finished. It wasn't that he was eager to enter; far from it. He was terrified. It was simply that he hadn't even considered doing anything but what the voice requested.

The office was simple, but, of course, it would be. The owner had no need of any physical objects, and, at this point, further decoration would serve no useful purpose.

It occurred to Milo that, perhaps, the office wasn't free of decoration. In fact, it could have been full of dancing chimpanzees and fountains of diamonds, but it would make no difference. He found that he couldn't look at anything in the room except his own feet.

"Sit down," said the voice.

Milo found himself sitting on a hard, flat chair. He licked his suddenly-dry lips, wondering what to say.

"You're likely wondering why you're here," the voice said.

"Maybe," Milo said in a small voice. "Well. No, actually. I'm not. I'm here because you brought me here." Though the why of that is a whole 'nother question...

"Good." The voice said, Milo thought he could hear the hint of a smile in the word. "Most, when first in my presence, are too occupied falling prostrate and begging forgiveness for sins and similar nonsense to actually speak the truth. But then, you are not most people, now are you?"

"If I may ask—"

"You may," the voice said, cutting Milo off. "Of course, I may not answer."

"What do you mean, I'm not most people?"

The voice fell silent for a moment. Not, Milo was sure, because it was thinking—the speaker was intelligent beyond words; he didn't need time to think. Milo would bet that the pause was for his benefit, to convey the idea that the words that followed were well thought out. "Tell me. What do you know of the nature of the Player Character and the Non-Player Character?"

Milo swallowed. "Well. Player Characters, more commonly called PCs, are... a different sort of person from NPCs. They are always sentient, most commonly humanoids. They appear sporadically throughout history in small groups, and their lives always change the world. Generally, they go on adventures, working their way up from defeating bandits to warlords to mythical monsters. NPCs... don't."

"That is only part of the story," the voice said. "The rest is only known to me and my kind. Tell me, young Wizard, did you know that, until quite recently, there were always four PCs?"

Milo shook his head.

"They appear always in groups of four," the voice continued. "When one falls, he or she either ends up here and is resurrected in short order, or disappears from the multiverse altogether and replaced by another of equivalent power."

"What do you mean by 'disappears from the multiverse?'" Milo asked.

"Poof. Gone, without trace. Bypassing the afterlife entirely. But there's more. The four PCs always—always—each follow one of four similar patterns of behaviour. We watch them quite closely. While sometimes it seems, early on, as if a set of Player Characters might deviate from the norm, shortly, cracks in their personas start to show. Either the deviant characters are quickly slain and replaced, or their behaviour patterns change to fit the mold of one of the archetypes. Among my kind, these archetypes are called the Valiant, the Mimic, the Trickster, and the Munchkin."

Milo tried to mentally take notes. It wasn't every day that he was given a dump of exposition this straight.

"The Valiant lives for action. They see battle, stubbornness, and blind courage in the face of certain defeat as the solution to any problem. The Mimic, on the other hand, is less predictable. They fall into the role of a being with the full spectrum of emotions and drives, and stay that way until they die. Adventures and heroic deeds are less important than simply living life in whichever way they so choose. The Trickster is the least predictable of all. They live," the voice became laced with disapproval, "for their own amusement. They are the sort who will Fireball a dragon just to see what happens." Sounds like Gerard, Zook, and Wellby, Milo thought to himself. Which makes me... "The Munchkin," the voice continued, "I believe needs no explanation."

"So you're saying I'm compelled by some whacked-out meta-cosmic spirit thingy to number crunch?" Milo asked. "Screw that. I do what I want."

"Which brings us to the crux of the issue," the voice said. "Milo Amastacia-Liadon. Look at me."

Milo looked up. Sitting at the desk across from him was a bony, weathered old man. He looked more than a few centuries past his prime, but his hard, angular face was set with an amount of determination and inner strength that Milo had only seen once before. He wore a purple robe decorated with golden arcane runes, and a wide-brimmed, floppy purple hat covered in stars sat on his head. A long, wispy white beard fell down below the desk, and a simple wooden staff leaned against the wall within easy reach of his seat. His eyes were a piercing blue, full of age and wisdom—and ice. His stare was so hard and cold, Milo felt like shivering.

He looked, in short, like the platonic ideal of a wizard.

Which was because that was exactly what he was.

He also could have been Dumbledore's twin. Well, his triplet, at least, Milo thought, remembering Aberforth.

Boccob, God of Magic, looked Milo dead in the eyes. "You are different, young Wizard. Unique. You are something that has never happened before."

"And what's that?" Milo didn't like the way that Boccob was staring at him, as if he was peering through a microscope at what was a particularly interesting beetle—but a beetle, nonetheless.

"You are no longer one of the four Player Characters. You were one of those who disappeared. You were replaced. The Munchkin has moved on. He is now, I believe, a Bard of rather surprising talents."

"I..." Milo felt fear grip him. He'd been prepared for a grisly death, for starvation, exposure to the elements, for injury and danger. Those were things that went with the job. But this was a fate far, far worse than death. He could barely even speak his fears aloud. "I'm an NPC?" he said in a very small, very quiet voice.

"No," Boccob said. "You are the character with no player. We do not have a word for what you are. And believe you me," Boccob's eyes flashed, "if one existed, I would know about it."

"Why are you telling me this?" Milo asked.

"As the mysterious old Wizard among mysterious old Wizards," Boccob said, "exposition is one of my chief responsibilities." The god smiled slightly. "Also, because I have a deal to offer you."

"Fire away," Milo said, curious.

"Your particular little Prime Material Plane is having some... issues. One who was never meant for that reality has barged in and caused no end of problems for the local inhabitants."

"Of course," Milo said. "I did."

"I am not referring to the world of Hogwarts and wanded magic," Boccob said, "but instead to your own plane. Your home."

Milo blinked. "What?"

"The ritual that brought you into the other reality also brought one known as Bellatrix Lestrange into yours. She wields powers unfamiliar to those of your world," Boccob's eyes flashed again, "and she cheats. She does not follow the pattern."

"But—but she's dead," Milo said. "I remember reading about it in the Prophet. She died in Azkaban. People cheered."

"She was replaced by another, who died in her place," Boccob said. "It's been done before, and it will be done again."

Milo narrowed his eyes. "Hold up. How do you know about this? Isn't it a little out of your, ah, jurisdiction?"

"Never forget, young Wizard." Boccob's voice was as still as stopped time, as hot as a storm of meteors. "I am the God of Magic. All magic."

"Right." Milo swallowed involuntarily. "Sorry. So. What's this deal you wanted to make?"

"I will send you back into the land of the living," Boccob said, "in return for one task."

Oh, goody. A quest.

"And what task is that?" Milo asked.

"Bellatrix Lestrange," Boccob said. "Find her. You have three days."

"That's it?" Milo asked. "Just... find her? I could do that with a Divination or three."

"Then you have no reason not to accept my offer, do you, young Wizard?"

Milo hesitated. "What do you want me to do once I find her?"

Boccob the Uncaring shrugged. "I'll leave that up to you."

"Why do you need me?" Milo asked. "I'm just a mid-level Wizard. You're... well, you're you."

"Ah," Boccob said. "But I am also an NPC, constrained to act within certain bounds. And besides," he smiled slightly, but it did not touch his eyes. "As the old saying goes: it takes a cheat to catch a cheat."

Milo considered the offer. Something seriously cagey was going on. Why the three day time limit? And why did Boccob want Milo to find Bellatrix? It wasn't as if Boccob didn't already know where she was. He was a god, after all. Somebody was being played here, and Milo was pretty sure it wasn't the all-seeing god sitting across the table from him. This was a setup, in more ways than one.

But on the other hand, it was an honest-to-goodness quest. You don't get to be a successful adventurer by not doing quests for mysterious old Wizards.

And besides. He was already dead. What was the worst that could happen?

"I'll do it."

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Here we have it! The long awaited Book Three of Harry Potter and the Natural 20! To those of you who were concerned about my killing off of the protagonist this early in, fear not! For the Pearly Gates of Adventurer Heaven are more like revolving doors, really.

Chapter 2: Old Friends

It was the sort of night that would have fit in late autumn: cold, wet, and dark. It had no place in early summer.

Lucius Malfoy pulled his cloak tighter around him for warmth. All this sneaking around in the dark was so... trite. And hardly fair. He doubted the members of the Order of the Phoenix ever had to deal with disastrously upset sleep schedules caused by these late-night rendezvous. Lucius glanced around to make sure no-one was watching, then blew his nose in an undignified fashion.

This was just the sort of blunder typical of the new administration. As a criminal organization, they couldn't just meet at a cafe someplace and talk about their evil plans, now could they? Ergo, they had to meet in cold, dark, wet forests on cold, dark, wet nights. Or so the logic went, Lucius supposed.

Because the simple fact of the matter was that they could just meet in a cafe someplace. Every single member of their select group was a fully capable wizard or witch. There was absolutely no reason they could not all Apparate to a gourmet coffee shop at a corner in, say, Luxembourg. Or Kyoto. Or Shanghai.

There were countless places where they could scream, in English, their intention to commit murder and sow discord and such at the top of their lungs and receive nothing more than a strange look from the locals—all the while enjoying a fine Chianti, or perhaps a latte.

Some form of furry woodland creature—Lucius neither knew nor cared which—scurried away from him as he walked to the meeting.

He half expected Riddle to appear from a bolt of lightning, or perhaps descending from the sky.

A black shadowy form appeared in front of him. Despite himself, Lucius smiled. Briefly.

He was the very picture of wholesome youth, well-dressed, clean-cut, with a serious, sincere expression on his face. Everything about him said: trust me. I'm intelligent, reliable, and not-at-all a maniac.

Only a born liar could look so honest.

Riddle smiled, wand in hand, sword belted at his hip.

"Greetings, Malfoy," he said.

o—o—o—o

Thud.

Milo hit the ground—hard.

"You did that on purpose," he muttered accusingly.

He looked around, but there wasn't much to see. Wherever he was, it was cool, dark, and had a hard stone floor. A very hard stone floor.

"Light," he muttered, but nothing happened. Of course—he'd died and come back. He shouldn't have expected his memorized spells to survive the process.

He poked himself, just to check that he was really real. Yup, he thought. Hit points, skills, feats, abilities, it's all here.

Except for his equipment.

Well. Crap.

Generally speaking, most people assume that Fighters and Paladins and whatnot are far more dependent on their gear than spellcasters. And for most spellcasters, that's true. Take away a Druid's scimitar and she can still turn into a tyrannosaurus rex. Take away a Sorcerer's spear and she probably won't recognize it, having never seen it since she bought it 'just in case' with her extra cash at level one.

But take away a Wizard's spellbook, and he's got nothing. Milo had to spend an hour every morning pouring over his spellbook just to refresh his daily spells, and without that, he's just a Commoner with a high Will save and a magic rat—saving, in Milo's case, for the rat.

What do muggles do when they need light? Milo wondered. He'd gotten so used to everyone around him being a single word and a flick of a stick away from magical illumination that he'd almost forgotten what it had been like.

Torches. Adventurers always carried torches. Even Milo did, in his Belt of Hidden Pouches, though he rarely used them. Milo wondered what would become of that belt, now. It was probably decorating the Chamber of Secrets, along with the rest of his old gear.

And his old body, for that matter.

Now there was a weird thought. He had a new body. It felt the same as the last one, and Milo knew that, if he had a mirror, it would look the same—but it wasn't.

Milo felt vaguely resentful of that. It may have been scrawny, and maybe it looked a little malnourished around the edges, and, he supposed, it had an interesting collection of scars and old injuries, but it was his body, dammit, and he was quite attached to it. So to speak.

Milo shook his head, focusing. He was on a time limit, here. An arbitrary and capricious time limit, sure, but a time limit, nevertheless.

Milo's eyes slowly adjusted to the darkness. He was in a large-ish circular room that seemed slightly familiar, somehow. There were a few lumpy shapes scattered across the floor. Milo crawled his way over to the nearest one, feeling around with his hands.

He touched tough leather. He felt around, and found straps and buckles. A backpack. Milo grinned.

A few minutes later, he was holding a lit torch.

There wasn't a backpack in the whole of Creation that didn't have fifty feet of rope, a couple of torches, and flint and steel in it.

When Milo saw what the backpack was connected to, he almost dropped the torch.

o—o—o—o

Hannah Abbot lay in bed. It wasn't that she couldn't sleep. It was just that she didn't really see the point.

She idly fingered a crudely made, lopsided, slightly battered silver rose. After a few minutes, she pinned it to the front of her nightshirt.

"I'm bored," she whispered. It was a lie, but it was the words, not the meaning, that was important.

"Squeak!"

A brown-and-white hamster appeared in her hands, composed of equal parts fluff and pudge, appeared in her hands. Milo had once told her that it used magic to look deep inside her mind and formed its shape to maximize cuteness. She wasn't sure how true that was, because Milo had once told her that the smallest possible unit of measurement was five feet and that carbon wasn't a real element.

But, for one reason or another, it felt hollow, now. Like it was trying too hard. It didn't seem... real.

Maybe the magic was fading. Or maybe it was just her. Cuteness didn't seem to have the same appeal that it used to.

They'd never found Milo. The Daily Prophet said, in a tiny footnote on the fourth page of section H, that he'd run off. But when Hannah had asked Hermione if she knew anything, she'd seen the look on her face.

And that was the last time Hermione had talked to her.

Hermione obviously knew something, but just as obviously wished she didn't.

Was Milo... had something happened to him? Had someone taken him? Or was he... could he be...

He wasn't dead, was he?

The hamster froze for a moment, staring her dead in the eye. Like it was... listening for something. It was uncanny; it had never done anything like that before. It seemed to make some kind of decision, then it did scurried off of her bed.

But it didn't fall. It just sort of... floated there, looking around. It glanced back at her, and she got that feeling again, as if it was ruffling through her thoughts. Then it floated over to her bedside table, pulled open a drawer, and found a pen. It was a practical, Muggle ball-point design that could write for ages without running out of ink; being a halfblood had some advantages. She hated writing with a quill.

It looked around again, then fixed on a poster of a map of the world she kept on her wall. Without warning, it ripped it off the wall.

"Oi!" she hissed. She didn't want to wake her parents. "Put that back!"

The hamster ignored her, and floated the map down next to her. She noticed that it wasn't actually touching the map with its paws. The map just... floated.

The pen floated up, searched around for a while, then stabbed down on England with enough force that it tore clean through the paper. The hamster stared at her, as if expecting something.

She looked at the map. The pen was pointing at a seemingly-random point in North Somerset, twenty or so kilometers away from her home in Bristol.

"Okay..." she said.

The hamster flipped the map over. It moved the pen rapidly in a line straight across the page, lifting it from the paper seemingly at random. Then it moved down slightly and started it again. And again. And again.

As it continued, she realized it was drawing a map of sorts, although it looked more like a photograph someone might take from airplane, or possibly broomstick.

There was a big 'X' drawn over an innocuous-looking hillock.

Hannah had pulled her school robes over her head and was climbing out the window, Cleansweep Seven in hand, before the ink was dry.

o—o—o—o

It was Gerard.

There wasn't much left of the big Fighter himself, but Milo would recognize the scale mail and greatsword anywhere. They'd bought it together, years ago, after Milo had persuaded him that dual-wielding Bastard Swords was lunacy. He'd been skeptical of the idea until he'd Cleave'd his way through a dozen or so goblins and a gnoll shaman without breaking a sweat. Then he'd taken to it like an otyugh to a municipal composting program.

And now he was lying on Thamior's floor.

Dammit.

Milo looked around.

Zook, the gnome cleric, lay on the far side of the room. Well, what was left of Zook, anyway.

There was one more body. Milo didn't want to look. He didn't want to see Wellby.

How had this happened?

Sure, he'd disappeared in a critical battle, but... seriously. Had Thamior done this? How had Thamior done this? He was evil, sure, and he had a few levels on them, but... experience or not, he was such a two-bit villain. He was cartoonishly evil. Milo couldn't believe that he'd actually won.

Maybe it was that his standards had been altered by his time in the other world. Pain and darkness there was... well, more darker and more painful. More real. It wasn't quite so... funny. Maybe he'd taken the new world so seriously that he'd forgotten that his world could be cruel, too?

He looked at the bodies around him.

Was this his fault? Sure, he hadn't chosen to be summoned away by Lucius and his cronies, but... if he was honest with himself, he hadn't tried all that hard to get back, either. He could take the Death Eaters that stayed out of prison. He'd done it before. He could have gotten the answers out of them, one way or another.

Sure, for part of that time, he hadn't been completely in control of himself, but that was just making excuses. He'd barely even thought of returning. He'd gotten so wrapped up in the new world's—

Milo's eyes narrowed.

That wasn't Welby's body. Welby was a halfling, three and a half feet tall in thick-soled boots.

The third skeleton was at least two feet longer.

Milo rushed over to the skeleton, holding the torch over it for close examination.

It was Thamior.

o—o—o—o

"We've been over this before! We agreed you mustn't tell him!"

"I agreed to no such thing! He has a right to know!"

Ron sighed, and tried to distract himself flipping through The Rise and Myriad Painful Falls of the Chudley Cannons. It wasn't working. His parents had been fighting on-and-off all week when they thought he and his siblings couldn't hear.

Any kid can tell you how much that sucks, but this was almost worse.

Because they weren't fighting about him or his brothers, and they weren't fighting about each other, or about Dad's hidden flying car that he was working unreasonable hours.

"But Harry's just a boy!" Molly Weasley protested.

There it was. Harry Potter. Sure, he was Ron's best mate, and he wouldn't trade him for anyone in the world, but... It wasn't always easy, being best mates with the most famous boy in the world. Not that Ron would trade; nobody would want to be famous for the reasons Harry was.

"With that lunatic on the loose, nobody can afford to be 'just a boy' any longer."

Both of Ron's parents were silent for a moment, or at least not talking loudly enough for Ron to hear through the floor.

"What happened, Arthur?" Molly's voice was quiet. Serious.

"You'll read about it in the morning Prophet," Arthur said. "I'm not supposed to—"

"That's never stopped you before," Molly said.

Arthur sighed. "He's killed again. But it gets worse. He—"

o—o—o—o

"I left the Mark!" Riddle said angrily. Petulantly, even. "Of course it was me!"

He had not taken Lucius's news well.

"Perhaps they don't want to believe you've returned, my lord," Lucius said in a low, reasonable voice. Dealing with Riddle was always like this. "It's much easier for them to blame someone more... mundane." Lucius had taken advantage of this very fact many times in his career. People would believe anything other than that the Dark Lord, or his followers, were still active.

"Mundane? Mundane?! I'll show them mundane! I'll usher in an era of darkness like the world has never seen!" Lucius flinched. It was like reasoning with a viper.

"Of course, my lord," Lucius said. "But perhaps, for now, it is efficacious to remain outside of the spotlight. After all, what they do not know cannot be defended against. If they instead believe that Sirius Black—"

"Who the Hell is Sirius Black?" Riddle asked. "Was he a Death Eater?"

"No; he was a member of the Order of the Phoenix."

"Then why on Earth would people think he would leave a Dark Mark?"

"We framed him for..." Lucius paused for a moment. Talking about the Dark Lord's previous defeat was... a tricky subject. "... treachery. And a little murder. They threw him in Azkaban."

"Azkaban? Azkaban? Then what's he doing out here taking credit for my work?"

"He escaped," Lucius shrugged.

"How?"

"I do not know, my lord." He could have used the same method Lucius had used to spring Black's deranged cousin, perhaps, though it didn't quite seem to be the Order's style. Of course, prison could change a man, and he wasn't certain the Order was even involved in this one. He felt no reason to share this with Riddle at this time, however.

Riddle thought about this for a moment. Then he had... a Look. As if his eyes flashed red for a moment. And then all traces of anger and frustration were gone, and it was back to handsome, honest, trustworthy youth.

"So you're saying that people will jump to blame this... Sirius Black... for whatever happens in the next few days?"

Lucius realized the danger in that question, but he'd backed himself into a corner. "Yes, my lord. Within reason."

"Within reason. Of course."

And then he was gone.

o—o—o—o

An hour and a bit later, Milo left Thamior's tower behind him. He'd given his comrades the ceremonial adventurer's send-off (a touching ceremony consisting of rifling through the deceased's pockets for gold and magic items, followed by a hastily-dug grave, as is tradition).

Milo may not have had his companions.

He may not have had his magic items.

He may not have had his spellbook.

But he didn't need them. He'd prepared for this exact circumstance.

Well. Close enough. With Uncanny Forethought he could cast any of a select few spells—Benign Transposition, Feather Fall, Shatter, and Shadow Conjuration—even without a spellbook. He could also spend a little time concentrating to cast any spell in his spellbook, of course, but he didn't have his spellbook—evidently it didn't count as 'his' if it was in another universe. Or, for all he knew, Riddle had burnt it after killing him. Of the few available spells he could still count on using, many would be quite use-impaired here; they were rather highly specialized for taking down wanded wizards.

He didn't have his spellbook.

But he did have Thamior's. Technically, he couldn't 'prepare' spells from it—but he wasn't preparing them, was he? He was casting them spontaneously.

It was a technicality, and a flimsy one at that, but it was one he intended to exploit to its fullest.

"Phantom Steed," he muttered, testing his assumption.

A quasi-real, horselike steed flashed into existence next to Milo, wearing what looked like a saddle, bit, and bridle. It looked like a horse, but it probably could have given the Hogwarts Express a run for its galleons.

He'd found the spell in Thamior's book, which, irritatingly, seemed to be primarily made of spells that seemed sort of 'dark' and 'evil.' In addition to the questionable practicality of picking abilities based on their aesthetic and thematic value, most of them were Necromancy and Enchantment, schools forbidden to Milo. This one, though sort of ghosty looking, was a bog-standard Conjuration. Milo could have cast it in his sleep.

Milo climbed onto his smoke-coloured mount.

Boccob hadn't chosen him for this task because of his interesting collection of Bertie Bott's Every Flavour Beans. He had skills that weren't written on a character sheet, and he planned on using them.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Author's Notes: I have a blog now! Fanfiction doesn't like links, but I think you can figure it out. It's my penname and it's on tumblr. There are .pdf and .mobi versions of Harry Potter and the Natural 20 and Harry Potter and the Confirmed Critical for download. I'll also post announcements and things there, and maybe, if I feel like it, the occasional blog post about DMing or optimizing or RPGs or whatnot, sort of like when I put D&D tips in my stories. I'm new to the whole blog thing, so I'm not sure how much I'll end up using it.

I'm changing the release day to Fridays. We're well on schedule for next week's release.

Chapter 4: Dragon in a Half-Shell

Abby Michaels set her quill down and waited for the ink to dry. Randal was finally starting to come around; they had to block Lucius's push for Severus Snape to keep his position as headmaster. The man was a world-class Potions Master, to be sure, and had many other admirable qualities, but managing teachers and small children were not among them. In fact, the rumours coming out of that school suggested that, sometimes, his teaching methods were borderline abusive. Minerva was by far the superior choice; being strict but fair, as well as reasonably well-liked among the students (at least, the well-behaved ones), and highly respected by the other teachers. Besides, she was Dumbledore's pick, and that should be enough reason for anyone.

Honestly, Abby couldn't imagine why anyone would want Severus as headmaster. She suspected, in fact, that Lucius's methods for persuading some of the others of the Hogwarts Board of Governors had not been entirely ethical, but obviously had no proof. Regardless, the Board was favouring Minerva heavily on this issue—split 7-5 with Randal on the fence—so she wasn't overly worried.

Just as she was about to tie the letter to the leg of her barn owl, Scratch, there was a knock on the door.

Abby sighed, put the letter down, and hobbled over to the door. The mediwizards at St. Mungo's said she should be walking with a cane, but she didn't see the use in one. She was far too old to start walking with a cane, in any case. She'd gotten by for eighty-eight years without; she didn't see why she should have to change now.

She opened the door.

There was a handsome, earnest boy at the door about the age of her grandson.

"Hello? Mrs. Michaels?" The boy asked, smiling politely. He looked vaguely familiar, though Abby couldn't quite put her finger on where she'd seen him last.

"Yes?" she asked. "How can I help you?"

"Well, it's a bit complicated," the boy said. "Do you mind if I come in and explain it to you?"

Something about the way he said it made it sound like such a reasonable request. Like she should invite him into her house without thinking. After all, it seemed to say, he's only a boy. And he's such an honest, responsible-looking boy. And familiar, too.

What could be the harm in letting him come in to talk for a moment or two?

o—o—o—o

Ron sat across from Harry, enjoying Florean Fortescue's famous Flaming Fudge-flavoured ice cream. They'd been about to get their school books when they'd noticed Fortescue had a buy-one-get-one-free sale, and it was bloody hot, and, well... their decision had been made before they'd even realized there was a decision to make.

Hermione was supposed to meet them, but she was a little late. Besides, she wouldn't approve of them eating ice cream; her parents were some sort of Muggle tooth-shamans or something.

"Did you have any trouble getting the Muggles to sign the Hogsmeade consent form?" Ron asked. "Can't imagine they fancy the idea of you having, you know, an actual good time."

"Nah," Harry said. "I waved it in their faces and they signed it just to get rid of me. I think Milo really had an impact on them last year. All I have to do is mention I write him every day, and they largely keep out of my hair. I can't imagine how I would have done it, otherwise."

Ron hesitated. "You don't reckon Hermione's right about him, do you?"

"Right about what?" It was Hermione, an oversized, empty book bag hanging from one shoulder, ready to be filled with, judging by the size, half the contents of Flourish and Blott's book store.

"Nothing," Harry said quickly.

"You're talking about Milo again, aren't you?" Hermione said, pulling up a chair. "We've been over this."

"But it feels wrong," Harry said.

"Of course it does," Hermione said. "That's why treachery is so vile—and effective. It doesn't work if you don't trust the person doing it."

"But..."

"If you try to look at the facts objectively," Hermione said, "it all adds up. He appears out of nowhere—summoned by Death Eaters, no less—he exhibits inhuman healing abilities and strange magic, yet nevertheless is enrolled in an elite school and seems to pass completely unnoticed. And as soon as he shows up, look what starts to happen! The Defence Professor was possessed by what he claims to be You-Know-Who, students start being replaced by undercover dark wizards and witches—and don't even get me started on the Chamber of Secrets. The Basilisk was using Milo's secret passages to get around, and almost killed Professor McGonagall because of him. Then we kill the Basilisk, and poof! Milo disappears from the face of the earth."

"You don't seriously think he was working with You-Know-Who, do you?" Ron asked scornfully. "I mean, come on. This is Milo we're talking about here."

"I don't know what his plan was," Hermione said. "But he almost got us all killed. And I don't think he's human. His magic isn't at all like ours. It doesn't work on any of the same principles, and the two don't interact predictably. And you know what that sounds just like?"

"Yes, because you've told us a million—"

"House elves. And centaurs. And leprechauns. There are plenty of magical creatures out there with magic that isn't like ours—just like his."

"If you're so sure he's a traitor, then," Ron said, "how come you're still taking care of his rat?"

"You can hardly blame a pet for the crimes of its master," Hermione said. "And besides, it's only until I find a new home for him. He bites, and my parents don't like him. Anyway, I'm just saying we should be on our guard. We need to look at the facts."

It was no use arguing with her. It was all the more irritating because she had a point, too—a lot of evidence did point to Milo being the one who opened the Chamber of Secrets.

They eventually made their way to the book shop. Rather than the usual, colourful posters advertising the latest hit seller (generally one of Lockhart's memoirs), the glass walls were plastered with wanted posters for Sirius Black.

"Who is this guy, anyway?" Harry asked. "The Muggles are after him, too."

"A murderer," Ron said. "My parents always hush up whenever they notice I'm listening, though. I think he was one of You-Know-Who's nuttiest supporters, back in the war, just behind Bellatrix. So they locked him up in Azkaban and threw away the key."

"And be broke out, did he?" Harry asked. "The Muggle news says he's been killing people left and right."

"It looks like he's been after Professor Dumbledore's old supporters," Hermione said. "But I don't think we have anything to worry about. Hogwarts is still the safest place for us, even without Dumbledore there."

That was a chilling thought. Dumbledore had been suddenly sacked last year after the Basilisk had rampaged through the school, with McGonagall taking over as Headmistress—for about two minutes, before the Basilisk got her, too. She'd made a full recovery once the Mandrake root had grown up, and Ron couldn't wait for her to come back. She was better than Snape, that was for sure, but she was no Dumbledore.

"Besides," Hermione continued, "they're taking this really seriously. I read the government's launching a nation-wide manhunt for him—both governments. He doesn't stand a chance."

"Well, let's hope they catch him," Ron said, opening the door. "But I don't think it has anything to do with us."

"Hey, Hermione," Harry said as they walked into the store. "How come you have such a big book bag?"

"Because I'm going to get a lot of text books," she said. There was an implied 'obviously' hanging in the air.

"Yeah, sure," he said. "But how come you're going to get a lot of text books?" he asked.

"No reason," she said quickly.

o—o—o—o

"Dark Way!" Milo cast. It had been Thamior's favourite trick. A weightless, unbreakable, shadowy bridge appeared linking the gunwale to the crow's nest on the redundant, sail-less mast, blocking the Dragon Turtle's line of sight to Milo. "Do something!" he shouted at Relkin, who was ducking behind the wheel.

"Inspirational Boost. Working on it!" she called back. Milo could feel a tip-tap-tippity-tap through the floorboards. "Can you see me from there?"

"Yeah. So?" Milo asked, flinching back from another blast of instant-death-steam.

"I'm doing some inspiring tap dancing! Can't you tell?"

Milo leaned out from behind his cover temporarily. "Glitterdust!" he cast, blasting the monster full in the face with its blinding, sparkly might.

Not that it seemed to care, ignoring the bright lights altogether.

"It has +9 to Will!" Relkin shouted. "Get your head in the game!"

Milo had almost forgotten that people could make saves against his spells. The people in the other world almost never did; he suspected they didn't really have bonuses to saving throws. He was losing his edge.

"Whirling Blade!" Relkin cast, throwing her crystalline sword over her head at the dragon's face. Propelled forward by magic and vibrating in tune with her (sigh) inspiring tapdancing, the blade struck the dragon across its face, leaving a deep gouge, before returning to her outstretched hand.

It was too windy for a Solid Fog, and the dragon was immune to fire, so Scorching Ray was right out. It was way too big for Evard's Black Tentacles to have any hope against, and any spell that required a save would be weakened by his lack of intelligence-boosting headgear. Thamior worked alone, and didn't have any proper buffs in his spellbook.

Lacking any half-decent options, Milo fell back on his second-favourite school of magic: Divination.

"Unluck," Milo cast. Just for an instant, he felt like he could almost hear the sound of rolling dice. Other than that, nothing seemed to happen.

The Dragon Turtle roared, and its massive head came right at Milo, treating him to a decidedly unpleasant odour of cooked, rotting fish.

The dragon's bite missed.

By like, ten feet. Milo hadn't even moved. The dragon blinked, confused, as if wondering how it could possibly have missed a stationary target like that. Milo grinned—his spell had clearly worked. The dragon would have to make every die roll twice and take the worse result.

Relkin's sword flew past the dragon's face, again, drawing blood.

The creature roared in pain, and retreated under the water just as Zook and Gerard arrived on deck.

"What's happening?" Zook asked.

"Dragon Turtle," Milo said. "But it just submerged. So we don't need to worry about it for now unless it... wait..." Milo tried to recall what the most recent publications on the monster's abilities had said. Was it the Dragon Turtle that had the savagely effective capsize ability? "It's going to try to flip the ship!" Milo shouted.

Relkin's eyes widened. "The Roll for Initiative is only fifty feet long!" she said. "It gets a..." she frowned for a second, trying to remember exact wording.

"50% chance to knock us into the water," Milo said, "and unless something has changed, the only one here with ranks in Swim is wearing fifty pounds of steel," he said, nodding at Gerard. "Jacks-of-all-trades excluded, of course," he added to Relkin.

"What do we do?" Zook asked. "I don't want to die again!"

Milo's mind raced. They needed to lengthen the ship by at least ten feet to foil the turtle's ability. Probably, anyway. But how would they... Milo looked back up at the mast. It was just sitting there, contributing nothing but drag to the ship.

"We're going to need a lot of mass at the back of the ship in eighteen seconds," Milo said to the party as he ran towards the mast. "Figure it out, I don't care how."

The mast was basically an entire pine tree sticking out of the middle of the boat. Milo had no idea why Relkin had decided to include it on her skeleton-powered ship, but she was going to have to learn to live without it.

Milo sized it up. It was about the right length, give or take five-ish feet. He reminded himself that what he was doing wasn't cutting it down. Not really, anyway.

In the other world, the price of various goods was determined by market forces. Factors like transportation, production, raw materials, taxes, fees, wages, and demand could cause prices to fluctuate unpredictably. This was the basis of Milo's salt trick—advances in mining technology and goods transportation had caused the price of salt to plummet from its historical value.

The value of goods in Milo's world was completely unrelated to the market, but instead dictated, essentially, by the gods. Everything—everything—had a fixed value that the universe ran on. This determined how an item was affected by certain spells, how long it took to craft, how much it cost to buy in a store, and approximately what difficulty of monster might be carrying it.

Depending on the complexity of the item, Milo could craft a certain number of that item, measured by its value in silver pieces, in a given period of time. The cheaper the item, the faster he could make it.

A mast might be big, heavy, and expensive, but a quarterstaff was free, with literally zero value. Ergo, Milo could craft one from a certain amount of raw materials—say, a conveniently located tree trunk—in an instant. Scaling up a weapon increased its value by a percentage based on its size, therefore increasing crafting time as well.

Quick, what's a thousand percent of zero?

Milo tapped the mast with a finger, and it was instantly severed from the ship.

"Feather Fall," he cast, and it gently descended to the deck. "Levitate," he said after it touched down, causing it to lift off slightly. He gave it a gentle push towards the front of the ship, and followed it until just under half of the 'quarterstaff' was sticking out over the water. Milo nudged the base such that it was just touching the deck of the ship. Then he glanced at the rear to see a tree growing from the deck. Of course Relkin had some Feather Tokens, he thought. She's me. Sort of. Then he grabbed a nearby length of rope—there's always rope nearby when you're on a boat—and tied it to the railing, dismissing his spell.

Boom, instant boat extension. The longer the boat, the higher the roll the dragon turtle needed to capsize it.

The boat rocked violently and yawed perilously as the dragon attacked from underneath. Water sprayed onto the deck—but it didn't flip.

Zook ran over to the edge of the boat and looked down.

"Hit him with everything you've got!" Milo shouted at the Cleric. "His saves will be garbage for the next three rounds!"

His holy symbol hanging around his neck flashed as he drew on his divine power to enhance his spells—specifically, to allow him to completely get around all metamagic-based restrictions via the incredibly overpowered Divine Metamagic feat. Milo was impressed; he didn't think the little Cleric had the head for that kind of optimization. It wasn't the most effective way of using the feat, necessarily, but it was a start.

"Empowered Sound Lance!" He called. A barely visible, translucent lance burst forth from his outstretched hands and into the water. As soon as it touched the surface, water exploded high into the air around them.

As Milo was hit full in the face with the fallout of the spell, he realized it wasn't just water that got kicked up by the spell.

"Ewww," he said, wiping dragon blood out of his eyes with his sleeves.

Gerard, meanwhile, had been tying a rope around his waist for no discernible reason. "Hold this," he said, handing one end to Milo.

"Uh, sure," Milo said.

"Thanks!" Gerard said, and, without another word, sprinted to the edge of the boat.

Milo looked at the rope in his hands, then at the 200lb, 6'7" juggernaut running away from him. Then he looked back at the rope. Then up at Gerard, who had disappeared over the edge of the boat, greatsword in hand.

"Oh, sh—"

The rope suddenly snapped tight, yanking Milo from his feet and pulling him bodily across the deck of the ship.

He just had enough time to see the railing moving towards him really, really fast before everything got painful and sort of confusing.

Milo pulled himself together, then tied his end of the rope to a metal hook-thingy that seemed to have no particular purpose beyond being a thing to tie ropes to.

A few seconds later, Gerard came climbing back up the rope, panting and heaving as if carrying something heavy. He swung back over the deck, a huge grin on his face, the head of the Dragon Turtle in his hand. It was significantly larger than he was, and landed on the deck with a meaty thud that rocked the whole ship.

"And that," Gerard said, "is how it's done."

"Are those... are those tears on its cheeks?" Zook asked, peering at the dragon's head.

"Dragons don't have tear ducts," Milo said. "They can't cry."

"This one learned," Gerard said, wiping the blood from his sword.

Chapter 5: City of Light

Milo couldn't sleep.

Or rather, he could sleep. Quite easily, in fact—as with everyone else from his world, he could fall asleep as easily as he could blink. It wasn't even an action. He just didn't want to, right now.

He wasn't sleeping because he was worried, and decided to prioritize, in the way people do late at night, stressing ineffectually about tomorrow over sleep.

Nobody had told him what happened to Myra (CityofLight!CityofMagic!) while he was gone. They were very pointedly not talking about it.

Bellatrix Lestrange was loose in the city, and she was certainly up to no good. Milo had read about what she'd done in the last wizarding war. Apparently she'd tortured five people to insanity with the Cruciatus Curse for no reason other than that she'd enjoyed it.

Of course, that particular curse would do her little good here—Milo had demonstrated that to Tom Riddle in the Chamber of Secrets—but that wasn't her only asset.

Milo was worried because Bellatrix had every advantage here that Milo had had in the other world. She ran on different rules. Rules that nobody knew about, much less how to counter.

Milo had gone up against Lucius's Death Eaters several times and won, not because he was a more powerful wizard, but because he was a weirder wizard. Draco Malfoy, of all people, had shown in the Duelling Club that a wanded wizard who'd done their homework had a very fair chance of beating him. He'd only lost because Milo'd had a handful more tricks up his sleeve than Draco had predicted. Milo had had to adapt rapidly to the new world, using spells and tricks that would have gotten him slaughtered here.

But here, it was Bellatrix who was the unknown factor. She had spells and powers that nobody here knew a thing about. She could ignore fundamental rules of the universe that her opponents would take for granted. She could act out of turn order. She could cast infinite spells every day. She could kill without allowing a saving throw. Of course, she could be countered in a few simple ways—such as using Protection from Evil against her Imperius Curse—if you knew how.

If Bellatrix played her cards right, Milo's home town wouldn't have stood a chance.

And now, thanks, in part, to Tom Riddle, he had people here who he actually cared about.

And that's why Milo wasn't sleeping.

o—o—o—o

Lucius Malfoy stubbed his toe through his leather loafers on an exposed tree root and cursed like a pirate, thankful that nobody had seen him.

He'd had it up to here with these clandestine forest meetings.

"You're late, Malfoy." Lucius felt his whole body go still. When had he gotten here? How long had he been watching?

Lucius turned around, slowly. Tom Riddle was lounging on a low tree branch.

"I was delayed by a meeting that ran behind schedule, my lord," Lucius said smoothly. "There was no way I could leave and maintain my cover. The fault, however, is mine."

"No. The fault lies with me for expecting punctuality from you. However, I can be forgiven, as your other suggestion is working perfectly. Nobody suspects you had anything to do with the deaths."

Lucius bristled inside, but kept it from his face. The reason nobody suspected he had anything to do with the deaths was because he hadn't. And this hadn't been his plan. When he'd said Sirius would make an excellent scapegoat, he hadn't expected this. The boy was insane. He had everything that had made the Dark Lord terrifying with none of the restraint.

"And what is the count now, my lord? Three?"

"Twelve," Riddle said happily. "Were I a gambling man, I wouldn't be placing any galleons on Minerva returning as headmistress of Hogwarts in September."

Lucius licked his suddenly-dry lips. He'd been on the verge of getting Snape given the position permanently as it was. Now he'd have to start finding strings to attach to a whole new group of governors.

"And what of the... last headmaster?" Lucius asked. "Has anyone found information as to his whereabouts?" Lucius knew full well that no-one had, because he had eyes-and-ears watching and listening the world over. But he had no intention of tipping Riddle off to that fact.

Of course, the entire concept of locating the whereabouts of a wizard such as Dumbledore was ludicrous. When you could Apparate across the world with the snap of your fingers, could you really be said to have any whereabouts at all?

No, Lucius didn't care where the old headmaster was. He cared what he was up to. And on that, his sources had been irritatingly silent.

"Dumbledore?" Riddle spat. "The man was older than the bloody Magna Carta even when I—" Riddle hesitated slightly. Someone less perceptive than Lucius wouldn't have noticed it. "—was in school," he finished smoothly. "I doubt we have much cause to worry about a senile old relic." Lucius suspected that Riddle had been about to say 'when I was alive.'

"Of course," Lucius said. "I only mention it because he has interfered with your plans in the past, my lord."

"Regardless. I did not summon you here today to speak of ancient history," Riddle said, dropping down from the tree branch with the grace of a cat. "Tell me of the boy."

"Potter?" Lucius asked. "He's an unremarkable student at best, showing only moderate aptitude in any field of study. He's headstrong and has little regard for authority, but also only displaying only limited capacity for planning ahead. I doubt we have much to—"

"No. The other boy. The one you brought here."

Lucius was genuinely surprised. One of the others at the ritual must have told him. "Milo? A freak. He wields extremely unusual and unpredictable magic of great power, but by all accounts appears to be completely insane. He disappeared midway through last year and has not been seen since. Nobody... official... is looking for him. I saw to that." Lucius glanced at the sword Riddle wore at his hip. Milo had had one just like it...

"They won't find him anyway," Riddle said. "He's dead. No, I want to know about how you summoned him. And why."

"Ah." Lucius hesitated. He hadn't expected this, and wasn't sure how much to tell the monster standing in front of him. "It was a very old ritual that Narcissa uncovered," he said eventually. In your things, he didn't add. This strange new Riddle seemed to be sometimes lacking in knowledge that the Dark Lord had had. "It seems to only have been used once—twice at the most—in all of history."

"Yes, yes," Riddle said. "But what did it do?"

"It makes a trade," Lucius said. "Equivalent exchange. Sacrifice someone great, and get someone great in return. Or so we'd believed. It didn't work."

"Oh?"

"We tried to summon a great mythical wizard only hinted at in ancient texts from... the other side. We believed he would have the power to bring you back, my lord. There was only one viable candidate to create a fair trade. We gave them our greatest in return for theirs." Getting her out of Azkaban had been the hardest part of it, by far. "But even though we specified the great wizard by his name in the ritual, all we got was that freak instead. It seems there is an unknown factor involved, my lord. The ritual is too dangerous."

"But it did work," Riddle said quietly, largely to himself. "He did bring me back. But maybe not in the way you had intended." He looked up at Lucius. "But that wasn't all of it, was it? There was more. A second step."

Lucius frowned. How had he known about that? Lucius was an accomplished Occlumens, but if he wasn't, he'd have thought Riddle was reading his mind. "We had... a backup plan. But it is quite impossible, now."

"Tell me of this backup plan, Malfoy."

"Our agent in the other world had an objective," Lucius said. "But with Milo dead, there is no way to bring her back, now. The point is moot." That wasn't, strictly speaking, true, but Lucius had no intention of experimenting with the ritual and other subjects.

"And what was that objective, Lucius?"

Lucius Malfoy could see no particular danger in telling him. Bellatrix's real mission, as far as he had been concerned, was to stay as far away from him as he could manage. She was charismatic, popular—well, among a certain kind of individual, anyway—and frighteningly talented with magic. She had also been the Dark Lord's favoured lieutenant. She was, in short, a threat to his position. Lucius had never had any intention of bringing her back.

Of course, he hadn't thought Voldemort would return, either...

Still. As long as the Dark Lord was around, Lucius needed to stay on his good side. And besides...

Looking into Tom Riddle's eyes, Lucius could absolutely believe that this was the Dark Lord returned.

So he told him Bellatrix's objective.

o—o

In the darkness of the forest, unbeknownst to either of the conversing dark wizards, an enormous black dog lay among the underbrush with its ears perked up...

o—o—o—o

Newhaven was pretty much your basic thorp. It wasn't much more than a cluster of one-to-three room cottages built around a combination tavern, livery stable, and general store.

It was, as adventurers like to say, a one-quest town. Drop in, find the innkeeper's stolen family heirloom, stock up on trail rations, and leave. It was the sort of town that might get a passing mention in a sentence such as "you pass through a few small villages in your travels to the Forest of Shadows..." While nominally a fishing and farming town, most of the incoming money came from travellers, especially Player Characters, who happen to be passing through on their way to more interesting locales.

At least, that was how Milo remembered it. But that had been before someone had burnt the tavern to the ground and forced the residents to flee. They left, in fact, in such a hurry that they left some things behind: things like clothes, tools, and, in some cases, heads.

Milo stared at the ruins from the deck of the Roll for Initiative.

"Garl's Glittering Gold," Zook said in a hushed tone.

"What happened here?" Milo asked.

"We'd heard rumours of this sort of thing. I told you there were hints we ought to go to the City, didn't I?" Relkin said. "Soldiers have been rounding up anyone with even a Cantrip of magical talent and taking them away. Sometimes people raise an objection or two, and are made examples of." Relkin shrugged. "Typical evil villain stuff, really. I thought that grand vizier guy was behind it, but it's looking like it's this Lestrange person instead."

"And where were you through all of this?" Milo asked, trying to keep his voice as neutral as possible.

"You know. Adventuring," Relkin said.

"Rescuing cats from treants, that sort of thing?" Milo said. "Getting treasure and Experience Points?"

"With clockwork efficiency," Relkin said. "We went up three levels in the last year alone."

"And Wellby was a prisoner during this time."

"As far as we can tell, yes," Relkin said.

"So you're saying that you let a hardened killer burn and kidnap her way through the countryside, with the only other person who might stop her out of action, while you were busy level grinding?" Milo stopped bothering to keep his voice in check.

Relkin stiffened. "I don't see why you're angry at me," she said. "Bellatrix was the one who razed this town."

"Because you had a responsibility to stop her and you didn't even try."

"Milo—" Zook began.

"You weren't there," Zook said. "You didn't see her. We wouldn't have stood a chance the way we were."

"Zook is right," Relkin said. "We needed the levels. Besides, they're only NPCs. Most of them haven't even been named."

"You really don't get it, do you?" Milo said.

"No. Please, enlighten me." Relkin's voice was completely free of sarcasm, but Milo suspected her colossally-high Bluff skill might have been part of that.

"Just because we didn't know them doesn't mean they didn't have names," Milo said. "NPC or not, they were people, just like us."

"Just like you, maybe," Relkin said. "But who are you to talk? I don't see you coughing up your wealth-by-level to bring them back."

"I don't even have a wealth-by-level anymore," Mio said. "All I've got are the clothes on my back and a spellbook written on human skin."

Zook coughed and surreptitiously sidled to the far side of the ship.

"That's an excuse and you know it," Relkin said. "That Belt of Hidden Pouches you used to have? Five thousand gold pieces. Same as it costs for a Raise Dead. You could have used that money to bring back, say..." She scanned the horizon briefly, "that one." She pointed at the body of a small humanoid, probably a gnome or halfling, lying in the street. At least, Milo hoped it was a gnome or halfling. "And if we just so happen to find a Headband of Intelligence in our travels, I somehow doubt you'll sell it to bring back, say, him." Relkin pointed at a dwarf lying against a well, riddled with arrows.

Milo said nothing. The fact that Relkin was right did nothing to improve his mood.

Together, they watched the village roll past them. Milo was tired. It had been so much easier when he'd been like Relkin. These sorts of quandaries never even occurred to him.

There were all kinds of arguments that Milo could make to defend himself. He could say that he'd earned his right to expensive magical gear by defeating monsters. He could say that he needed it to fight evil and protect the innocent. He could say that it was inherent to the system that heroes gained treasure. He could say that even Paladins collected expensive magical gear, and their moral position was unquestionable. After all, if they did wrong, they'd stop being Paladins. He could have Zook cast Detect Good on him and prove that Milo's actions were in the right.

But none of that would change the fact that Milo liked being powerful. He loved being able to magically suplex bad guys. The thrill he got when he'd worked out the salt trick, allowing him to craft magic items at a small fraction of their usual cost, had nothing to do with being able to use his new equipment to defend the innocent from He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named.

Newhaven disappeared behind a steep hill.

Milo needed to change the subject. Ethical conundrums would get him nowhere.

"How come I'm only a kid?" Milo asked, eventually.

"Sorry?" Relkin blinked.

"The starting age for Wizards is seventeen to twenty-seven," Milo said. "But I was level three by the time I was eleven."

"I don't know anything about that," Relkin said woodenly.

"Oh, come on. You and I both know you do."

"Fine," Relkin relented. "It's basic age optimization. Look, we're both human, right? The bonus feat is a solid choice that tends to outweigh the ability modifiers of the other races. But it comes with a drawback: the simple fact of the matter is we don't live for very long. Not compared to elves and dwarves, anyway. There are ways to extend our lifespan, but they're generally available only at higher levels and are deeply suboptimal. I wanted to put that off for as long as possible, so I—er, that is, you—started out with a level in Commoner, which has no starting age, and retrained out at first opportunity. A longer adventuring career means more chances to gain experience and magic items."

"You must know I have no intention of dying of old age," Milo said. "That's just not in the cards for us."

"One should always have plans in place for the event of failure," Relkin said wryly.

Milo stared out over the burnt wheat fields. He could just barely make out the pink-white walls of Myra, City of Light! City of Magic! in the distance.

"We're taking her down," he said. "Boccob's task regardless."

"Deal," Relkin said. She stuck a hand out of her burgundy cloak. "And that's a promise."

Milo grasped her hand and looked her in the eye.

She could Bluff circles around Milo's Sense Motive, and Bards were almost required to be Chaotic, but nevertheless he believed her.

He shook her hand.

o—o—o—o

Tom Riddle hovered over the London cityscape, admiring the skyline.

Well. Admiring wasn't quite the right word. Perhaps... analyzing.

So much had changed since he'd killed Myrtle. The last time he'd visited London, it was a smoking ruin. How he had marvelled at the capability and the sheer, stunning willingness of Muggles to kill each other. He had only ever paid scant attention to their news, but he had been so certain that England would soon fall to the Germans. Not that it would make any difference, in the end.

Their so-called Great War, of course, only lent further evidence for the mastery of wizards over Muggles. They killed millions of each other, and over what? Minor differences of race and creed? Material resources and wealth? Wizards had no care for either. National pride and ethnicity were immaterial concerns compared to the very real, very powerful difference between the magical and the non-magical. Wizards and witches had the power. It was their destiny to rule. Any idiot could see that. And as for fighting over resources? The idea was laughable! Who needed pig iron and rubber when you could transfigure a house out of thin air in an afternoon? Hunger, disease, poverty, scarcity—even mortality itself. Magic could solve any problem. It could solve every problem. It was being squandered, used only in secret.

The world was tearing itself apart, begging to be drawn into the light. What was the loss of a few lives along the way? They would thank him, in the end.

For he was Lord Voldemort, and he had conquered death.

Tom Riddle flew away from the city, his captive tied securely across the back of his Nimbus Two Thousand and One.

All he had to do now was make sure death stayed conquered.

o—o—o—o

The walls were of the fantastical scale that you only really get when the person designing them earned their position by virtue of heredity, rather than by holding a degree in Architecture, Military Science, History, or Common Sense.

The towering walls were shining, pinkish-white marble, dotted with frequent guard towers and roofed with green tiles. Great expense had gone into magically treating the walls to keep soot and mildew off, with the unexpected side-effect of causing migraines in those who left their Detect Magic switched on. The overall effect was quite intimidating: "Watch yourself," the walls said. "We're so powerful, we don't even understand why we'd need walls for non-decorative purposes."

Normally, there was a long wait to enter through the gates as the guards checked visitors for undesirables (read: kobolds) and their wagons for contraband (also, primarily, kobolds).

Today, there were no other travellers on the long, broad causeway into the city, though there were twice as many guards stationed at the entrance as was the norm.

"Halt," one of them said, holding out her mailed hand. "No admittance."

"You take the six on the right, and I'll take the six on the left?" Gerard whispered loudly to Zook.

"Garl Glittergold teaches of patience and restraint," Zook said sagaciously.

"The one second from the right is a hobgoblin," Gerard said.

"Oh, then bugger restraint. Divine Mi—"

"Wait," Relkin said sharply. "I'll talk our way in." Relkin advanced up to the guards. "Yo," she said, pointing a thumb over her shoulder. "Am-scray."

All twelve guards lowered their halberds at her in one smooth motion.

"They're under some sort of mental control," she said, ignoring them entirely. "My Diplomacy check result was pushing low orbit."

"May I try?" Milo said.

Relkin shrugged, and stepped back.

Milo advanced to the guards, keenly aware that he had less hit points than a camel and their pole-arms looked very pointy.

"Aunt Regina!" Milo exclaimed, conveniently remembering her existence. "So good to see you! It must have been, what, three years? So long that you didn't recognize me!" She lowered her halberd uncertainly, blinking as if there was sand in her eyes.

"Milo?" she said. "What... what am I doing?"

"Uncle Reginald!" Milo said, moving to the next guard in line. "Why, you taught me my first cantrip! And Second Cousin Reggie! Remember all those long nights in the woods hunting, er, huntable animals? And, why, if it isn't Adopted Cousin Regan! What unspecified good times we had!" Pretty soon, they all had their weapons lowered, and were milling about in confusion.

"What did you do?" Relkin asked in a hushed voice.

"I remembered each and every one of them as a treasured friend or relative from my backstory," Milo said quietly. "One who would never, ever raise a hand against me or impede the cause of Justice or the furthering of Good. And who gets +2 and a reroll against magical orders against their nature." Thank Boccob that Bellatrix wasn't controlling them directly, he thought. He was pretty sure that the Imperius Curse had no such convenient clause.

"You can do that?" she choked.

"Evidently," Milo shrugged. He raised a hand. "All Amastacias and Liadons, with me!" he said, and strolled through the mighty, adamantine-banded gates into Myra, City of Light! City of Magic!

Chapter 6: City of Magic

Milo was, barring one egregious error in ability score allocation, a naturally pragmatic person. So much so, in fact, that he was sometimes said to be almost robotic. Function over form, crunch over fluff, Grease over Burning Hands. He liked things efficient and cheap, and didn't much care about how they looked.

But even he had his breath taken by the City of Light. The City was laid out on a grid with evenly spaced, wide boulevards cutting through on the diagonal. This tended to wreak havoc on traffic systems and created complicated six-way intersections, but it had the (deliberate) effect of creating very striking sightlines clear through the city. Sweeping monuments, palaces, and key civic buildings were located at the intersections of these diagonal roads, and could be seen unimpeded, rising up above the city, every time they were crossed. On a mighty hill located in the middle of the urban centre was the domed Palace of the Azel Empire, where grand viziers had ruled with an iron goatee for centuries.

The only thing more expansive in the City of Light than its roads were the storm sewers, which housed, at latest estimates, the greatest population of kobolds in the known world.

The City had changed since Milo had visited last. Gone were the brightly-clothed guards endlessly touting the City's tagline, and gone were the great throngs of people scurrying about their business from early in the morning to late in the night. Signs had been posted on shop windows reading CLOSED—BY ORDER and CURFEW IN EFFECT: FINAL WARNING.

As he walked down the City's streets, he saw no-one, save, perhaps for the occasional furtive shadow in back alleys, where the Continual Flames that gave the city its name did not quite reach.

The party had split up. The others were gathering supplies and information. Normally, splitting the party is considered a cardinal sin, but Milo wasn't certain it really applied in this case. After all, hadn't the party been split since Bellatrix took Wellby?

Milo had a special job to do. He'd dragged Relkin along with him, though he still wasn't completely certain that the Bard wouldn't mess everything up. On the other hand, Milo would probably do that anyway. This was not a task he was well-suited for.

Navigating his way through the familiar streets, he eventually found the house he was looking for. It was a little place on a side street in a comfortable, but not exactly wealthy, part of town.

"Are you sure about this?" Relkin asked. She had stopped several paces back, and was sweating a little. "It's not too late to reconsider. We could get backup. Zook—"

"Has no business here," Milo said. "We do."

"Did I tell you that I once killed a Hill Giant with only a donkey? Yes? Good. Then believe me when I say that I am a very versatile and resourceful person, and even I have no idea how we're going to go in there and do this. I'm not equipped for it. This is out of my league, and it's sure as Hell out of yours."

"I learned a thing or two while I was gone," Milo said. "Trust me. But however it goes, it's something we have to do. It's our responsibility."

"Yours, maybe," Relkin grumbled.

"And yours. You and I both know it. You couldn't resist, could you? It would give you first dibs on my loot on the off-chance you recovered my body. Coming up with new names was never your strong suit. And—"

"It gave me roleplaying XP for, essentially, munchkining. Yes, I know. Fine. Let's just get this over with, shall we?" Relkin fingered the hilt of her sword nervously.

Milo reached his hand up to the door. He swallowed anxiously.

He knocked gently, three times.

The smell of fresh-baked bread wafted out through the doorway as it opened.

"Yes? Hello?" a woman asked. She had short, dark brown hair, streaked with grey, and lightly dusted with flour. She wore a similarly flour-ed white apron reading "MATERIAL PLANE'S GREATEST CHEF." An aging, tiny gray cat lounged on her shoulders, lazily watching them with too-intelligent eyes.

The woman gasped when she saw them. The cat, however, yawned and went back to sleep.

Milo tried to speak, but his throat was suddenly dry. As he tried to clear it, she threw her arms around him.

"Hi, Mom," said Relkin Amastacia-Liadon.

o—o—o—o

"Pull up your sleeve," Riddle commanded.

"Y-yes, my lord," Avery stammered, leaning aside his cane and complying.

Riddle couldn't believe the idiot had been foolish enough to get shot by a Muggle. Of all the ridiculous ways to be injured, being hit by a fast-moving piece of metal crudely launched by a chemical reaction had to be among the most unwizardly. And undignified, for that matter. Not to mention those who'd actually died in that idiotic fiasco...

The Dark Mark was clearly visible on Avery's left forearm, like an angry, red tattoo.

Riddle grabbed him by the wrist and pressed that idiot boy's wand against the Mark. Avery whimpered as the Mark burned black, calling his inner circle to join him.

"Go take your place," Riddle commanded. Avery reached for his cane, but Riddle kicked it away from him. Anyone stupid enough to come out the worse in a fight with a Muggle peace officer deserved what they got.

Within minutes, those Death Eaters too cowardly to be in Azkaban and too intelligent to ignore his summons stood, rank-and-file, in front of him. A stray dog wandered behind them in the dark forest.

"Greetings, friends," Riddle said, giving them his best smile. "Today, you're here to finish what you started two years ago." He kicked his hooded ritual offering to the ground and held him there with his foot. "Form a circle," he barked at his 'family.' "I believe you already know how to do the rest."

o—o—o—o

"You're back!" Ley exclaimed, putting out a plate of +5 Chocolate Croissants of Hazelnut. "And not dead!" she added, looking at Milo.

"You said that already," Relkin said, looking slightly embarrassed. "Three times."

Milo won initiative and went for the croissant with the most powdered sugar on top, though he needn't have bothered. Relkin stared at them as if she wasn't certain what they were for.

"How do you know it's really us?" Milo asked. "You should be more careful; something's awry in this city."

Ley made a gesture that suggested how much she cared about that idea. "Pfft. I can tell it's you."

"A mother can always tell?" Relkin suggested sarcastically.

"Sure. And the battery of Silent, Stilled Divinations I hit you with the moment I saw you didn't hurt. Now, what brings you back home?"

"Lestrange," Milo and Relkin said simultaneously.

"The psycho up at the palace?" Ley said. "'Bout time someone took her down. I'd do it myself, but I'm past all that, now, of course."

"Oh, yeah?" Milo said. "Then how did a high-level Wizard like you avoid being snatched up by Bellatrix's 'recruiters'?"

"Fine, fine," Ley said with a shrug that rained flour down on the table. "So I lead a little resistance movement from time-to-time. But who doesn't, these days?" She poured three cups of steaming tea. "So, you're here for help?"

"Not exactly," Milo said. "I..." he glanced at Relkin. "We haven't been home in a while. A long while." Not since their backstories. "And I in particular might not get a chance to see you again for a long time." Maybe ever. "So I just thought, I don't know..."

"It's all right," Ley said. "You don't need a reason to visit your old mother. And if you did, well, I charge less than an inn. So there's that." Ley gave Milo a Look that made him feel like she was using Detect Thoughts on him. Not that she really would, of course. "Was there something else?"

Milo shrugged uncomfortably. Then he looked at Relkin. "Hey, Relkin. Try one of these croissants."

Relkin shook her head. "I'm sure they're... nice, but I primarily derive sustenance from my bag of Everlasting—"

"Just eat one."

"Fine, fine." Relkin eyed the pastry suspiciously, then took a cautious nibble. Her eyes went wide and unfocused for a few seconds. Then she ate the rest of it in one or two titan-sized bites.

A few seconds later, she fainted on the table.

"Sensory overload," Milo explained to Ley, who looked surprised. "Nothing to worry about." The same thing had happened to him a couple of years ago when he'd first had Every-Flavoured Beans. "She'll be up and about in a few minutes. Longer if she got one of the dark chocolate ones."

Ley coughed. "So, now that you've so cleverly got me alone..." she looked at him in the eye with one of those mind-reading parental Looks. "Oh," she said. "Is this about, you know... your run-in with the mortal coil? That gnome friend of yours sent us a Sending about it."

Milo nodded mutely.

"It's okay," she said. "It's okay. Dying can be scary. You're allowed to be scared."

"But it was so scary," Milo said, feeling, perhaps for the first time, his actual age. He was just a kid. He wanted to elaborate further, but for some reason his throat was burning. Had his pastry been poisoned, again? Who had let house elves into the city?

"No-one's around," Ley said, putting a hand on his. "Relkin's out cold, and your father and the others are out of town until this whole 'Bellatrix' thing blows over. You don't have anything to prove."

The room got a little blurry for some reason. Definitely poison. "I thought I would be gone forever," he said in a voice that was barely audible, even to him. How could his throat be so dry if his eyes were so wet? "I thought, maybe, this was it. It's over. I'd be trapped in the Outlands. That all I was, and would ever be, was a collection of stats and abilities indistinguishable from the next. That I'd never managed to be anything… more than my spells, my feats, my items, my skills. All of which failed me in the end, regardless. I was useless. Worse than useless; I was a tool wielded by a monster. There were people who counted on me, people who… who are probably dead, now." That last part came out in a barely audible whisper.

"It's okay, honey. It's okay."

"I don't want to die, Mom."

"I know, sweetie. But, just in case, your father and I did set aside a not insignificant amount of diamond dust in case of that very event."

Milo sniffed. "Thanks, Mom." He moved to wipe his nose on his sleeve, but Ley gave him another Look, this one of Motherly Disapproval. She had a wide array of Looks. "Prestidigitation," he cast, feeling sheepish. His face and clothes were instantly surgery-room clean.

The two of them sat together in silence for a while, drinking tea. But it was one of those rare non-awkward silences that you really only get with family and friends that are as good as family.

Relkin groaned on her chair next to him. "What happened?" she asked. "I feel like someone hit me with a Mind Fog." She rubbed her forehead and groaned again. "And I got a natural one."

"You just used your taste buds for the first time since your backstory," Milo said, clearing his throat.

"It was... intense," Relkin admitted.

"Backstory? " Ley cocked an eyebrow and stared at her. "Are you both PCs now?" she asked.

"Erm," Milo said. "Sort of. Maybe. Yeah."

She got a scary-looking glint in her eye.

"Two PCs in the family?" She said with maybe a little too much excitement. "Oh, those old codgers at the Mage's Guild are going to choke on this," Ley rubbed her fingers together wickedly. "Well, they will when they stop being possessed, anyway."

"Speaking of," Relkin said. "I think I had an idea. We might be able to use your help after all..."

o—o—o—o

"How will we know if it's working?" Gerard whispered. "Is there a signal?"

"We arcanists have our ways," Milo said airily.

"Oooh, a communications spell?"

"Well, yes. Broadly speaking."

Relkin rolled her eyes. "When things go boom, we go zoom," she said.

"Are you really certain this trick is going to work?" Zook asked. "It doesn't seem terribly... reliable."

"Positive," Milo said.

"Couldn't we just... test it out? Just to be safe?"

"Absolutely not," Milo said firmly.

"But... why?"

"It'll only work once. After that, I'd bet my spellbook the gods won't allow it again. Also, this spellbook is pretty gross anyway. Ink runs right off human skin. Who knew."

The ground shook, and the sky started flashing technicolour. Bolts of lightning, balls of fire, and bursts of glittering dust flew out of a tall, twisty tower visible on the City's skyline that was the home of the Mage's Guild. Thanks, Mom. A guerilla strike on a building full of angry, imprisoned or Dominated spellcasters was a Hell of a distraction.

"That's our signal," Milo said. "Shields up, people." Milo lifted the heavy tower shield with both hands awkwardly. He didn't like shields, and he especially didn't like tower shields. They got in the way of the delicate gestures and concentration needed to cast his spells. But, just this once, he needed one.

His companions, one by one did the same. And then they disappeared from vision.

"Remember that they can still hear you," Milo whispered. "So try to move around when there's no-one near or when there's already loud noise."

"I don't like all this sneaking about," Gerard said. "It's Rogue business."

"Well, our Rogue is a touch indisposed at the moment," Milo said. "So the dirty work falls to us."

The gates to the palace slammed open, and soldiers poured out, running right past them towards the Mage's Guild.

Milo licked his lips and hoped that his plan would work.

As the soldiers passed him, some of them—mostly officers and sergeants, with a fair number of enlisted as well—slowed, and looked around, blinking in confusion. Some soldiers ran right into them and fell, causing pileups, while others stopped to see what was going on.

Some of the confused soldiers started bellowing orders to their men to stop what they were doing, while others started arguing amongst themselves. Most were milling around aimlessly, and a small few were staring into space, sobbing.

Not one of them noticed that they had run over a line of Magic Circles against Evil, but all of them realized they were no longer under the effects of magical compulsion, either from the Imperius Curse or from an Enchantment spell.

"I just want to mention that that was all of my third-level spells," Zook whispered. "So if anyone has some, say, serious wounds that need, for example, curing, you're out of luck."

"We understand," Relkin said. "I can pick up the slack in the healing department if it comes to that. Let's move."

As the army fought amongst themselves, the party snuck past them, unseen, through the open gates of the palace.

"I can't believe this is really working," Zook whispered.

"The theory was perfectly sound," Milo said, though he wasn't, in truth, as certain as he was pretending. The theory was, of course, definitely sound. In fact, until he'd seen it working right in front of him, it had been nothing but sound.

The rules, however were indisputable. Fact one: tower shields could grant you cover, the same way that hiding behind a wall could. Fact two: if you have cover, so does all of your gear, including the tower shield granting you cover. Fact three: total cover blocked line-of-sight and line-of-effect.

All of this together meant that you could hide behind a tower shield and you—and the shield you were hiding behind—could become both invisible (no line-of-sight) and untargetable by attacks and many forms of magic (no line-of-effect).

But it was the kind of trick that would only work once before someone upstairs cottoned on and changed the very nature of the universe. But until then...

Milo grinned, and he and his invisible comrades began to infiltrate the most heavily-secured building in the empire.

Chapter 7: Magnum Opus

Corporal Regina checked range and angle for the fourth time, and once again found it to be perfect. It was as if the creepy, self-winding catapult wanted to hit its target.

"Stop fiddling with it," her brother, Reginald, said. "That kid in the red cloak said all we have to do is pull this lever."

"You mean your niece, Relkin?" Regina said.

"Yeah," Reginald blinked. "My niece."

Regina supposed she was her niece, too. Obviously. She'd always been her niece. That's how nieces worked. She could even remember holding her as a baby. She was family. You're supposed to do anything for family, right? That's what people said. She didn't think most people usually meant treason, though, when they said it. Did it count as treason if the emperor himself was being mind-controlled? This was right, wasn't it?

Well, family or no, mentally dominating people was wrong. It was possible—even likely—that there would have been a mutiny once the extent of the domination over the army was uncovered. Regina knew that she, at least, had been mad as Hell when that boy—who was her favourite nephew, she reminded herself—had broken the spell. Taking someone's life and re-writing it to your own will was black as night. And now they were taking the fight to the one who had done that to her. That had to be right.

Regina checked the catapult again, feeling a little uneasy. The firing angle was still perfect.

Those two kids were family. They'd always been family.

The question that nagged at the corner of her mind, though, was, well...

They were always family. They'd always been family. Always. But had they always been family yesterday?

o—o—o—o

Milo walked into the Palace's grand entrance chamber. Pinkish marble sheathed the walls, and a small, tasteful fountain cascaded water on either side of the room. The thick red carpet was covered in muddy bootprints from the soldiers who had been stationed here.

"Everyone still here?" Milo whispered. The rest of his party wasn't simply invisible (as that could be countered with magic), they were outright un-see-able.

There were a series of affirmatives.

Milo felt as if he should give an inspirational speech. Something that would thank his friends for risking their lives to help him, that would get their blood pumping, and that would drive them to new heights. Something suitable to the momentousness of the occasion.

"You all know what to do," Milo said. Screw it. Inspiring people was un-wizardly. "Let's get to it."

o—o—o—o

"Is the package prepared?" Bellatrix asked, pacing impatiently, her silent bodyguard lurking in the corner.

"Soon, mistress," Lkoturo the Vizier said. Even the Imperius Curse couldn't quite banish the oil from his voice.

"What's taking so long?"

"There is an affray at the Mage's Guild, mistress" Lkoturo said. "Unenlightened Wizards—"

"Wizards!" Bellatrix snapped. "They are not wizards!"

"Of course, mistress. Unenlightened... users of magic launched a raid in an attempt to free their comrades. Further, they deployed some sort of... trap against our army. It may take some time to clear up the mess."

"Army," Bellatrix mocked. "Muggles with sharpened sticks. I care not one way or the other."

"Of course, mistress. But may I remind you that, for the pacification of the lands surrounding Myra, City of Light! City of Magic! we need—"

"For now," Bellatrix cut in. Once the package is prepared, this strange mockery of a world can burn for all I care. "And I thought I ordered you to stop saying that."

"Of course, mistress."

"You may leave me."

"Of course, mistress." Lkoturo bowed deeply and walked out, closing the great spell-wrought wooden doors behind him.

o—o—o—o

Most other seats of government don't have prison cells in the basement, excluding, of course, the conference rooms.

Despite ready access to Continual Flame-based lighting, the prison was dark, smoky, and poorly lit, because some conventions are more powerful than mere practicality.

Unconscious prison guards lay scattered about the room, of whom roughly half were suffering from severe injuries.

"Cure Minor Wounds," Zook murmured over one of them. With a gasp, the guard's eyes shot open, and he reached for a weapon. "Gerard?" Zook gestured.

Gerard, holding a broken table leg, effortlessly thwacked the guard over the back of the head, knocking him back unconscious.

"Must you?" Relkin asked impatiently.

"These guards are innocent," Zook said. He looked down at the guard Gerard had just knocked out, who had RSIST AREST tattooed on his knuckles, and a black eye patch with a skull on it. "Well, given the benefit of the doubt, they could be innocent. We don't know. So we need to make sure they're unconscious from nonlethal damage. Otherwise, they'll just bleed out when we leave."

Relkin sighed, but left the issue alone.

Surprisingly, considering the new regime, the cells were largely empty. Milo had expected more, well, starving political prisoners and the like. Maybe a couple of loyalist guardsmen or knights willing to help their cause if you put a weapon in their hand.

Though, he supposed, it actually made sense for the place to be empty. Anyone like that would simply have been brainwashed by Bellatrix or one of her cronies before being sent back out into the streets to act as a double agent. And besides, most of the magical prisoners were being kept up at the Mage's Guild, and since when had a Death Eater ever paid attention to the goings-on of Muggles?

There was, however, one prisoner: an aging man in filthy tatters that were once fine robes. Regal, even.

The old man stared up at them with blank eyes.

Milo recognized him immediately. He'd seen his face every time he'd sat down at an inn, bought new equipment, or looted a treasure chest in a fifteen-foot room after slaying the orc defending it.

"Your Majesty!" Milo hissed. "We're here to rescue you!"

The Emperor continued to stare at him blankly from the other side of the bars. Right, Milo realized. He's probably under a whole boatload of mental compulsions. There was no way to fix that without first getting into the cell.

"Oy, skill monkey! I've got a job for you."

Relkin perked up. "Oh?"

Milo gestured at the lock.

Relkin stepped up and took a look at the oversized, rusty lock. Then she produced a series of fine, complicated-looking tools and probes, and went to work. In a few seconds, the door swung open.

"Protection from Good," Milo muttered, and tapped the Emperor on the forehead. He felt weird casting the inverse of his usual spell, but this was all he'd found in Thamior's creepy spellbook. For these purposes, the results should be exactly the same.

The old man gasped and looked around as if he'd never seen, well, anything before.

"You're free," Milo said. "But we need your help. Someone has to take over after we—"

"This is your tube," the old man said in a serious tone. "This is your tube in ruins."

"Er. What?"

"Any treads?" the man said, dropping to a whisper, and clutching Milo's hands desperately. "Madness and ages past; that's what really matters. Yea! Fie! Treads! Treads!" The old man suddenly stopped rambling and stood up straight, adopting a beatific pose. "Neither a borrower nor a treasure be," he said sagely.

Relkin frowned. "Detect Magic," she cast. "He's clean," she said.

"So, what... what's wrong with him?" Milo asked. "I heard him give a speech a few years back; he wasn't like this then."

"No man," the emperor said pompously, "is fit to coagulate another that cannot coagulate himself."

"I think he's been under mental compulsion his whole life," she said. "I don't think he's... all there. I'm not certain it's something magic can fix."

This posed a problem. It had all seemed so simple on paper: break in, free the rightful monarch, take out Bellatrix, everyone goes home happy.

"The sample and the plug," the old man rambled, "are alike admired for a saturated tank—and for their transparent pits."

But the emperor was clearly unfit to rule. Milo didn't want to leave the City to fend for itself after dealing with Lestrange, but what could he do...?

"I've got an idea," Milo said grimly. "But I think some of you may not like it."

Milo told them.

They didn't like it.

o—o—o—o

The hallway was empty.

Red plush carpet covered the floor, and the walls were expensive hardwood. Every here and there was an alcove or sconce with a painting, urn, or other tasteful, and, more importantly, expensive piece of art. It was, basically, your typical palatial hallway.

Lkoturo the Grand Vizier strolled down the hallway. He looked confident, in control, smug, and hardly mind-controlled at all. His long, waxed goatee looked particularly oily today.

He paused, tilting his head, as if he heard something that he couldn't quite make out. After a few moments, he gave the minutest of shrugs and continued walking.

He didn't realize he wasn't alone until after Milo had tapped him on the back with a Protection from Good and dropped his tower shield.

Lkoturo spun around, eyes sharp on Milo.

"You!" he hissed. "You're supposed to be dead!"

It was Milo's turn to be surprised. "You know who I am?"

"You're a PC! What do you take me for? Of course I know who you are! Now, why did you free me?"

"We want to help you," Milo said. "Actually, let me rephrase that. We're grudgingly willing to help you."

"To what end? And in exchange for what? And why shouldn't I rid myself of your meddling presence now, while I have you alone and out-levelled?"

Milo coughed delicately, and there were three thuds as tower shields hit the floor, revealing Zook, Gerard, and Relkin with mace, greatsword, and longsword held, respectively, in a generally menacing manner.

Lkoturo paused. "Your case is persuasive," he said finally. "Now, what do you want?"

"We're here to take down Lestrange," Milo said. "We want you to return the city to a generally status-quo-sort-of situation afterward. In the meantime, you stay out of our way."

"How do I know this isn't some sort of trick?" Lkoturo asked. "After all, with me in charge, sooner or later we'll likely have it out anyway."

"True," Milo said. "But you're the sort of villain PCs are there to handle. You're capital 'E' Evil, and Bellatrix is lower-case 'e' evil, and I think we've all seen what's scarier. And besides, I lived in the City under your rule for eleven years. Bandits and kobolds were problems, but the people never went hungry and oppression was generally kept to a minimum."

"I pride myself on my modern outlook," Lkoturo said.

"You're this world's problem, and this world can deal with you later. Until then, someone has to keep the trains running on time. Do we have a deal?"

"Very well," Lkoturo said. "But what is a train?"

"Irrelevant to our conversation. Where is Bellatrix?"

"In my office. Take the stairs two floors up, first door on the left. But you'll never get in; the doors are heavily protected with magic."

Milo made a dismissive gesture. "Not a problem. Why was she rounding up spellcasters?"

"For her search," Lkoturo said. "She's completely obsessed, especially in the last few days. High-level spellcasters possess very potent divination and transportation spells, allowing them to find and retrieve objects the world over."

"Interesting. But what is she looking for?"

"Philosopher's Stones," Lkoturo said. "She's got dozens of them."

Chapter 9: The Fourth Mistake

"I only joined the Death Eaters in the first place to get a shot at Bellatrix."

Magical rituals are fickle things.

"I—sometimes—enjoy Muggle jazz music."

They aren't spells. That's the first thing people get wrong. Spells are simple and well understood. Use a wand, focus your mind, channel your inner magic through the wand, say the words, and bam. Magic happens. The more accurately you perform the incantation and the gestures, the more efficient your mind and wand can channel the magic to get the desired effect. But wands are barely two thousand years old—new inventions, in the grand scheme of things. They were the product of human ingenuity at its finest, creating a simple tool that allows anyone (well, anyone that mattered, anyway) to perform simple, reliable magic. The real beauty of a wand is how safe it is. Ninety-nine times out of a hundred, botching an incantation results in nothing happening at all. When something does happen, ninety-nine times in a hundred it's harmless magical discharge—sparks, light, noise. Uncommonly, there are minor magical side effects, easily remedied. Still, very rarely, reckless wand usage can result in severe injury or even death. Nevertheless, they are considered safe enough to be given to children. But rituals are not like spells.

"My family is deeply in debt because of my gambling problem. My husband hasn't found out yet."

Rituals are dangerous. One wrong word, one wrong ingredient, and you're lucky if all that results is death. It's the ones that create life that you have to worry about.

"I like to kill insects just for the fun of it."

Rituals are not invented, either. That is the second thing that people get wrong. Spells have inventors, often famous ones, who work to tease out the shifting, often nonsensical rules of magic and create spells that allow one to repair glasses, to chop onions, to turn rats into teacups, to speak to a crowd, or even to kill. It was a field of lore that Lucius Malfoy knew little about, but that wizards and witches with much more skill and much less ambition than he could regularly work with to produce hundreds of new spells every day, usable by anyone in the world with the patience and time to learn (except for Muggles, of course). But rituals are not invented. They are discovered. Chant a little Old Aramaic, burn a little sandalwood, sprinkle a powder made from the canine teeth of a child murdered by his brother over a bowl containing stone from a fallen star under the light of a crescent moon and, in three days, it will rain vinegar. (This is true. Try it at home; see for yourself).

"I still pick my nose."

And nobody knows why. That terrified Lucius. Who out there was watching, waiting, to see that someone performed the ritual and had the power to follow up with the effects? More troublingly, why would they do it? What possible gain could this shadowy entity get from powdered teeth and space rocks? Or maybe there was no entity, and it was a fundamental property of the universe that vinegar would rain in the middle of the lunar month because somebody said the right words in a dead language? Lucius wasn't sure which was worse.

"I killed my sister's cat with a steak knife after it vomited on my bed. Everybody thinks he ran away."

Almost more frightening was that rituals were, apparently, timeless. Worse than the chanting in dead languages was the chanting in languages that hadn't yet been created. In the early 1600s, Italian explorers discovered an apparently isolated tribe living on an island in the south pacific whose magical population regularly made use of a rain-causing ritual whose incantation, it was discovered in 1976, was in perfect, modern Esperanto.

"Ever since my injury, I've had nightmares of that Muggle girl with the metal wand coming back to finish the job."

All of this brought up the uncomfortable question of who it was who first figured that out. It can't have been coincidence, or even experimentation. Maybe there was one Neo-Assyrian dentist with a weird thing for meteorites who stumbled across the vinegar ritual. But that such an event would have happened many thousands of times in written history defies imagination.

"I wanted to be a Hufflepuff."

All evidence suggested that wizards and witches across all cultures and throughout history and pre-history were, on occasion, suddenly inspired to collect a series of essentially random articles and chant complete gibberish. Stranger still was how often they felt the desire to pass this information along. Even supposedly 'secret' rituals still wound up written down and preserved through fires, Muggle witch hunts, wars, and natural disasters, despite the self-evident fact that the best way to keep anything secret was to not write it down in the first place—and, of course, kill or Obliviate any witnesses. Rituals, it appeared, wanted to be discovered—and, more troubling, wanted to be shared.

"I haven't loved my wife in years."

All of this is to say that Lucius Malfoy did not generally approve of the use of ritual magic. In fact, the one timethat the situation had grown desperate enough that he decided to overcome his natural suspicion of ritual magic, he'd accidentally set in motion a series of events that culminated in the precise opposite of his desire. Rather than prevent the Dark Lord's return, he'd brought it about.

"I wanted to be an Auror, but couldn't get my Transfiguration Owl."

And now here was the final product of that ritual, preparing to perform it again. Lucius wished he could bring himself to believe it was mere coincidence.

"I'm worried I might be an alcoholic and don't know who to talk to about it."

And now it was Lucius's turn. The ritual required all participants to reveal one secret that they had never spoken aloud to anyone before. What he hadn't mentioned, however, was that it didn't need to be an important secret.

"I don't have strong feelings either way about American versus English spelling."

The only one who hadn't spoken was Riddle, their thirteenth. Lucius found himself strangely curious—would he fall into the trap of the others, and allow the drama of the situation to colour their choice of secrets? Would he follow Lucius's route, and reveal something meaningless? Would he choose a secret that, when revealed, would provide some sort of gain?

"Sssthisss kerasshe ssslan ssssshira."

Clever. By speaking in Parseltongue, Riddle could both avoid revealing any information he desired to keep secret, but also reminded people that yes, despite his youthful appearance, he really was the Dark Lord. Hardly subtle, but subtlety was often lost on the other Death Eaters.

Riddle kicked the sacrifice into the middle of the circle. Who had Riddle chosen as an equivalent exchange for Bellatrix, supposedly the greatest Death Eater who ever lived? Who was, in Riddle's mind, greater than anyone else present in the circle? Was it McGonagall? Or perhaps a great Auror, like Moody? The alchemist, Flamel? Lucius began to worry that, maybe, Riddle decided the best way to find a close equal would be to choose Bellatrix's own sister, Narcissa Malfoy...

Riddle removed the sheet covering the victim, and Lucius had to strangle a laugh as their face was revealed.

Riddle's chosen equal for Bellatrix Lestrage, widely considered the greatest duelist of her generation, killer of an unknown number of wizards, witches, and Muggles alike, famed for torturing Alice and Frank Longbottom to the point of insanity and well beyond was none other than Gilderoy Lockhart.

For a moment, Lucius wished the ritual actually worked the way that everyone else believed. It would make his life so much easier. As it was, this would only serve to cement Lockhart's reputation. How strange the way the world works sometimes...

o—o—o—o

A bored rat is an unhappy rat, and it's up to you to provide fun and games for your little guy. Hannah looked up from the pamphlet she'd gotten from the pet store and watched Mordenkainen. She hadn't ever really realized what a big rat he was. He'd always seemed so tame and friendly around Milo, but ever since his... disappearance... Mordy hadn't been the same.

Hermione had been almost too happy to give him up to Hannah. Almost suspiciously happy, actually. She really should have thought to ask why the bookish girl's hands were covered in bandages...

Hannah sighed. Her parents were not going to like this.

o—o—o—o

A dark, flickering orb slowly grew out of Bellatrix's chest. She didn't appear particularly perturbed by it.

"I though this might happen," Milo muttered. He glanced outside. He hadn't been keeping track, but he was willing to bet it was within a few seconds of exactly three days since Boccob had brought him back. The old Wizard hadn't ever intended for him to beat Bellatrix, all he'd wanted was for Milo to be in this room at this precise moment.

"What's happening?" Relkin asked. "Is that—oh. Oh." Comprehension dawned on her face. She—like Milo—had never seen this from the outside, before.

"I don't have a lot of time," Milo said. "Wellby," he said, turning to face the Wellby. "I'm sorry you had to spend so long in her thrall. I wish we had more time to talk. Look after my sister for me, okay? And tell Gerard and Zook I said something appropriate."

"You're talking like you're about to—hey, wait," Wellby's mouth dropped. "Your sister? Since when do you have a family?"

Milo turned to Relkin. "Sis..." No, gross. Never again. "Relkin. This world is in your hands, now. Level up a little, then go after that vizier guy, kay? He's bad news."

"I know, I know," Relkin said. "He probably has four or five high-level, quirky underlings for us to work through, first."

"Look after Mom," Milo said. The sphere had almost completely enveloped Bellatrix, now.

"Look after yourself," Relkin said. "I don't think you can count on another deus ex machina like the one Boccob threw at you." She sighed, and unbuckled her belt reluctantly. "Take this with you," she said. "You'll need it more than me." Milo grabbed it. The leather felt familiar—it was almost identical to the Belt of Hidden Pouches that he'd once had.

Milo shook his hands out of his sleeves once again, Readying a spell. He knew what was coming, this time. The sphere had almost completely enveloped Bellatrix, now.

Milo sprinted towards the disappearing witch and dived towards her. Just as he was about to make contact, he shouted, "Feather Fall!"

The world turned dark and cold.

o—o—o—o

The circle of candles flared into life, burning dozens of times brighter than any natural flame could.

Gilderoy Lockhart looked around with his eyes wide, a rag shoved into his mouth as a gag.

"Bellatrix Lestrange," Tom Riddle spoke. Despite the light, his face was dark as night, except for his eyes... Lucius shivered. The Parseltongue hadn't been necessary; one look at his eyes was all that was necessary to prove his identity. "Bellatrix Lestrange," Riddle said again. A west wind buffeted them, almost knocking Lucius from his feet. The flames, however, weren't affected at all. "Bellatrix Lestrange," Riddle said for the third and final time. The air went perfectly still, and, between one second and the next, Lockhart vanished.

Maybe it won't work, Lucius thought. Last time, we specified a great and powerful wizard by name—by name—and look what happened. Instead of the great Archmage, the enigmatic Ninth of Eight, supposedly the first wizard that ever existed, all they got was some half-crazed, semi-human child.

There was a flash of darkness that left Lucius blinking spots out of his eyes, and Bellatrix appeared a few feet above the ground, covered, for some reason, in grey dust.

She slammed into the moss as if she'd fallen from a much greater height, and there was a gristly snap of bones breaking. She lay on the ground, groaning faintly.

Lucius almost lost his usually iron control. He felt like breaking something. After all that work I'd gone through to get rid of the woman, she just comes right back.

Lucius closed his eyes and focused on his breathing, calming himself down. The damage was done. The important thing now was to establish his position as—

"Glitterdust!" Everything went yellow-white. Oh, no, Lucius just had time to think before the inevitable happened. "Evard's Black Tentacles!"

o—o—o—o

Mordenkainen looked up, directly into Hannah's eyes.

"Squeak?" he said.

Hannah blinked. Sure, rats tend to squeak a lot, but...

Well, they just sort of squeak. They don't really say 'squeak.'

"Mordy?" She said. "Is that really you in there? You're… back?"

The rat nodded impatiently "Squeak!" he insisted.

Hannah tossed the pamphlet away and opened the latch on the top of the cage. Mordy climbed his way up the bars and brachiated, monkey-like, across the top. With an acrobatic flourish, he flung himself out of the cage and landed on the top.

Hannah was barely watching, though—instead, she was fishing her broomstick out from her closet. As an afterthought, she also pulled on the spell-enhanced robe Milo had given her. She also pocketed her wand, though she knew she wasn't allowed to use it.

"Coming?" she said, holding a hand out for the rat.

o—o—o—o

Milo touched the ground gently.

It was a nice change from his usual method of entry to alternate planes of existence.

Among the writhing mass of glitter-covered, black, rubber tentacles generally ruining the day of a not-insignificant number of Death Eaters was none other than Tom Riddle, who was attempting to hack his way out of the mess with a sword. A tentacle had firmly grabbed his wand hand.

Milo narrowed his eyes.

"Return," he muttered. The sky-coloured crystal in the sword's pommel flashed briefly, and it appeared in Milo's hand. Riddle blinked in surprise, staring at his now-empty hand. Then he looked up, and met Milo's eyes. To think, Milo had gotten a discount when he'd made the item by making the return functionality only work for capital-"W" Wizards. Technically the item was weaker by being more limited, but in practice, it was strictly an advantage.

"Fourth mistake, pretty boy," Milo said, bashing the sword's golden hilt into the Dark Lord's nose with an enormously satisfying cer-UNCH.

Sure, a spell would be more effective, but when would he get the chance to punch He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named in the face again? Besides, it was a free attack of opportunity; his turn's real action would have to be used getting the heck away from this mess.

Riddle touched his nose. His fingers came away red.

"PCs are never beaten in battle. They can always come back for another go." Milo sheathed the sword in Relkin's Belt of Hidden Pouches. Without his amulet of Mirror Move, it was more a liability than an asset. "Now, eat Kelgore's Fire B—"

"Stop," Riddle commanded, his eyes flashing red.

Milo blinked. His hand was outstretched, but the spell was gone from his mind.

Riddle smirked, despite his precarious position and broken nose. "I'd been doing magic long before that fool gave me a wand," he said. "Now. Draw." Despite himself, Milo found himself drawing his sword once more. "Now, Kill Yourse—"

Something huge and heavy slammed into Milo from the side, knocking him well clear of the tentacles. An enormous black dog pinned him down against the dewy grass.

The dog looked him in the eye for a moment, and the next thing Milo knew, he was being carried through the forest by a gaunt, skeletal man with long, dark hair.

"Idiot," the man said.

"What—who—why—no, let's stick with who. Who are you?" Milo asked.

"Hang on," the man said. At first, Milo assumed he meant it as in, 'wait and I'll tell you,' but he quickly realized the man was speaking literally.

A moment later, Milo was hanging on to the back of the giant black dog again, being carried through the forest at speeds that were, frankly, irresponsible given the darkness and density of trees. As requested, Milo hung on for dear life.

A green bolt slammed into the tree in front of them. Brown and red leaves rained over them as the tree died.

Milo attempted to throw up an Illusory Wall to screen them, but the dog's mad sprint threw off his concentration.

He'd have to be a little less ambitious with his spell choice if he wanted to be able to cast with any reliability from the back of a sprinting dog, he realized. "Dancing Lights," he muttered quietly, firing a spray of vaguely hostile-looking red bolts behind him, shouting, "Diddlum's Deadly Death, er, Bolts!" With their pursuer presumably cowering in fear from his 'attack,' he risked a glance around. A couple of Death Eaters—he couldn't distinguish them between their hoods and the darkness—were following on broomstick, weaving between trees. Just to confuse them, he had his Dancing Lights swoop around again from behind and just barely miss the one in front, this time green, making a passable imitation of the Killing Curse.

The lead Death Eater veered away from her partner, making a rude gesture with her hand.

"Can't you, like, Apparate or something?" Milo shouted at the dog as they ran. The dog didn't reply, which Milo took as a negative. Technically Milo could use Dimension Door to teleport them away, but its range was pretty limited, and he wasn't sure he could pull it off from horse—er, dog-back. Similarly, he could summon a Phantom Steed and run significantly faster than this dog, though the Steed couldn't carry the both of them and he didn't want to leave his rescuer (?) behind.

Milo did some rapid arithmetic in his head.

"Grease!" he cast again, targeting the broomstick under the rear Death Eater. The broomstick, now frictionless, continued to accelerate, but the Death Eater did not. The results were fairly predictable.

No, that didn't really help them escape—two more Death Eaters flew up to take the place of the one he'd taken out—but it did push him just over the experience-point threshold to level nine.

In addition to getting him to level four of Rainbow Servant, which came with all kinds of goodies, this allowed him to have been retroactively researching two spells—and also allowed him to more ranks in Concentration. For his spells, he snagged the 5th-level Wall of Stone and Teleport, both spells he decided—in the thirty seconds or so in which he had to consider this decision—would be useful in this world.

Not immediately helpful, of course, because as Wizards have to rest for eight hours in order to prepare any spell slots of their level.

Well. A lesser Wizard would, anyway.

As this was his ninth level, he was able to choose a feat—in this case, Versatile Spellcaster. He hadn't been planning on taking this one, but he couldn't see any other way out of the current situation without it.

Versatile Spellcaster was never intended for Wizards, but Sorcerers. Technically, however, it only requires one to be able to "spontaneously cast spells," which Milo could do thanks to his ridiculously powerful Spontaneous Divination ability.

Outside of a few unnecessarily complicated, if powerful, tricks that Milo wasn't in any position to utilize, Versatile Spellcaster was a strictly mediocre feat that allows one to burn two spell slots of a lower level in order to cast one of a higher level, bypassing the whole "preparation" business.

"This is going to feel weird," he said to the dog. "But don't fight it if you want to live." Without waiting for a response, he began casting. This was the most complicated spell he'd used to date, and the circumstances were hardly ideal. He'd to bring all of his focus to bear.

"Teleport."

Chapter 10: The Dogs of War

The dog under Milo stumbled slightly as the ground he was standing on shifted from uneven forest floor to smooth, packed dirt.

Milo hopped off, grateful to finally be standing on solid ground. He wasn't built for riding animals.

"Light," he said, tapping the wall and causing it to glow. The previously-dark room lit up instantly, revealing the familiar sights of one of his many nigh-identical bolt holes. This one, which happened to be closest, was located in... ah, who am I kidding, Milo thought. I'm not going to pretend I remember the names of this world's political regions. "It worked," he said, more than a little surprised. He wondered what, exactly, would happen to his newly-learned Teleport spell. In order for him to cast it like that, it had to be in his spellbook. But he didn't have his spellbook... Riddle did, unless it was growing dusty in the Chamber of Secrets. But he had learned the spell—and Wall of Stone, for that matter. Had the text of the spell simply appeared in the book, wherever it was? Or...

Milo quickly skimmed through Thamior's really, incredibly gross spellbook. Nope, not there. Milo shrugged. He was less dependent on his spellbook than most Wizards; the important thing was that it still existed, wherever it was.

On the topic of his old stuff... Milo wondered what had happened to his body. It was a weird experience, knowing that the body you were in, no matter how identical it looked, was not the body you were born in. Was it, too, decaying in the Chamber of Secrets? Or had Riddle taken steps to dispose of the evidence? Could coming back from the dead in this manner be somehow exploited as some kind of macabre corpse-generator? Milo was forbidden from using Necromancy, but if he wasn't, what kind of weird undead could he create using his own body? How could he get around that no-Necromancy restriction? Now there was a thought...

"Are you even listening to me?"

"Sorry?" Milo said, broken out of his reverie.

"I said something to the extent of, 'you didn't know that would work'?" said the dog, who was now a scruffy man again. He looked like a man who had made a few too many Starvation checks in his time. At the sight of his teeth, Milo immediately thought of Hermione's parents. If anyone needed a dentist, it was this man.

"Well, I didn't even know the spell until I took out that Death Eater back there," Milo said. "And once I did, Teleport only has, at best, a 97% success rate." The more familiar Milo was with the destination, the more likely it was that he would arrive on target.

The man-dog-man-person gave Milo a look with which he was fast becoming familiar. It was sort of halfway between cautious and impressed. Oh, and wondering if their leg was being pulled. It was a third of the way between each of cautious and impressed and wondering if their leg was pulled. And the look generally reserved for crazy people. It was a quarter of the way between—

Well, you get the idea.

"I see," the man said, sitting down on one of the wooden chairs. "Who taught you to Apparate without a license? And how come the Ministry lets you do magic underage? Have things really changed so much?"

Milo shrugged. He wasn't sure how much information he should give to this strange man. "I'm out of their jurisdiction."

The man nodded slowly, as if that meant something. For all Milo knew, maybe it did—he understood, dimly, that there were other political bodies outside of the United Kingdom, which had their own Ministries of Magic (or the equivalent). For all Milo knew, maybe the local Ministry really couldn't tell if foreign children were performing magic within its borders, and instead an alarm went off halfway around the world.

"My turn for a question," Milo said. "Who the hells are you?"

o—o—o—o

There was a sharp pop as Riddle appeared by the uninhabited stretch of coastline, drawing his wand. He aimed it at an unremarkable-looking patch of ground and muttered a quick spell incantation. Ghostly shovels appeared, and, in a manner of minutes, had dug a perfectly rectangular hole, about three feet across, six long—and six deep.

Riddle looked down. It wasn't a pretty sight, but even at this stage in his career he'd seen worse. Most importantly, it was still there.

Here, all alone and with no witnesses, he let his icy control slip.

"Impossible!" he muttered. How could that half-crazed boy have managed to fake his own death? And if he had, then whose body was rotting in the ground?

No. It was impossible. Riddle had been inside his mind. There could be no deception. The death had been real.

So who—or what—had come through the ritual? Could it really be the same person? Had the boy really learned to cheat death so completely? Or was the ritual somehow flawed? Did it simply... create these strange, semi-human children as a byproduct of its use?

No. The boy had said something—fourth mistake, pretty boy. Hadn't he said, back in the Chamber, that Riddle had made four mistakes?

It had to be the same boy.

"Madness!" Riddle shrieked. Around him, grass blackened, thin tendrils of smoke rising from their burnt stalks.

He'd come back, as far as Riddle could tell, at full power and in a matter of months. How? Even after all the work Riddle had gone through, he'd still lost the bulk of his memories and it had taken him close to a year living in another's head. What did the boy know that he didn't? What was his secret?

Riddle didn't know how, but he knew that he would find out, whatever the cost.

But for now, he had more pressing business.

With a wave of his wand, the grave filled itself in again, and he was gone.

o—o—o—o

The stranger remained silent, obviously debating how to answer Milo's question.

"I'm Sirius Black," he said, finally. He clearly assumed that would mean something to Milo, which, of course, it didn't. Last Milo had seen, Harry was still carrying the Plot around with him. Maybe Sirius was on there, somewhere, but Milo couldn't remember for the life of him.

"I'm Milo Amastacia-Liadon," Milo said, holding out his hand. "Pleased to meet you." It was amazing what a difference a few extra ranks in Diplomacy could mean, even purchased cross-class. He'd come to learn that there was a lot more dialogue in this campaign world than the one he was used to.

The man stared at Milo's hand, as if he wasn't sure what it was for. He blinked, as if remembering, suddenly, and awkwardly shook it.

"So," Milo said, "what were you doing back there in the forest?"

"Watching," he said. "For some reason, the Death Eaters have gotten into their heads again that forests are private. And now that... he's back, I decided someone had to keep an eye on them. Then my supposedly-dead cousin and you appeared, and I had to act or they'd finish you off." He flicked his eyes over Milo again. "Whoever you are."

"You're Bellatrix's cousin?" Milo was surprised. It was easy to forget that villains sometimes had family, too. He was suddenly keenly aware that he was low on magic, in a small, enclosed space with a man who could turn into a giant dog.

"Estranged cousin."

Milo resisted the urge to say 'Lestranged Cousin,' and felt just a little satisfied at his success. If that wasn't Character Development, he didn't know what was.

"So, what are you, a werewolf or something?" he asked. Everyone was always saying there were werewolves in the Forbidden Forest; it seemed semi-plausible that there were some in this one, too. Of course, it was patently absurd that there were werewolves living in any forests at all, being bog-standard human 27 days a month, but that didn't seem to stop them.

"No, thankfully," Sirius said. "I'm an Anima, Gus."

Milo blinked. "A spirit? And I'm Milo."

"No, an Animagus. I can turn into an animal."

"Oh. Like how McGonagall can turn into a cat." Milo was always careful around shapeshifting magic. While technically it wasn't forbidden, like the Candles of Invocation were, the gods kept their eyes on those who abused it. Milo didn't trust himself not to—in fact, he wasn't even sure it could be used in a non-abusive manner—so he'd stayed well clear of Polymorph and its ilk, despite the phenomenal power those spells offered.

"You've met Minerva?" Sirius glanced at Milo's robes. "You're a student," he said. "I don't suppose you've met Harry Potter?"

"Loads of times," Milo said. "We share a dorm, and fight evil together, on occasion."

Sirius chuckled. "Why am I not surprised? Tell me, how is he—"

"Hands in the air, dirtbag," said a voice.

Milo almost jumped out of his skin, complying immediately. Had his secret hideouts been compromised? Was it just this one, or all of them? Could the Death Eaters somehow track his Teleport magic? Or was it Aurors? The DMLE? Had he taken the blame for the Basilisk attacks in Hogwarts?

Sirius raised his hands, too, looking grim. They both turned to face the door together, and Milo's jaw dropped open.

It was Hannah Abbot, wand aimed menacingly at Sirius. Mordenkainen was perched on her shoulder, explosive knut-launcher (slightly chewed) held at the ready. Milo prayed he didn't use it; the blast would easily vaporize everyone in the room, including himself.

"Hannah?" Milo goggled.

"Don't worry," Hannah said. "You can lower your arms." She glared at Sirius as he began to do so, too. "Not you," she said in a hard voice.

Milo blinked. "I don't even know what question to ask," he said. "Let's start with 'what' and work our way down through 'why,' take a detour on 'how', and end off with another 'what,' maybe."

"I'm rescuing you," Hannah said, as if it was obvious.

"Oh. Good."

"From him," Hannah gestured at Sirius.

Milo looked at the scruffy shapechanger. "Um. Why?"

"Don't you know who he is?" Hannah asked. "That's Sirius Black."

"Yeah..." Milo said. "I feel like that's supposed to mean something to me, but it actually doesn't."

"He's a murderer," Hannah said. "He escaped Azkaban."

The penny dropped. Bellatrix supposedly died in Azkaban, but instead wound up in Milo's world. Her cousin, also a killer, also escaped Azkaban.

"You got Bellatrix out of Azkaban," Milo said. An idea hit him. "Detect Evil," he cast. A minor ability of his Prestige Class, Rainbow Servant, allowed him to cast the spell at-will. It was supposed to highlight evil creatures and people with a glow strength depending on their level. Of course, the local people and creatures didn't seem to have levels, and Milo was uncertain that they even had Alignments. Good, Evil, Law, and Chaos seemed somewhat more… fluid here.

Sirius stubbornly refused to glow, however. Whether that meant that he wasn't evil or if the spell simply wouldn't work here, Milo wasn't certain. Unfortunately, he couldn't simply test this by casting Detect Good on Hannah, as it wasn't a spell Wizards had access to.

"I absolutely did not," Sirius said firmly. "I don't know how Bellatrix escaped, but it's absolutely impossible that she did so the same way that I did."

"Don't listen to him," Hannah said. "He killed twelve Muggles—that we know of. He might have done more; he never confessed."

"I never killed any Muggles," he said in a quiet voice. Milo was keenly aware of the difference between his statement and 'I never killed anyone.' Still, who was Milo to judge? When it came to stopping bandit raids, Adventurers were not generally known for taking prisoners.

Besides, there'd been a war. Milo didn't doubt there had been blood on both sides—though which side Sirius was on had yet to be established.

"Then I think we need an explanation," Milo said. "Who are you, where did you come from, how did you get out of Azkaban, and why are you here?"

Sirius sighed. "The other prisoners were acting up," he began. "They were excited. The guards don't like excitement—or rather, they like it a little too much, so that was rare. Unheard of, actually. It took me a long time to find out why, and even longer to work up the effort to want to find out." Milo had no idea what that was supposed to mean, except perhaps that this Sirius fellow might not be the most proactive tool in the shed. "Of course, they thought I was one of their own, so eventually one of them told me. An unexpected upshot of being framed, I suppose." He licked his lips. "It was the Dark Mark," he said. "It began to burn as brightly as ever; a sign that their master was back."

Hannah gasped.

"Hold up," Milo said. "The Dark Mark?"

"It's a sign that... he... marks his inner circle with." If Sirius was surprised by the tangent, he didn't show it.

"Like, a literal sign?" Milo asked. He blinked. "Wait. High-ranking Death Eaters are visibly marked?"

Sirius nodded.

That, of course, struck Milo as sheer idiocy. Tattooing all members of your very-illegal, subversive, criminal organization was beyond idiotic.

There had to be more to it than that, though. Sure, You-Know-Who seemed to make several of the more conventional villain missteps, but he could also be surprisingly devious. Milo was keenly aware that he was one to know, having been thoroughly outsmarted and soundly defeated by him last year.

Milo sat down and thought. He could practically feel the wheels in his head spinning.

He had to look at this from Voldemort's perspective. Why would you brand your own followers? It practically guaranteed that, on thorough inspection, they would be imprisoned on capture as a result. There could be no denial of one's identity as a Death Eater. But evidently that hadn't happened—boatloads of Death Eaters had walked free, Dark Mark or no.

"Was it widely known what the Mark meant?" Milo asked.

Sirius shrugged. "To the general populace, not normally. But the Ministry was well aware of it, as were some of the better-informed members of the public. That may have changed since."

Milo glanced at Hannah.

"This is the first I've heard of it," she admitted.

"So the Mark was a sure sign of guilt, and the relevant people knew it," Milo said. But what if Voldemort put a Dark Mark on an innocent wizard or witch? "Are there any examples of a person known to have the Mark walking free?" Otherwise, it would be a trivial matter to frame an otherwise innocent victim and then set the Aurors on them.

"Several," Sirius said. "But there's three I think you'll be most familiar with. Narcissa and Lucius Malfoy," he said. "And Severus Snape."

Despite himself, Milo stared. "You're not serious," he said. Snape, a Death Eater?

Sirius frowned. "Actually, I am Siri—"

"I'll just head that one off right there," Hannah interrupted. "Sirius, Milo meant 'serious,' with an 'e', as in the opposite of 'silly.' Milo, Sirius mistook you for saying his name."

"Ah," Sirius said. "That happens. Quite a lot, actually. Though most of the misunderstandings in my life were caused by my last name, not my first."

And just like that, in a rare flash of insight, Milo knew what the Dark Mark was really for. Voldemort deliberately marked all of his top minions permanently, knowing full well that it would identify them as criminals. It made sense—from the point of view of someone who was already insane, in any case. Voldemort didn't trust his own people; hardly surprising, considering some of the Death Eaters Milo had met. Given that simple premise, the real use of the Dark Mark became obvious.

The Dark Mark's use as a tool of communication for Voldemort to summon his henchmen was merely an excuse. The real reason his minions were permanently marked was to ensure their loyalty. If they were captured, and the Mark was discovered, they could never fully integrate back into normal society. They were branded. Lucius Malfoy was the perfect example—as much as he tried to appear as a perfectly legitimate businessman, everybody knew in the back of their minds, at least, that he was up to no good. No matter how much he liked to claim that he had simply been bewitched by Voldemort, Ron had told Milo the very first time they'd met what the real truth was. And if eleven-year-old Ron Weasley had been able to see through Lucius's disguise, it was clear that Voldemort's system had worked. Snape was another perfect example—no matter how much Dumbledore insisted that the man had changed, nobody except for the old wizard really trusted him. No wonder the man's hygiene was so poor; there wasn't really any point, anymore, in looking respectable.

Milo blinked. Where had that come from? He was certain he was correct, though the logic was foreign to him. Not a single part of that train of thought relied on knowledge of story conventions or even previous adventuring experience.

"What happened then?" Milo asked. "After you learned that their Dark Marks had become visible." That had probably been how Bellatrix learned that she was about to be summoned back, Milo realized. Her own Dark Mark had begun to burn, just like the prisoners in Azkaban.

"The Azkaban guards, they…" Sirius trickled off, as if unable—or unwilling—to bring himself to remember.

"…they steal your happy thoughts?" Hannah suggested.

Sirius nodded mutely.

Milo shot Hannah a glance. Was this just another one of those things that everyone here knew, that he had somehow missed? But he'd found it practically impossible to get anyone to talk about Azkaban, and the books outside of the Hogwarts restricted section skirted around the topic uncomfortably. It wasn't as if it was secret, so much as if the authors would rather that they themselves didn't know, and wouldn't plague the reader with the knowledge as well.

Milo was aware that wanded wizards were able to read thoughts, and even alter memories (there was a thought to Milo awake at night; he'd have to make a new Amulet of Protection from Evil as soon as physically possible). But deliberately filtering for happy memories to remove? That just seemed…

Well, if the prisoners weren't crazy going in, they'd sure be crazy coming out.

"Locate Object: Sirius's Wand," Milo cast under his breath, disguising it as a cough. The spell didn't turn up anything, suggesting at least that Sirius couldn't use magic on them if he turned violent (possibly explaining his inability to Apparate earlier, though Milo remained uncertain whether or not Apparition required a wand). Though, of course, there was still the matter of his ability to transform into a giant, fanged dog.

Sirius shook himself, a curiously canine act, and the haunted look disappeared from his eyes. "But I knew that, if he ever came back, he'd go for Harry immediately. That wasn't a happy thought, so they left me with it." He swallowed again. Wordlessly, Milo handed him an Everfull Mug (Relkin kept hers in the same pocket that Milo had kept his). Sirius took it and drank gratefully. "I latched onto that thought, and I knew I had to get out. I might be the only one who knew that he was back; the only one that could warn Harry."

"But how did you actually do it?" Milo asked. Again, he didn't know what sorts of defences Azkaban might have, but it was enough to keep the most dangerous wizards and witches locked up in there for decades. Yesterday, Milo would have said that that would be an easy enough task—just take away their wands and put up similar defensive spells to Hogwarts', keeping would-be rescuers from Apparating in. But now… Riddle had almost killed him without a wand. It seemed like no matter how much he read about magic in this world, there was always a new rule or power to be learned in another book.

"It took me six weeks to come up with a plan, and six more to remember it when the guards took the idea away from me. I had to write it in my own blood, because the thought of escape was a happy one, and could never stay in my mind. But the core of it, the driving force that kept me going… it was anything but. That he had returned, and would finish what he'd started, so many years ago.

"It took me months to remember how to use my powers and work up the will to do so. For weeks at a time, I forgot that's what I was even doing. But then, one day when the guards opened the cell door to give me food, I slipped past them as a dog. They don't see the world the way we do, and a dog's emotions were too simple for them to understand. They were confused. Blind. From there, I swam to shore, and I've been following him ever since. I can't… I don't remember where Harry lives. They took that, too."

Well, Milo wasn't about to tell him. But something that Sirius said rang alarm bells in his mind.

"They can't see? Who the hells is guarding this place?"

Sirius shivered slightly, but didn't say anything. Milo glanced at Hannah, whose face was pale.

"Dementors," she whispered reluctantly, as if it were a vile curse word.

Hm. Well, clearly they had the local wizards and witches terrified, but Milo wasn't unduly worried. If their main power was draining happy thoughts, they probably wouldn't affect him, much in the same way that Riddle's Cruciatus curse hadn't really affected him. It would suck, probably, but he doubted it would really inhibit him in combat. For all he knew, they wouldn't even be able to see him.

"Do you mind waiting here a moment?" Milo asked Sirius. "I need to confer with my confederate, here. Mordy can keep an eye on you."

Sirius eyed Milo's rat suspiciously, paying close attention to its paws for some reason, but nodded.

Milo and Hannah walked to the cave entrance.

Once they were out of view, Milo pulled her into a hug.

"I didn't think I'd ever see you again," he said.

"I was about to say the same," Hannah said, giving one of those laughs that a person gives when they want to pretend something is funny, knowing full well that both people know it isn't, but also knowing that everyone knows that and won't mention it. People are strange, sometimes. "What happened to you? I thought… Oh, this is going to sound stupid. I thought you were dead."

"I was," Milo said. "Sirius was right about You-Know-Who being back. He, uh… he was, um." Milo briefly debated concealing the fact that he'd been possessed for about a year, but decided against it. He'd probably done some mighty suspicious things, and for all he knew, Hannah and the others thought he'd gone evil. Or maybe that he always had been. "He was sort of living in my head ever since we fought Quirrell back in First Year. I don't fully understand it, but apparently he had a part of himself living in a book, which, like an idiot, I straight-up copied into my brain with a spell."

"So… you were Slytherin's Heir?"

"Sort of, yeah. He could take over, sometimes, and I'd just wake up after time had passed. He had me block off secret passages in Hogwarts with Illusory Wall to give the Basilisk free run of the place. At first, he wanted to get Dumbledore fired by threatening the students—but notice how he never killed anyone? Well… almost never. I think he didn't want Hogwarts to close. I think… I think he likes it there. And then he targeted McGonagall, getting Snape—one of his own people—put in charge."

"What about your amulet?" Hannah asked. "I thought you couldn't be possessed."

"He jumped me when I had it off," Milo said. "I used it to disable You-Know-Who's possession of Quirrell, causing him to flee. I was vulnerable. And then, well, he had me make a new one for myself with a back door, and that was that."

"Wait. You're not still, you know… possessed, are you?"

"No, I'm clear. He lured me into the Chamber of Secrets and killed me, giving him a new body or something. I was pretty out of it, to be honest. Being resurrected hits 'reset' on status effects like possession."

Hannah froze. "You're a ghost?"

Milo laughed. "Oh, thank gods, no." Milo gave Hannah a (highly compressed) version of his last three days.

"I didn't know you had a sister," Hannah said.

"Neither did I," Milo laughed. "But I'm back now, and I have no intention of dying again. But back to the topic at hand: should we trust Sirius?"

"Wait," Hannah said, her eyes widening. "If your amulet had a backdoor…"

Milo cocked his head to the side, wondering where she was going with this.

"…what about all those amulets you made for the Ministry?" she finished.

Chapter 11: No News is Good News

FERAL CHILD ON THE LOOSE

by Rita Skeeter

Concerning reports were brought to the attention of the Daily Prophet yesterday about a strange and possibly dangerous child calling himself "Milo Amastacia-Liadon."

"He's attacked me and my mates several times," says Gregory Goyle, a soon-to-be third year student. "But no-one ever does anything about it." Goyle declined further comment, citing fears of what Amastacia-Liadon will do to him if he went public with the full truth.

There are several eyewitness reports of him performing dangerous magic on other students without the use of a wand, as some magical children have been known to do in times of stress and danger. Among other incidents, he is said to have temporarily blinded an entire first-year Potions class, and thrown Harry Potter, the Boy Who Lived, from his broomstick during a Quidditch match. He was also found in the school grounds alone with a critically injured first year girl, who was unavailable for comment, who appeared to have suffered serious knife wounds. On several occasions he has caused major damage to Hogwarts school property, including several broken windows. He is reported to have been involved in an elaborate prank to conjure a fully-grown oak tree in the middle of the school, costing taxpayers untold galleons in repairs. On one occasion, he attacked the family of the Boy Who Lived, leading to his arrest by Muggle police officers (Muggles armed with sticks who enforce the will of their queen) last summer. Further, he was among the last to be seen with Professor Quirrell, former Defence Against the Dark Arts professor, before the professor's complete nervous breakdown.

He was thought to have disappeared for good midway through his second year at Hogwarts, immediately after a highly-dangerous magical beast, the Basilisk, was released into the school. The identity of the culprit, claiming to be the "Heir of Slytherin," remains unknown, though some have speculated that it is no coincidence that this wild youth fled the school when the Basilisk was killed.

It is unknown at this time if this child is an orphan or simply a runaway, but what is known is that despite a history of violence and wild behaviour, he has been attending Hogwarts for the last two years and there is nothing to suggest that he will not return for the term starting next week.

Do not approach Milo under any circumstances. If you have any information regarding the identity or whereabouts of this child, who was last seen roaming a park near Bristol, please contact the Ministry immediately, as much for his own safety as for yours.

"We have to find this kid," Amelia Bones said, setting down the Daily Prophet. The strange necklace she'd taken to wearing the last few months dangled from her neck.

"Doesn't that sound like a job for the Improper Use of Magic Office?" Kingsley Shacklebolt suggested lightly. "Besides, we have our hands tied up looking for Black—who, I will remind you, is a killer, not merely a delinquent."

"This takes priority," Bones said, firmly. "He's one of Potter's friends."

"I don't see the connection," Shacklebolt confessed.

"He knows where Potter lives," Bones said.

"And the Prophet just told everyone of that fact." Shacklebolt felt his eyes widen as realization hit him. "Sirius Black."

"We find the kid," Bones said, "and we'll find Black. And Merlin only knows who else. This isn't the number one priority. This is the only priority."

o—o—o—o

"Dangerous, yes, but 'feral' seems a bit much," Milo grumbled, setting down the Daily Prophet. He felt like twelve miles of bad clichés. He'd run out of high-level spells, and was therefore unable to muster up another Teleport the night before, and with Sirius unable to Apparate, they'd both had little choice but to stay the night in his little hidey-hole. Milo didn't trust Sirius further than he could Bull Rush him, and didn't fancy the idea of falling asleep in a confined space with him. As such, he'd had to rely on his least favourite rules loophole: technically, to get his spells back, he didn't need to sleep for eight hours; he simply had to "rest".

Sitting with one's back to the wall staring at a snoring escaped convict may have counted as 'rest,' although it was far from being restful. He was also annoyed by having to once more prepare spells without the benefit of his own spellbook, limiting him to a handful of his chosen spells and those found in Thamior's. Druids never have to deal with this kind of arbitrary inconvenience. It would take him weeks of work and hundreds of pounds of salt to make a new one.

"I can't believe this," Hannah said. She'd dropped by for a quick visit early in the morning, before her parents woke up. Sirius was still asleep in the corner, and honestly, he looked like he needed it. "The Prophet makes it sound like you're a wanted criminal."

"I haven't gotten my Hogwarts letter," Milo said. "Probably because their magic owls couldn't find me while I was heartbeat-impaired."

"The book list is simple enough," Hannah said. "Although the Monster Book of Monsters is a bit of a pain. It came with a consent form, though."

"A what?" Milo knew what the words 'consent' and 'form' meant, individually, but he had no idea what they implied when put together like that.

"It's a form your parent or guardian is supposed to sign," Hannah said. "It's to allow you to go to Hogsmeade on weekends."

"That... could be a problem," Milo said. "My parents live in another universe, and only one of them is even fully-realized. What happens if I can't get it signed?"

"You don't get to go to Hogsmeade," Hannah said.

"Eh," Milo shrugged. "Suits me fine. Anything I want from town I can owl order. Besides," he added, "it's not like they could really keep me from going there if I really wanted to."

"So, what's your plan, then?" Hannah asked curiously.

"Drop by Harry's house, illegally copy his books with Amanuensis, Teleport to King's Cross, board the Hogwarts Express, and enjoy Snape's surprised look when I come back from the dead," Milo said. "No big deal."

"Um," Hannah said. "You might not want to see Harry just yet."

"No problem," Milo said. "I'll drop by your house, illegally copy your books with Amanuensis, Teleport to King's Cross, board the Hogwarts Express, and enjoy Snape's surprised look when I come back from the dead. Why shouldn't I go see Harry?"

"Weeeeerrrrlllllll..."

"Yes?" Milo asked.

"Hermione may have gotten it into her head that you were the Heir of Slytherin," Hannah said. "And she may or may not have convinced some others of this fact."

"Oh," Milo said. "So you're saying if I unexpectedly drop in on Harry, he might think it's an ambush and blast me to smithereens with magic?"

"Maybe," Hannah said. "Probably."

Milo leaned back heavily in his chair, rubbing his forehead. "Hermione," he said, heavily.

"I know, right?" Hannah agreed sympathetically.

"She is too smart for her own good," Milo said. "Or, more accurately, too smart for my own good."

He reached into Relkin's belt and pulled out his Everfull Mug. "Prestidigitation," he muttered, waving his hand over the water inside. In an instant, it was steaming and milky brown, and tasted exactly like spiced cinnamon tea. He took a sip, savouring the sharp aftertaste. "It never hits, but it crits."

Hannah chuckled. "I should probably be heading back," she said. "I'll drop by this evening with my school books, and some rat food for Mordy."

"Wait," Milo said, as she got up to leave. "One last thing."

"Oh?" Hannah asked.

"'Hands in the air, dirtbag?'" he asked lightly.

"Oh," Hannah said, her cheeks colouring slightly. "Well, I'd just been watching a lot of Batman, and, uh, it seemed appropriate..."

"What kind of manservants do they have in this world?" Milo asked.

"What?" Hannah asked.

"A batman—it's a soldier who's assigned to an officer as a servant, right?"

Hannah chuckled. "Forget about it," she said.

After that, they said their goodbyes, and she was off on her broomstick.

"So," a voice behind him said. Milo whirled around, hands at the ready for spellslinging. It was Sirius Black, who wasn't quite as asleep as he had appeared. "Looks like we have more in common than I'd thought."

"How do you mean?" Milo asked.

He held the Daily Prophet. "We're both wanted," he said. "And we both annoyed the same people."

"I don't think I follow," Milo said.

"Do you think it's coincidence that this story broke now, of all times?" Sirius asked. "Yesterday you didn't even exist."

Milo blinked. "You think this is part of You-Know-Who's plan?" he said. "To turn the peasants against me? But it says here to contact the Ministry if I'm found. That's the last people that..." Milo was barely aware that he'd stopped talking. If Hannah was right about the amulets being cursed, then he absolutely could not trust anyone in the Ministry.

"Not his plan," Sirius said. "This has the stink of a Malfoy's touch."

"I am so sick of those guys," Milo said. "And with Snape as Headmaster, they'll basically be running Hogwarts."

"Snivellus?" Sirius's eyebrows climbed up his forehead. "Are you sure you still want to go there in September? It might not be the most hospitable place for you."

"Wouldn't miss it for the world," Milo grinned. "As Head of Gryffindor, only McGonagall can actually expel me, so the baddies can't keep me out. And all the fun happens at Hogwarts."

Sirius shrugged. "It's your call."

"So," Milo said. "As long as we both have nothing better to do, mind telling me what's your history with Snape?"

Sirius grinned. "Pull up a chair."

o—o—o—o

"Bloody hell," Fiona Smythe said, setting down the Daily Prophet on the pub table and sliding it over to Evan Travis. "Does this boy look at all familiar to you?"

The Bring 'em Inn was the sort of pub that was generally full of coppers that wanted nothing more than a quiet drink, some chips, and to forget for a moment that they were coppers. Even when the place was packed to the rafters, it was always quiet, with most of the clientele sitting by themselves, staring into their mugs and trying to think about anything, absolutely anything, other than work.

It was the perfect place for conspiring.

Travis picked up the tabloid and glanced at the picture. "Nope," he said. "But most little boys of a certain age look sort of the same. He probably reminds you of your nephew."

"Read the article," Fiona pushed.

Travis rolled his eyes in a the-thing-I-put-up-with way, and read through the article. A few sentences in, and his smirk was wiped off his face.

"Bloody hell," Travis said, putting the paper down. "You don't think..."

"Just how many wizard children do you think were nicked by coppers in Little Whinging last year?" Fiona asked. "It's him. I know it."

"So say it is," Travis said. "What are we going to do about it? This isn't our responsibility anymore."

Fiona knew that when he said 'we' and 'our,' he meant 'you' and 'your.' As it turns out, telling your therapist during a mandatory psych evaluation that five constables were killed by magic during a raid on a house full of wizards, and that you couldn't remember any of it, because, well, magic, doesn't do your career any favours. Technically, she was still a copper, but 'mandatory indefinite psych leave' wasn't a thing that a job could really bounce back from.

Travis had had the good sense to lie through his teeth and a low enough rank that he'd managed to evade any blame, and had actually been bumped up to fill Fiona's place as police sergeant in the latest round of promotions.

"What do you think I'm doing?" Fiona asked.

Travis sighed. "You're going to Bristol."

"Damn right I'm going to Bristol."

"Fiona, I know you don't want to hear this right now, but it's important that you keep going to your therapy sessions. It's the only way you'll get your job back. You can't just leave."

"Bugger the therapist," Fiona said, standing up.

"Figured you'd say that," Travis said. "Look, I'd come with you, but..."

"I understand." Travis was in a tough position. Between his recent promotion and the lingering black mark of his participation in the doomed police raid last year, there was no way he could take time off now, especially during the manhunt for Sirius Black. He had everything to prove and, now that Hannigan had resigned, few friends among the brass. Or anywhere else, for that matter. As Fiona had found as well, having your life completely turned upside-down by an experience that you couldn't share with anybody wrought havoc on your personal life. "Look after Sprocket while I'm gone. The keys will be under the doormat."

"You're going now?" Travis asked.

"Their term starts in a few days, and he'll be out of reach once he's in their school. There's no time to waste." She grinned, and flashed him a smile. She hadn't felt this excited and, well, purposeful in almost a year. "The game is afoot."

Chapter 12: Hot Fuzz

Someone had seen Milo near Bristol, that someone had recognized him on sight, and had chosen to report it to the Daily Prophet.

Based off of reports from their network of bird watchers, there were three suspected magical homes in the Bristol area that subscribed to the Daily Prophet. Or at least, there had been six months ago; most of her fellow conspirators were now either dead or had moved on with their lives. Of them, only two had any children. One of those seemed to have lost the genetic lottery (assuming genes were even involved), and attended an ordinary public school.

That left a single potential classmate of Milo's in the region: one Hannah Abbot. She had the means, opportunity, and, if Fiona was right, motive to spot the boy and report it. She didn't know how many students were at Hogwarts, but if the Prophet was correct and Milo really had stabbed a girl in his year, it seemed plausible that it had been a friend of hers.

Fiona grinned to herself, putting her files into a bag and disembarking from the train. All she needed was a quick change of clothes and a payphone to call a taxi and she'd finally get the breakthrough she'd been looking for all this time.

o—o—o—o

"Dinner!" Hannah's father called.

Hannah hurriedly stuffed her textbooks into her bag (except for the Monster Book of Monsters, of course, which last she'd seen was still lurking in the shoe closet). Her parents didn't know that she was sneaking out early in the morning and late at night to see Milo, and she intended to keep it that way by avoiding any unnecessary suspicion. They'd never seen her with a textbook in hand during the summer before, and they weren't going to start now.

The evidence packed away, she headed downstairs for dinner.

As she headed down the stairs, she heard a knock at the door, followed by the silvery tinkle of the chimes her mother had hung on the door that announced to the house whenever it was opened.

"Hello?" her mother asked.

Overcome by curiosity, Hannah ducked below the stairwell and listened.

"Ms. Abbot?" said a brisk, businesslike female voice with a faint Scottish accent.

"Mrs. Abbot, thank you. Can I help you, miss..."

"Eskarina Smith, Department of Magical Law Enforcement. Would you mind sparing a moment of your time to answer some questions, ma'am?"

"No, not at all," Hannah's mother said, surprise evident in her voice.

"Do you have a son or daughter approximately thirteen years old?"

"Yes, a daughter. Is she in some sort of trouble?"

"No, ma'am. Nothing like that."

Hannah heard footsteps. "What's going on?" her father asked as he walked to the front door.

"This is Eskarina from the Ministry," her mother said. "She's here because... actually, why are you here, Ms. Smith?"

"We at the DMLE have reason to believe that your daughter may have information pertinent to locating a missing person," Eskarina answered.

Hannah's heart skipped a beat. How had they found her so quickly? Or at all, actually?

"Hannah?" her mother asked incredulously. "If the missing person happens to be a package of Oreo biscuits, maybe."

Hannah bristled. That only happened the one time.

"With your consent, I'd very much like to speak to her."

There was a pause, and Hannah could practically picture the looks her mother and father were exchanging. "Very well," her mother said, finally. "If we can be present."

"Of course, ma'am."

"Hannah!" her father called.

Hannah had already crawled most of the way back up the stairs just so she could convincingly hurry down them from the top.

"Yes?" she asked, rounding the corner to the front hall. Standing there between her parents was a pint-sized witch with ragged, greasy brown hair, dark bags under her eyes, and a black, pointy hat with a brass buckle on the front. She looked like she'd just barely survived some sort of Shampoo Apocalypse, and had come to warn the world of the dangers of proper hair hygiene. And of sleeping, for that matter.

"Hannah, this woman wants to speak with you," her father said. "You don't have to answer her questions if you don't want to, but you do have to be honest. Do you understand?"

Hannah nodded.

"To confirm," Eskarina said, a Muggle-style notebook and pen in hand. "Are you Hannah Abbot?"

"Yup," Hannah said. The witch scribbled down her answer.

"Are you a student at Hogwarts?"

"Yup."

"What year are you in at Hogwarts?"

"Starting my third year tomorrow," Hannah said.

"Have you ever seen this boy," she asked, holding up the photograph of Milo from the Daily Prophet.

"He's a classmate of mine," Hannah said evasively.

"Would you describe this boy as a friend of yours?"

Hannah paused. She didn't want to say anything to this woman that would lead her to the conclusion that she would know anything about where Milo was hiding, but she also didn't want to lie outright. For all she knew, the woman could use magic to tell. "He's in my House," she said, and immediately cursed her wording.

"Excuse me?" the woman said, reaching into her pocket, presumably for a wand. "He's here now?"

"No, no, no," Hannah said hurriedly. "My House at school. House Gryffindor."

"I see," she said, relaxing. "So you take classes together, that sort of thing?"

"Yes."

"Can you positively identify this boy as Milo Amastacia-Liadon?"

Hannah nodded.

"Do you know where he's from?"

Hannah shook her head. "Not exactly. I don't think he's from anywhere in the UK, though."

Eskarine cocked her head sideways. "And why is that?'

"His accent's different. Could be American, maybe."

"I see," the woman said, scribbling in her notebook. "Would you describe Milo as 'dangerous,' Hannah?"

Hannah paused, and thought about it. Was Milo dangerous? She thought about the Redcap, and about the Troll, and about what he'd done to the Death Eaters in the Gryffindor Common Room. On the whole, she thought, yes, he's very dangerous... but he's on our side. She couldn't very well say that, could she, though?

"I'd prefer not to answer."

Eskarina's eyes narrowed. "Has this boy ever harmed you or anyone you know?"

"I'd prefer not to answer." Her mother and father shot her sharp looks, identical, unspoken questions forming on their lips.

"Have you seen this boy at any time in the last seventy-two hours?"

"I'd prefer not to answer."

"Do you know where this boy is right now?"

"I'd prefer not to answer."

Eskarina put her notebook and pen away. "Thank you for your time," she said to the three of them. "That will be all. Have a nice evening." With that, she crisply spun about on the heel of one foot, and walked down to the road.

"Wait!" Hannah's mother called. "What's going on?" But the woman either didn't hear her or chose not to, and quickly walked out of sight. As soon as she was gone, both parents turned to look at Hannah.

She had to warn Milo that the heat was on, but one look from her parents, however, told her that that would have to wait until she could effectively shake them off—a daunting proposal, to say the least. They were likely to be full of questions, now that the woman from the Ministry had implied in front of them that she'd been attacked by this boy at school (which she had, technically, but it hadn't really been her at the time, and it was all a misunderstanding, anyway).

o—o—o—o

Fiona practically skipped down the street, shoving the uncomfortable robes and hat into her satchel as she did. That girl had all but screamed 'I KNOW SOMETHING' at her. Fiona had expected the girl to send her right to Milo, but apparently, she'd opted to cover for him instead (which, then, raised the question: if she hadn't turned him in to the Prophet, who had?). Obviously, she hadn't said anything that would hold up in a proper investigation, but, refreshingly, this wasn't a proper investigation. In fact, as far as Fiona could tell she hadn't even broken any laws—there was no rule against pretending to be part of what was, as far as her government was concerned, a fictional, supernatural, organization to engage in completely consensual conversation. She did feel somewhat guilty about tricking a child, but the last time she'd underestimated magical children, Milo—she was sure it was him—had pinned her partner down with magical tentacles and then called in a crack team to erase her memory. At least, that's what she'd written down before losing said memory.

The next phase of her plan required a little more preparation, a few phone calls, and a fair amount of money, but if she'd gauged the situation in the Abbot household accurately, she reckoned she had two hours at least to prepare—which was, of course, part of her plan, once she'd established that Hannah was likely co-operating with Milo.

o—o—o—o

Black robes and a black hat against the black night sky were virtually invisible, save for the occasional blotted star or silhouette against a tree. Even the most observant person didn't have a hope of following a flying witch at night. It wasn't magic, it was simply human biology.

Which was why, when, two hours later, Fiona spotted Hannah climbing out her bedroom window, she had no intention of trying to track her with her bare eyes alone.

The AM/NIR-7 was a bulky, military headset from the mid-eighties that flooded the world in fluorescent false-colour magentas and oranges, depending on heat or radiation or whatever phlebotinum the thing used to work. After some fiddling with it, she configured it to highlight Hannah in bright white. While very nifty, the thermal goggles weren't strictly legal, but then, she wasn't strictly a copper, and anyway, who was counting? Besides, she was out of her own jurisdiction.

Hannah shot off into the night, and Fiona raced after her on a rented dirtbike. She'd reckoned that the girl would mostly follow major highways to get to her destination (assuming it was out of the city centre, as the Prophet had implied), as she couldn't imagine navigating by broomstick at night would be easy without frequent landmarks.

Fiona was more than breaking the speed limit, but she knew to avoid most of the major speed traps and most patrolled routes. She didn't have to directly follow the flying girl, just make sure she remained in sight at all times. Hannah stopped to check a map and get her bearing every few minutes, each time allowing Fiona to close the distance.

Had it been daytime, Fiona was sure she wouldn't have had a prayer of following the broomstick, which could easily travel at double the bike's speed, and, further, could completely ignore more mundane considerations such as traffic and geography. But as it was, Fiona kept within a few kilometres of the flying girl, until she was abruptly cut off by a speeding lorry, and lost her.

"Dammit," Fiona muttered, pulling over and scanning the skies. Nothing gave off the telltale white glow. She was just about to call it a failure and head back to Bristol to come up with an alternate plan, when she spotted a white, vaguely humanoid shape on the ground. She lifted up the goggles, revealing a scraggly, seemingly-abandoned field that might have once been farmland.

Abandoning her bike by the side of the road, she easily hopped the low stone wall and sprinted towards the figure. Well before catching up to her, however, she simply disappeared.

Fiona lifted the heavy headset again (the thing clocked in at two-thirds of a kilo... her neck was going to take its sweet revenge on her tomorrow, of that she was certain), feeling foolish. In front of her was a solid, adult-sized boulder. Sitting in the middle of a field, as it did, it'd probably caused no shortage of irritation to the former owners of this field.

Could Hannah really have simply vanished? If wizards and witches were capable of Star Trek-style teleportation, that did explain how they managed to get around so easily in their ridiculous robes without arousing suspicion. Had that been how her police raid had been so handily slaughtered last year? If only she could remember...

No. If Hannah could simply will herself around, why on Earth would she fly here on broomstick? She had to still be around somewhere, but was concealed by trickery or sorcery.

Given that she was hiding nearby, and that she couldn't simply turn invisible (or she would have done so en route to this hideaway), it meant that, somewhere nearby, there was a hidden entrance, tunnel, or other hiding place. She'd chosen to land near this rock rather than somewhere else in the field, so it stood to reason that the rock played some part in the hiding place.

Fiona circled the rock, deep in thought. There was no sign of a false door or entrance, and the vegetation wasn't overgrown enough to hide a person—even if it was, she realized, it certainly wouldn't mask their heat signature. Fiona pulled the bulky headset over her eyes once more and scanned the area.

There wasn't any sign of anyone around her...

...wait.

Something... weird... happened when she looked at the rock face with the headset on. A section of the rock, just over five feet across, was simply gone. She pulled the headset off, and stared at it again, this time fishing for her torch.

Sure enough, now that she looked at it in plain light, a large, square chunk of rock wavered indistinctly in front of her, revealing a passageway beyond.

"Hello..." she murmured to herself, entering the tunnel. She had to stoop to enter, and for once was grateful that she was, well, somewhat vertically challenged.

She crept down the tunnel silently, staying to the shadows wherever possible. Before long, it widened into a small, square room with some crude, handmade-looking wooden furniture. Lining the walls was enough obsolete weaponry to give Sauron pause, as well as other simple survival gear (including some literal torches).

The room, however, seemed to be completely empty of any inhabitants. Just to be certain, Fiona scanned the area with her thermal goggles, but she didn't spot anyone. There was, however, a mug of tea on the table—and, judging by the glow it gave off, it was still hot.

Next to the mug was a copy of yesterday's Daily Prophet, and a map of the world with a big hole stabbed through the paper roughly over her current position, as well as a handful of other markings across Britain. Fiona donned on some rubber gloves from her bag (old habits are hard to break) and held the map up to the light of her torch. She spotted a few slight deformations in the surface, and flipped the map over, revealing a hand-sketched area that Fiona realized corresponded to the surrounding field.

Fiona flipped the map over again, and made a mental note of the locations of the other X's. What were they? Magical settlements? Other hideouts? Targets of some kind?

And what was with all the crossbows? For the life of her, Fiona couldn't fathom why a witch would need a weapon, much less an archaic one.

And where had Hannah and the others gone? There didn't seem to be any more hidden passageways, and they had to have been here recently—the tea was evidence enough of that.

Fiona sighed, and, deciding that she must have just missed them, settled in to do some more rigorous investigation of the little hideout.

o—o—o—o

"That was way too close," Hannah muttered as she re-oriented herself after the Teleport, which was easy enough, considering that the new bolt hole they found themselves in was largely identical to Milo's previous one.

"Agreed," said Milo. "But how did they know you were with me?"

Sirius shrugged. "Process of elimination. Can't be too many classmates of yours living in the area."

"But how did they find my hiding place?" Milo asked. "I put so much work into that!"

"Are you sure they did?" Sirius asked.

Milo nodded. "I had an Alarm spell up. Someone triggered it after Hannah got in."

"Then she must have been followed," he said. "Difficult, but possible. Most likely with an invisibility cloak and a broomstick." He grinned wryly. "It's how I'd have done it. More to the point, though, we need to keep moving."

Milo snorted. "Come, now. That can't be needed. There's no possible way they'll find us here. We Teleported, we didn't fly."

Sirius shook his head. "Doesn't matter—we left the map behind."

Milo shrugged. "That will only help them if they find their way through the illusion, which would take an exceptionally strong Will. Back when I cast it, I was buffed like you wouldn't even believe."

"You don't get into the DMLE by collecting bottle caps," Sirius said. "I wouldn't count on your magic to keep them out."

"Well, then where can we go?" Hannah asked.

"I think I know a place," Sirius said. "It won't be terribly comfortable, but I can guarantee, nobody will think to look there."

o—o—o—o

Mrs. Abbot was woken up by knocking at her door. She climbed out of bed, pulled on a housecoat and stepped into some slippers, and went downstairs to see who it was. Mr. Abbot was not far behind her.

"Hello?" she asked, opening the door.

"Mrs. Abbot?" a friendly-looking man in deep purple robes asked.

"Yes, that's me," she said.

"I'm Kingsley Shacklebolt, with the Department of Magical Law Enforcement," he said. "Would you mind sparing a moment of your time to answer a few questions?"

Chapter 13: Passing Notes

"Protection from Good," Milo cast on the silver, palm-sized Eye of Boccob on the desk in front of him. In his experience, it never hurt to have a couple of extra holy symbols around for when the vampires come knocking. This time, just in case, he'd created the amulet while under the effects of a separate Protection from Good spell. So even if Riddle was somehow still in his mind, he wasn't exerting any influence over this amulet. He wished he had his old spellbook back so he could cast the marginally more helpful Protection from Evil, but he might as well wish for a Candle of Invocation or the moon. He'd just have to make do with what he had, for now.

"Are you almost done yet?" Hannah asked, her arms wrapped around herself for warmth. For all that it was late summer, it was also the middle of the night, and the hovel Sirius had brought them to was far to the north. The thin glass windows (where they weren't broken) and ancient wooden walls provided little in the way of insulation.

Milo nodded. "Just finished," he said, clipping the amulet around his neck. The plot was thickening fast, and he had absolutely no intention of going anywhere without his customary Amulet of Protection—especially considering that the Ministry was after him, and they weren't known to use restraint when it came to memory modification. Still, he had to be careful crafting items for now, because he was only a hair over the threshold of level nine, and didn't have any XP to waste.

"So can we go home, now?" Hannah asked.

Sirius shook his head. The cold didn't seem to bother him as he reclined in the shabby, rat-eaten chair. "I don't recommend it. They'll be watching your house. Your disappearance will have confirmed for them that you're an accomplice with Milo, here."

"My parents will be freaking out," Hannah said. "Could I at least get a message to them?"

Milo scratched his chin. "I don't have any specialized long-range communication spells, and I've only got enough juice for one more Teleport," he admitted. "And that's if I burn all but one of my fourth-level spells. I could deliver a message, but I'd be stuck there. Sirius?"

Sirius shrugged. "They took my wand when they threw me in Azkaban," he said. "You'd have to lend me yours," he said to Hannah. "I don't have a House Elf's hope of casting a Patronus, so I'd have to Apparate there with a letter." He sighed. "But..."

"...we'd have no guarantee you wouldn't simply run off with my wand?" Hannah said.

"Yeah," Sirius said.

"I'd lend you mine," Milo said, "except that a certain dretch-lover has his bony little hands on it. And most of my other swag."

Hannah shrugged. "Okay," she said, and passed her wand, butt-first, to Sirius.

"Are you insane?" Milo choked.

"Trust me," she said.

Sirius stared at the wand as if she'd just offered him the world. In a way, Milo supposed, she had. Milo imagined he might feel much the same way when he finally got his hands on his old spellbook.

"Thank you," he said, accepting the wand. To Milo's astonishment, there were actual tears in his eyes. Hannah scribbled a quick note on a scrap of parchment from Relkin's Belt of Hidden Pouches. "You won't regret this," he said, taking the note and Disapparating with a pop.

"I repeat," Milo said, turning to Hannah. "Are you insane?"

"Think about it," Hannah said. "Now we get to test, with a reasonable degree of certainty, if we can trust him. If he returns the wand, we trust him. If he makes a run for it, we can't."

"What if he comes back to tie up the loose ends?" Milo asked.

"Have you ever seen a wizard try to cast magic with someone else's wand?" Hannah asked. "It usually takes a half-dozen tries to get even the simplest of spells working. If he comes back for us, just blind him with your glittery dust, or conjure up some tentacles to grab him, or trip him with grease. You know—the usual. If you have to, shatter the wand. I can always buy a new one."

Milo's jaw opened and shut involuntarily as he tried to come up with a counter-argument. "That's actually a pretty clever plan," he conceded grudgingly. "Reckless," he added. "But clever. So, what'd you tell your parents?"

"The truth," Hannah said. "Anything else would only complicate the situation further. But I used language that only they'd know, so if the DMLE finds the note, it won't mean anything to them. I also asked them to bring my school stuff to King's Cross tomorrow." As she spoke, her stomach rumbled noisily.

"Hungry?" Milo asked, pulling his Everlasting Rations out of his belt. Seeing as how he probably wasn't going to be able to return it to its original owner any time soon—if ever—he decided to stop thinking about it as 'Relkin's Belt.'

"Thanks," Hannah said. "I ran off before I had a chance to eat dinner." She reached into the bag and pulled out a handful of crunchy, greyish, vaguely round blobs. "Ah," she said. "These again."

"Sorry," Milo said. "I'm out of Prestidigitations, so I can't do anything about the taste."

Hannah shrugged. "There's a Charm the Weasley twins were telling me about last year that makes anything taste like peach cobbler," she said. "They use it whenever their father cooks. But I don't have my wand, and even if I did, I can't use magic in the summer."

Milo had heard about that rule, of course, but he hadn't really thought about it before. "That sucks," he said. He'd already only had to spend less than a week with reduced spell casting capacity after Voldemort took his spellbook, and it was really starting to wear on him. He couldn't imagine having to go for two months without using any magic at all.

"Yeah," Hannah said. "And it's the most surefire way I can think of to keep us from remembering anything we learned the year before. Before Hogwarts, I went to Muggle school—my parents didn't know if I'd take after my mum or my dad when it came to magic—and it was hard enough remembering, say, maths after the summer. But even then, I mean, I never did, but theoretically, I could have cracked open a textbook and brushed up during the break, right? But with magic, doing a bit of summer revising is illegal. Which is annoying, because unlike maths, floating feathers around is actually pretty fun."

Milo could hardly speak. He'd just heard what had to be the most horrifying thing he'd ever encountered. "You..." he pulled himself together. "You forget your skills if you don't use them?"

Hannah nodded.

"I mean," Milo continued, "you actually get worse? Not like, maybe getting a bit rusty and not realizing what the most effective spell to cast in a given situation is," Milo knew full well that feeling, having been thrown against a Dragon Turtle shortly after returning to his world, after only fighting wizards and the occasional Redcap for a year, "but actually forgetting how to cast the spell?"

"Yeah," Hannah said. "Not just magic, everything. Languages, facts, talents. Physical stuff, too—if we go without exercise, we get unhealthy. Is it really not like that for you?"

Milo shook his head. "I've never actually had the opportunity to speak so much as a whole conversation in Draconic," he said, "but I'm still fluent in the language. And always will be."

Hannah gave a low whistle. "Sometimes, I forget how different you are," she said.

"And so do the Death Eaters," Milo grinned. "Nobody has yet hatched an evil scheme that relies on me not perfectly remembering minutiae from years ago, but one day, someone will. And when they do..."

Milo was planning on finishing that sentence with something machismo-laden like 'bam!' before performing a pantomime punch, but instead, he was cut off by the distinctive pop! of Apparition, which he supposed worked almost as well.

Milo turned to find Sirius Black standing behind him.

"I left your letter on the kitchen table," he said, returning Hannah's wand. In his other hand, he held up a large paper bag with a bright-yellow 'M' printed on it. "I also brought dinner," he said.

"Detect Poison," Milo muttered under his breath, but the bag came up clean. He nodded to Hannah, who casually tossed the tasteless Everlasting Rations behind her and leapt at the paper bag in a manner reminiscent of a Dire Lion taking down a gazelle.

Milo forced himself to re-evaluate Sirius Black. Maybe, just maybe, he could trust this strange, fugitive shapeshifter after all—a welcome revelation, all things considered, as until he could clear up this whole 'Heir of Slytherin' business, his list of allies was remarkably short.

Either way, this whole 'on the run' business was about to come to an end. Tomorrow, one way or another, he was boarding the Hogwarts Express and going to school. Hogwarts was where the action was, where the plot happened, and where the Experience Points lay about just waiting to be claimed. The Death Eaters wouldn't dare make a move on him there—well, they had last year, now that Milo thought about it, but it had hardly been easy for them. And if the Ministry decided to have him arrested, well, they could try. In his experience, there were two distinct strands of law enforcement, depending on who had been irritated. The first was sent when a PC made an enemy of someone powerful, and were generally low-to-mid-level government employees just there for the paycheck, and could be reliably defeated in droves. If that was the case, Milo wasn't worried. But the other kind only appeared if a PC had made an enemy of the DM ('Dispassionate Moderator'), in which case, they would have at least ten levels of experience on the party, have access to unfeasibly expensive hardware for a government agency, and come in groups of essentially infinite. And if that was the case, well, Milo still wasn't worried—there wouldn't be anything he could do.

Come to think of it, though, he had been pushing the DM pretty hard of late.

To test a hypothesis, Milo reached out and tapped one of the shack's interior walls, to see if it would devolve into a pile of hundreds of quarterstaves.

Nothing happened.

Milo wondered: was that because the DM (or the gods, for that matter) had altered the nature of the universe after he had revealed such an easily-exploitable flaw, was it because of the different nature of this world versus the other one, or was it, most concerning of all, because this world had a different DM than the other one? One who made different calls, and with different motivations?

Milo's food went cold in front of him, untouched, as he drifted among his own thoughts.

o—o—o—o

Fiona woke up, and immediately wished she hadn't.

Her left leg was on fire.

She wasn't supposed to be running on it yet, possibly ever. Hell, she wasn't even supposed to be walking without a cane. Getting shot is like that, sometimes—hardly ever like in the movies, where Bruce Willis can shrug off numerous gunshot wounds in one movie and walk in on the beginning of the next with nothing to show for it but a cool scar, if that. She never did find out how she'd taken a bullet to the thigh, as those bloody wizards had taken her memory from that night, but just because she couldn't remember being shot was no reason she shouldn't remember that she had been shot. She'd just gotten so caught up in the moment, the hope that she might finally get some answers, that nothing else seemed to matter.

Her neck was hardly in better shape, having had to support a ludicrously heavy piece of military-surplus hardware for most of the night before. She wanted nothing more than to stay in bed for another hour or twelve, as even the thin mattress of the cheap motel she was staying in felt incredible in her state. She also wanted to go home, to see Sprocket, and to read a good book.

As much as she wanted to, however, she knew she couldn't. Today was the first day of term for the wizarding world, and every student attending Hogwarts was going to be at King's Cross station, according to the Daily Prophet and Hogwarts: A History. It was too good of an opportunity to pass up, much as she'd like to.

She pulled herself out of bed reluctantly, tucked the disaster that was her hair into a pony tail, threw some clothes on, grabbed her bag, and left. The sun had yet to rise, but it was all the same to her. She barely ever slept more than an hour or two at a time these days, anyway, so all this meant was that the walk to the train station would be a quiet one.

o—o—o—o

"—eleport."

King's Cross was the same as ever, albeit with a non-moving, Muggle poster or two up warning passersby that the dangerous criminal, Sirius Black, was on the loose after having escaped from an unnamed prison.

Milo wondered just how much co-operation there was between the Muggle and magical governments. Were the people at the top well aware of the magical world's existence? Was the Muggle ruler a wizard himself? (Or witch herself; Milo neither knew nor particularly cared who was in charge on the Muggle side of things). Or had the magical government simply planted some false evidence, and memories, in front of the right people to make them take the steps they'd wanted?

All that was quite irrelevant, of course. Milo didn't know what role Sirius Black was to play in whatever Voldemort's evil scheme was going to be this year (he always seemed to have one), but it had nothing to do with his problem at the moment: getting onto the Hogwarts Express, and getting to Hogwarts, despite being pursued by the DMLE. Why he was being pursued, he wasn't totally clear, but he very evidently was, which was what mattered in this case.

"Invisibility," he muttered as soon as he arrived, and disappeared from view.

"Hey," Hannah whispered.

"Yeah?" Milo whispered back.

"If you're invisible," Hannah said, "can you see when you close your eyes?"

Milo frowned. "No..." he said, though he couldn't figure out why that would be the case. If his eyelids were invisible, why couldn't he see with his eyes closed?

"Weird. I'm going to go find my parents and my luggage. I'll meet you in front of the train, okay?"

"Sounds like a plan," Milo said.

Hannah turned to leave, but froze. "Do you see that woman over there?" she asked, covertly pointing at a dishevelled-looking, dark-haired woman in a wrinkled man's shirt several sizes too large for her, whose sleeves looked like they'd been rolled up a half-dozen times just so her wrists could poke out. She had heavy bags under her eyes, and leaned against a pillar surreptitiously facing Platform Nine and Three-Quarters with a wooden cane within easy reach. "She was the one who came to talk to my family. She had a bunch of questions about you and if we knew where you'd been hiding. She's with the DMLE."

Milo narrowed his eyes and started counting the adjectives. "No, she isn't," he said. He'd seen her once before, when she'd arrested him in Harry's house—but she'd been in the uniform of the local city watch, then. What he hadn't ever seen before, however, was a random mook show up again, having apparently gained characteristics since then. Whoever this NPC was, she was clearly highly significant.

"How long do we have until the train leaves?" Milo asked.

"Uh..." Hannah consulted her wristwatch, "twenty minutes."

"Save me a seat," Milo said, and strolled towards the mysterious woman.

o—o—o—o

Fiona nearly jumped out of her skin when a piece of paper was pressed into her hand, despite the fact that there was no-one within five meters of her.

She reached into her bag and pulled out her well-worn copy of The Restaurant at the End of the Universe, and read the note such that the book was hiding it from view—ironic, considering she'd first learned that trick to read the very same book hidden inside Principles of Maths 11 to keep it out of view of her teacher, Mrs. Haversham.

The note was written on a thick, heavy material that Fiona was surprised to find wasn't paper at all, but some sort of thin animal skin.

Walk slowly towards the corner by the door with the big red glowing EXIT sign. Come alone.

P.S. that came out more villainous than I'd intended.

Well... that wasn't creepy or anything.

If it hadn't been for the fact that whoever had given her the note had clearly used magic to do it—nobody could sneak up on her like that—she'd assume that following the instructions would be walking right into a mugging. Most likely, whoever it was was simply going to erase her memory again, which was something Fiona was willing to risk, seeing as how she'd already written the day's events in a journal, and was wearing a wire to boot. Nevertheless, it was a decidedly creepy thing to do, giving someone a note like that out of the blue.

Curiosity overcame common sense, and she decided to follow the note's directions.

The corner the note mentioned was as good as one could find in such a public place for a secret meeting. It was out of direct line of sight both of the entrance and of Platform Nine and 'Three-Quarters,' and one of the lights nearby seemed to have burnt out, shading it in a modicum of darkness.

She was hardly there for a second before a boy appeared beside her. He was wearing black robes with a silver trim and an honest-to-goodness Batman-esque utility belt, complete with dozens of pouches. A massive brown and white rat sat on his shoulder, mimicking his expression disconcertingly.

"Milo," Fiona said, nodding. She didn't remember their last encounter, but her own notes mentioned that she'd managed to handily subdue him with a billy club, and he didn't have his wand out. She shifted her weight, and her grip on her cane. She didn't have her billy club this time, but she did have two-and-a-half feet of solid wood, which was at least as good.

"You know my name?" Milo asked. "Who are you?"

Fiona shrugged. "Someone inquisitive," she said.

"That is spectacularly unhelpful," Milo said. "Look, I recognize you from Little Whinging, unless you have an identical twin, and—wait. Do you have an identical twin? If so, we should probably get that whole misunderstanding out of the way sooner, rather than later. Dramatic irony is fun and all, but it isn't terribly productive."

Fiona shook her head, somewhat bewildered. This wasn't how she expected this meeting to go at all. In her mind, this strange wizard child had always been something of an evil mastermind, manipulating events behind the scenes. But she was fast facing the possibility that he really was as mad as the Daily Prophet had made him out to be. "No, I don't have a twin," she said.

"Great. Anyway, look, I'll just cut to the Initiative roll here: why were you pretending to be with the Ministry? And what's your interest in Hannah Abbot?"

"Why do you think I'm only pretending to be with the Ministry?" Fiona asked.

"Because you're with the city watch..." Milo frowned. "Unless you're a witch who was pretending to be a Muggle? Honestly, I hadn't considered that."

Fiona simply shrugged. She didn't know where this conversation was going, but it seemed like keeping Milo off-guard would only work in her favour. "Now, I have a question for you: why did you attack that family in Little Whinging?"

"Who, them?" Milo asked. "Uh... they were being pretty awful to a friend of mine."

"Harry Potter?" Fiona asked. She'd read a lot about this 'Boy Who Lived' in the books she'd bought from Diagon Alley. Apparently he was viewed as some sort of saviour-slash-minor-messiah-type-character by the magical community after he somehow defeated an improbably-named hardened criminal as a baby.

"Yeah," Milo said. Then his eyes narrowed. "What's your interest in Harry?" The boy shook his hands free of his sleeves and flexed his fingers in a way not unlike a gunslinger from a Western. Despite his lack of wand, Fiona recognized his body language: the boy clearly considered himself armed and dangerous.

"None," Fiona said honestly. "Though if there was some sort of abuse going on, there are steps I can take."

Milo shrugged. "I already took care of it."

"You mean threatening his aunt and uncle at swordpoint?" Fiona asked.

"Pretty much," he said, not, apparently, much caring that he'd as good as confessed to a crime. "Detect Object: Wand," the boy muttered under his breath.

Fiona tensed. The boy had said it in the rote, slightly sing-songy way of a memorized, oft-repeated phrase that's meaning was quite devoid of the actual words said. She was pretty certain, in short, that he'd cast a spell—without a wand.

"You're no witch," Milo said. "How did a Muggle like you even find out that the Department of Magical Law Enforcement exists? What's your angle, watchwoman?"

"I just want answers," Fiona said. "How did the magical government arrange for the British police to hunt for Sirius Black? Why did those wizards and witches steal those kids from Hogwarts? Why weren't they arrested by your government? If they're at large, where are they?"

Milo blinked. "You mean Sean, Dean, Thomas and them?"

"Yes," Fiona said. "Although I think Dean and Thomas are actually the same person."

"How do you even know about them?" Milo asked.

"I was part of the police raid that saved them," Fiona said. "Good men and women died that day." And so did my career.

"Lockhart saved them," Milo said. "He fought the Death Eaters off single-handedly. It was all over the papers, Hannah said." Hah, Fiona thought. I knew that girl was in cahoots with him.

"Death Eaters," Fiona said. "Was that who they were? Aren't they what's-his-face's criminal gang?"

"You could call them that," Milo said. "Are you saying that Lockhart lied about saving them?"

"Was that the golden-haired Kenneth Branagh-lookalike?" Fiona said. "Yeah. He took the credit, and my memories." She'd had to do a good bit of investigation to figure that one out; one of the nurses said she saw someone who looked a bit like Hamlet in the halls, and asked for an autograph. It was the first time she'd ever seen a suspect sign their real name during the act.

"Do you mean to tell me that you went up against a gaggle of Death Eaters and won?" Milo asked. "I wish I'd seen Lucius's face when he heard that news," Milo said dreamily. "No wonder they let the story about Lockhart get out; if anything, it's less embarrassing that way."

"Lucius?" Fiona asked. "Lucius Malfoy?" He appeared in the Prophet frequently as a wealthy philanthropist, giving money freely to charitable causes—and, now that Fiona thought about it, probably a certain magical news media corporation, as well.

"Yeah, he's basically their leader," Milo shrugged. "Well, he was until You-Know-Who came back. I imagine that shook things up a bit." The boy glanced up at the large clock on the wall. "Well, I'm out of time. This conversation was interesting, but ultimately unhelpful. I was hoping for more, I don't know, clues. Plot hooks. I guess that Lockhart thing could be relevant. Invisibility."

Without any drama or special effects, Milo vanished from sight.

"Wait!" Fiona said. "I don't know who!" But it was to no avail; the boy was gone.

Despite what the strange boy seemed to think, though, this conversation was highly profitable—just not for him, maybe. Because now she had a name.

Lucius Malfoy...

o—o—o—o

Milo slipped through the solid-seeming wall at Platform Nine and Three-Quarters just as the Hogwarts Express started it's... Milo's mind blanked on the technical terminology. It was doing the thing where it made a lot of noise just before it started moving. The doors had already shut.

"Dimension Door," Milo muttered, and suddenly he was in the train's central hallway.

He strolled down the hallways, glancing through the windows into the compartments, until he found Hannah. The seat next to her was empty, and Neville sat across from her.

"Hey," Milo said.

Hannah jumped. "Milo! Don't sneak up on people like that!"

"Sorry," Milo said. He'd forgotten he was still invisible, and dismissed the spell. "Did I miss anything?"

"Nope," Hannah said.

"It's the Hogwarts Express," Neville said. "What could possibly happen?"

Milo nodded his agreement to that, and sat down next to Hannah. "So I take it you don't think I'm a lunatic feral child?" he asked.

Neville shrugged. "You saved me from poison back in first year," he said. "You're fine in my books, even if you were raised by wolves."

Milo grinned, and leaned back, ready to enjoy a lengthy and uneventful trip.

As Hannah had said—it was the Hogwarts Express. What could possibly happen?

Chapter 14: The Hogwarts Express

"H-Hannah?" Milo asked, stunned. Gods, what have I done?

There was no response.

"Okay," Milo said, out loud. "I'll go find her, and she'll be fine. Just... fine. You'll see."

Milo stood up from his prone position, shaking off snow. He waded through the deep snow to where Locate Object told him Hannah lay.

He felt as if he was drowning in cold. The air, the snow, even his own clothing, felt like ice water.

"Hannah?" Milo called again, yet was again unanswered.

Abruptly, the snow stopped blocking Milo's vision, revealing an old tree that might have been a willow. Hannah lay against it, slouched into a half-sitting position. Her wand was held loosely in her right hand; her left was clutching the hilt of Milo's dagger. It was sticking out of her stomach. It was difficult to tell—her school uniform was black, after all—but there was a lot of blood. A scary amount of blood. Her head lolled to her the side, and she wasn't moving.

And it was all Milo's fault.

Hannah stirred feebly, and reached for her wand.

"E... e..." she said weakly.

"Hey, Hannah," Milo said gently. "You'll be okay, okay? I've... I've got a Healer's Kit and +1 from Wisdom, so I can do first-aid, okay? So just... don't move." Milo tried to reach for his kit, but found that his arms were locked into place, as if the ice water had frozen completely.

"Ex..."

"Tell me back at the castle, when you explain just what you were doing out here, 'kay?"

"Expecto Patronum!"

"Milo! Milo! Wake up, mate!"

There were lights hanging above him, and he could just barely make out a pink, round face.

"Neville?" Milo asked. The blizzard was gone, as was the tree, leaving only the feeling of ice—and the guilt. "What... what happened?"

"Still happening," said a familiar voice. Milo blinked, trying to clear away the blurriness. He felt slow, and weak. Neville's face slowly came into focus, and Milo saw that he looked the way Milo felt. Worse, even, if that were possible. The normally ever-present, slightly dopey smile was gone, replaced by a pale grimace.

"Ex... ex... expecto... 'specto..."

They were still on the Hogwarts Express, Milo realized. The last thing he remembered was drifting off on the train, confident in his safety. Now, he was lying on the floor of the compartment in a pool of his own sweat. He turned to face the door, and almost wished he hadn't.

Floating in the doorway was a... thing. The best Milo could describe it was a three-dimensional shadow that had taken the form of a tattered, black cloak. It vaguely resembled a Wraith, except that it was exposed to broad daylight through the train's windows and was still alive.

He couldn't make out the majority of its shape, as Hannah stood between him and the shade, wand out, shaking like a gelatinous cube in an earthquake. Or like she was shivering, out in the forest...

A hair-thin tendril of white-grey fog floated between her and the shade, which seemed reluctant to touch it, but it was fading fast.

Hannah was keeping it at bay, but it wouldn't last. She needed help.

Milo pulled himself to his feet and shook his hands out of his sleeves.

Fortunately for her, he was something of an old hat at fighting things that could best be described as 'eldritch.'

"Glitterdust!" he shouted.

Nothing happened. Milo frowned. He hadn't failed a Concentration check, like he had when chased by Death Eaters the other day, so what had happened? He wasn't in an Antimagic Field, or his Belt of Hidden Pouches would have exploded as the non-dimensional space inside each pouch became uncomfortably, well, dimensional.

Maybe he should just try another spell?

"Kelgore's Fire Bolt!" Again, nothing happened. It didn't feel like he'd tried and failed to cast the spell, though, it felt more like...

...like when he'd died. During his sojourn into the Outer Planes, he'd been similarly unable to perform magic.

But he couldn't be dead, could he? He was still in the Material Plane, implying, if he had died, he was more of undead persuasion.

He didn't feel undead, though. He still had a Constitution score, for starters, and his maximum Hit Point count hadn't increased, which was supposed to happen to undead...

Milo froze. His maximum Hit Point count hadn't increased.

It had decreased.

"...specto... patronum..."

The wispy tendril between Hannah and the shade disappeared, and Hannah collapsed to the floor. Pushing aside the problem of his reduced Hit Point total for later, he focused on the problem at hand.

"Summon Skeletal Troll," Milo tried—and failed—to cast, unsure of what else to do.

The shade rounded on him, reaching out what Milo took to be an arm towards him.

Giving up on magic, Milo reached into his bag of tricks, producing a thin glass flask of water with a brass sun stamped on it.

Milo flung the flask at the shade in a hefty overhand throw. "Eat holy water, freak!" he said in a manner he'd intended to be defiant, but it came out a little closer to 'feeble.'

The flask shattered harmlessly against the revenant's torso, accomplishing nothing but making it a little damp.

Milo backed into the corner, almost tripping over Neville, who lay on the floor with his eyes rolled up into the back of his head.

Driven once again to the absolute last resort of any primary spellcaster, Milo reached into his Belt of Hidden Pouches and drew the quarterstaff he'd acquired from his bolt hole's weapon stores.

Milo gripped the staff at one end with both hands and swung it around him with all the strength he could bring to bear (which, bearing in mind that he was a Wizard, was next to none) and swung directly at where the shade's head would be, had it had one.

As he swung, however, he felt his grip slacken and his arms weaken. He heard a clatter ring through the compartment, and belatedly realized that he'd dropped the staff, and the only thing keeping him standing was the wall he was leaning against.

"What are you?" he choked, sliding to the ground.

The shade reached towards him, and its cloak slipped, revealing a pale, rotten hand that gently gripped Milo by the chin. He hadn't felt this helpless since Riddle had drained his soul in the Chamber of Secrets.

"Expecto Patronum!" shouted out an unknown male voice.

A silver-white dog burst into the room, slamming bodily against the shade, pinning it against the wall above Milo. Where the dog's paws and teeth gripped the tattered cloth, steam appeared as if the mere contact of this spectre burned.

"Sirius?" Milo murmured, feeling half-delusional, but as he examined the animal more closely, he realized it was a wolf, not a dog.

The shade managed to slip free of the animal's grasp, and fled through window, scattering shards of glass across the room.

"What was that you said?" asked a man in the hallway. His eyes widened, presumably as he noticed the full extent of the carnage that had occurred in the compartment for the first time. "Never mind that. How are you all feeling?"

"Mrggnnnnnnn..." Hannah groaned, pulling herself up into a sitting position.

The man, who looked more worse for wear than anyone Milo had seen alive, bent over to examine her more closely, careful of the shards of window and holy water flask on the ground. Milo realized belatedly, as he followed the creature's progress out the window, that at some point the train had stopped moving. "I'm sorry, what did you say?" the stranger asked, leaning closer to Hannah.

"I said, 'like my bloody brain got mauled by a bloody bobcat,'" Hannah muttered, holding her hand against her forehead. "Ow."

"What she said," Neville agreed, sitting up. "What happened? Was that a... a..."

"A Dementor," the stranger said solemnly. "Though why someone decided to let one loose on a train full of children escapes me. Eat this," he said, breaking off a piece of chocolate to hand to each of them.

"That's a Dementor?" Milo asked. "What..." he swallowed. "What did it do to me?"

"Nothing that a little chocolate and some time in the sun won't fix," Lupin said. "Best not to dwell on it. Which one of you produced the Patronus?"

"The mist thingy?" Neville asked. "That was Hannah."

"That was a very advanced spell," the man said. "Fifteen points for... uhm..."

"Gryffindor," Hannah said, taking a bite out of the chocolate bar.

"Fifteen points for Gryffindor, then. I'd best be off," he said, "there's still many more students to check on."

"Wait," Hannah said as he turned to leave. "Who are you?"

"Ah, of course," the man said. "I'm Remus Lupin, the new Defence Against the Dark Arts professor. I'll be seeing you all in class tomorrow, I expect." With that, he hurried off, his worn grey robes trailing behind him.

"How did you know how to cast the expecto-whatsit?" Neville asked Hannah curiously, munching away on chocolate.

"After Milo di..." she swallowed slightly. "After Milo disappeared last year, and the Basilisk attacked Hermione, Harry, and Ron in the halls, I sort of thought I should study up on some more advanced defensive magic. That's the first time I'd actually managed to make the spell work, though," she admitted. "And barely, at that."

"It probably saved us," Milo said. "Boccob knows I was completely useless," he added ruefully. "Prestidigitation," he muttered, intending to clean up the glass on the floor, but again, nothing happened. It was almost as if... "Wait," Milo said. "Didn't Siri..." he glanced at Neville, "our furry friend say something about the Azkaban guards draining happy memories?"

Hannah nodded. "Dementors are said to take away your happy thoughts," she confirmed, "including your memories. The only thing that can stop them is a Patronus."

"Let me guess—they also make you relive your worst ones?" Milo asked.

"Sometimes," Hannah said. She gave him a curious look, but didn't press the issue when he changed the subject.

"I think it took my spells," he said. Every morning, he had to memorize the spells he was intending to cast that day, and if the incantation for Glitterdust didn't count as a happy memory, then surely nothing did. Though how it had pulled it off while Milo wore his Amulet of Protection was beyond him—he was supposed to be immune to all forms of mental attack. "...and my Experience."

Hannah's eyes widened. "How can you be certain?"

Milo shuddered. "I'm weaker, now. Much weaker." He took a bite out of the chocolate, and it was like (and Milo was embarrassed to even think this, accurate as it was) taking a bite out of sunshine itself. He swallowed, and felt warmth spread from his stomach outwards. It didn't return his spells or Experience Points, however. He estimated that he'd lost at least two thousand XP, dropping him back down a level—taking his ability to Teleport with it. "Thank you," he said to Hannah, and he really meant it. "If you hadn't intervened, that could have been worse. Much worse."

"Will you... be okay?" Hannah asked.

Milo nodded. "I'll be right as rain as soon as I pound a few monsters' faces in," he said. "Though I doubt I'll roll maximum HP again when I level up." he narrowed his eyes. "Actually, if we can trap a Dementor in a controlled environment, I can use it to repeatedly de-level and level up again in order to get the highest number of HP each time with minimal XP cost. I'll get two free new spells each time, too." Despite the warmth from the chocolate, he shivered slightly at the thought of willingly subjecting himself to the Dementor's attack again. Some memories were best left in the past. "Though I don't expect I'll actually do that. You say the only way to fight them is with this spell?"

Hannah nodded. "Nothing else—not even the Killing Curse—has any effect on them."

"Damn," Milo said meaningfully.

He knew he'd been pushing things pretty far lately, but he hadn't realized that he'd apparently crossed the line enough to make the DM resort to this. Dementors seemed purpose-built to completely destroy him in particular. They could steal his most potent abilities, they could permanently take away his hard-won experience points, and, worst of all, if Hannah was right, he was completely helpless against them.

Milo leaned back against his seat, trying to devise some sort of strategy to deal with these Dementors, if and when he encountered them next. Perhaps a spell like Heroism could counter the happiness-sucking-ness of their attack, but Milo was unable to cast any spell from the Enchantment school—which ruled out any spell that had any sort of mind-affecting or morale-based effects. The real surprise was that they could somehow work around the protection granted from his amulet. That ruled out possession and mental control as things the Dementor could have done to him, which really made him wonder what it had done. How was forcing someone to relive their worst memories while you stole their best ones not mental control? Did chocolate really counter the Dementor's attack because of a property unique to chocolate—a property that could be exploited—or was it simply because most people liked chocolate, and that comfort was the counter? Would a favourite musical composition, perfume, or painting have a similar effect? Or was it that chocolate, specifically, had some sort of anti-Dementor property, in a similar way that garlic did for vampires?

"Hey..." Neville said, breaking Milo out of his reverie. He wasn't sure how long he'd been musing on the issue for.

"Yeah?" Milo asked.

"How come we haven't started moving, yet?"

Milo narrowed his eyes. The Dementor was long gone, and the lack of screams and impacts of fainting students hitting the ground meant that there weren't any more aboard the train.

"Dementors work for the Ministry, right?"

"More or less," Hannah said. "Although they're more like... extremely dangerous work animals than actual employees."

"Meaning they wouldn't send them out alone without a handler," Milo reasoned.

"Probably not," Hannah agreed.

"Can Dementors communicate with humans?" Milo asked. "Such as to—"

The compartment door slammed open, and a wizard and pair of witches entered, wands held out threateningly. Such as to report that they found a wanted person, he was going to say.

"Milo Amastacia-Liadon," the one in the front said in an authoritative tone, "You're coming with us."

"Uhm," Milo said. "Why? Other than the fact that you have wands out and I don't, of course."

"For your own protection," the man said. "I'm Kingsley Shacklebolt, with the Department of Magical Law Enforcement, and we have reason to believe that you're being targeted by dangerous felon, Sirius Black."

"That doesn't make any sense," Hannah cut in. "If Sir—if Black is after him, then surely the safest place for Milo is at Hogwarts?"

"This is not a request," Shacklebolt said. "I've been authorized to use force if needed."

Milo held his hands up. He had no spells, hardly any magic items, and no real hope of escape. He considered bolting out the window, but it was all open fields—he wouldn't get thirty feet before they took him out with a Stunner. One look at Shacklebolt and the others dispelled any notion of fighting his way out with physical force. They looked almost as tough as the Muggle police he'd seen.

"I'm coming," he said. Milo stopped, a sudden thought occurring to him. "Hey... none of you happen to be wearing one of my amulets, do you?"

"What are you talking about?" Shacklebolt asked. "No, and I'd suggest against any further delays. Get your things and let's get going."

"Yeah, I don't actually own anything, per se," Milo said. All of his possessions were in his Belt of Hidden Pouches—and scattered throughout bolt holes across the country, but he had no intention of tipping the Ministry off to their existence, if they didn't already know. "So that won't be a problem."

Shacklebolt gave him a weird look. "Fine. Let's go." He placed his hand on Milo's shoulder, and Milo was greeted with a distinctly unpleasant sensation not unlike being pulled through a Portable Hole backwards as they Disapparated.

o—o—o—o

Lucius Malfoy adjusted his robes in front of the mirror. Appearance would be critical, today. His pawns in the Ministry should be bringing in the freak momentarily, and he needed to be present. As a member of the Board of Governors, it was his duty, nay, his privilege to protect his students, and Milo was no exception. Why, he couldn't imagine a better way to do that than to suggest the boy be sent to a safehouse in, say, Egypt, or Nepal. Somewhere far, far away from the 'ruthless criminal,' Sirius Black.

He was interrupted from his thoughts by a knock on his manor door. Dobbie was out getting some last-minute school supplies for Draco, so Lucius went to answer the door himself.

"Hello?" he asked curiously, opening the door, but whoever had been there had already left. At his feet, however, was a large manila envelope addressed to him stamped with what had to be an unnecessarily large, red 'URGENT'.

Lucius picked it up curiously and examined it, searching for any indication as to who it was from.

"Who the bloody hell is Inland Revenue?"

o—o—o—o

Fiona smiled to herself as she hung up the payphone. Some problems, the government was content to sit on, moving at the barely perceptible speed of, well, government, taking little to no action. Other problems were simply conveniently forgotten about, or shuffled back and forth between departments and bureaus for so long that they may as well have been. But there was one very specific kind of problem that launched the government into action at speeds that would make Einstein sit up and take notice. This, she was quite certain, was one of those cases.

Lucius Malfoy, she thought, is in for a bad day. She wondered what the interest was on unpaid property taxes dating to before the Magna Carta, and whether it came with a prison sentence or not. The important thing, of course, was simply to get him 'on the books,' so to speak, like the Abbots had been. Running shady conspiracies is much harder when you're in the public eye.

Fiona flipped through the phone book and fished another couple of coins from her satchel. She still had a few more phone calls to make—this time, to the first red top tabloid listed in the phonebook.

Chapter 16: Safer Justice Practices

Lucius Malfoy winced as Tom Riddle slammed the Muggle tabloid onto the table, scuffing its immaculate finish. They were in Lucius's dining room, though Riddle had taken Lucius's customary seat at the head of the table. Bellatrix sat silently in the shadows, twirling her wand about her fingers. Aside from them, the house was empty.

"How could you let this happen?" Riddle asked. "Explain yourself."

Lucius glanced at the headline. MASSIVE COUNTRY ESTATE HIDDEN IN PLAIN SIGHT. And, underneath it in slightly smaller font: Weird Tree Found Growing out of Roof.

"I…" Lucius hesitated. How had this happened? The Muggle authorities had never troubled him before. What changed? "I'm looking into the matter, my lord," he said.

"It made the papers, Lucius," Riddle said. "The papers."

"I can take care of this," Lucius said.

"How?" Riddle said. "You can't Obliviate the entire country." Bellatrix glanced at Riddle, an unreadable expression on her face.

Lucius bristled, but he fought back his response. He couldn't stop himself from thinking it, though. Maybe if you hadn't Imperiused the Ministry's head Obliviator and sent his second-in-command to an alternate world with an ancient ritual, it never would have gotten this far. That was the problem with most so-called 'Dark Lords.' They're so blinded by the prospect of absolute power that they don't stop and think about how much day-to-day minutiae they're shouldering on themselves after liberating it from the powers that be. Someone has to keep the floo networks open, pay the owl post office workers' pensions, and keep the Muggle world from discovering the wizarding one. Driving out the Mudbloods and obtaining immortality is all well and good, but what's your ten-year economic plan, Riddle?

"Muggle news isn't like ours, my lord," Lucius said. "Three weeks ago they reported they saw Bigfoot in downtown London."

Riddle blinked. "That's ridiculous. Everyone knows Bigfoot never leaves Tibet."

"Precisely, my lord. Magical Britain only has one paper of note: the Daily Prophet." Lucius had gone through great pains to make certain that was the case. "Wizards and witches have no choice but to believe what the Prophet tells them. They have no other source of information. To Muggles, this is but one shocking scandal among many. Until it gets picked up by a reputable paper, no-one will take this story seriously."

"What's to stop just that from happening?" Riddle asked.

"I'll give them a bigger story." Lucius smiled slightly. "The bigger question, my lord, is who tipped them off. My home is protected by Charms; Muggles can only come here if they already know it exists." Other wizards liked to prevent Muggles from coming altogether, but sometimes Lucius found it useful to exert some influence on the non-magical who were nevertheless 'clued-in'—such as the parents of magical children, or certain Muggle officials—and there were few better ways to do impress a person than to show them a house such as this one. Or rather, there weren't until that bloody boy put that bloody tree through my roof… It would still take months to repair the damage. "One of our enemies has moved against us."

Riddle laughed. "No-one worth concerning ourselves over would attack us with Muggles."

Lucius was beginning to have deep suspicions about the 'Dark Lord'—beginning with why it was so easy to think of him as Tom Riddle, rather than by his title. He was growing increasingly convinced that Riddle hadn't simply returned with a teen's body, but a teen's mind, as well.

"'The coward in the shadows can be more dangerous than the champion in the light,'" Lucius quoted.

"Wise words," Riddle conceded. "Who said them?"

You did, right after Pettigrew sold out the Potters. "Merlin," Lucius shrugged.

Riddle held his fingers together in a narrow steeple for a minute or two, deep in thought. "Very well," he said. "You seem to know these Muggles well, Lucius." He didn't say it with any particular intonation or expression that would hint at it, but Lucius did not fail to notice the implied insult. "Find their source when you clean up your mess."

"Yes, my lord," Lucius said, bowing low. When he looked up again, Riddle was gone.

"For a moment, I thought he was going to off you then and there," Bellatrix said.

Lucius simply shook his head. "He needs me too much for that."

Bellatrix's eyebrows shot up.

"Why ever would the Dark Lord need you?" She said in a mocking tone, but hesitated for a moment. Lucius stopped and paid close attention to her—he couldn't remember ever having seen her show doubt before. "Did you notice anything a little… different about him? Other than his body, of course."

Like the fact that he's got the power of a living legend and the impulse control of a hormone-addled teenager? "No," Lucius said. This incarnation was infinitely preferable—and more easily manipulated—than the last. Bellatrix was feared and respected by the other Death Eaters, so he needed her loyal to Riddle. Significantly more feared and respected than he was. If she began to waver… "He does and says exactly what he means to, as he always did." Lucius wondered idly if there was any way he could arrange for her to be… martyred for the cause.

Bellatrix nodded dubiously. "How much do the taxmen want?"

Lucius told her.

"Is it still three and a quarter pounds to the galleon?" she asked.

"No. It's up to five."

"Blimey," Bellatrix said. "Still, wouldn't want to be in your shoes." She glanced down at his Italian leather loafers. "Shiny though they may be."

As Bellatrix left his office, Lucius realized he wasn't altogether certain he disagreed with her.

He turned back to the tabloid on his desk.

Who would stoop to using Muggles as a weapon?

o—o—o—o

Fiona adjusted her robes uncomfortably as she skimmed through the book in the aisle of Flourish and Blotts. She doubted she'd ever get used to robes. They were a little too much like dresses, which she never much cared for, either—far too much loose cloth to be grabbed if some street hooligan resisted arrest. She also wasn't entirely clear on what she was supposed to wear under robes. Did witches wear trousers under their robes? Underskirts of some variety? Tights? Fiona didn't know and had no real way to find out, so she did wore what she was sure any sensible person would, given the option: trainers, sweatpants, and a stab vest.

"…and all they found of him was his little finger…" Fiona mused. She kept coming back to that line. Was it rhetorical? Simply added for effect? But she'd seen it in the other books, too. Still, it was possible that one writer came up with it to add a little zest to the story, and others cited the first one, and then each other, until it became established fact.

But, well…

Fiona had some mates who'd fought in Kuwait, but even before that, she'd known that that just wasn't how explosions worked. They didn't just vaporize people—not at the scale of this one, at least. She'd seen enough movies to know that. The only real 'vaporization' she'd seen had been from Terminator 2, but that was an atomic blast, and a nightmare besides.

The wizards had passed it off to the Muggle world as an exploding gas line. Fiona remembered, because her cousin's boyfriend was among the twelve Muggles killed. (If her cousin was to be believed, he'd been a bit of a git, mind, so it was no great loss to the world). The footage from the news showing the devastation certainly made it look like a more-or-less conventional explosion, though the wizards could have faked that.

Fiona was tempted to just throw up her hands and say 'it's magic. There's no reasoning with it.' But all the books she'd found agreed that the spell had made a bona fide explosion, not some fancy magic-disintegration-blast-thingy or whatever. And that meant it had to follow some of the rules of a proper explosion, and simply deleting ninety-nine percent of Pettigrew's body from existence wasn't following those rules, especially because the other twelve victims had left, well, corpse-shaped corpses.

Oh, and this was after Pettigrew shouted that Black had betrayed the Potters to Voldewhatsit—though how that had entered the public record, Fiona couldn't say, because everyone present at the time had been promptly blown up. Then, who should stumble across the scene? None other than the Minister for Magic himself, who testified that Black was standing there, covered in blood, holding Pettigrew's finger, and laughing.

No, scratch that. He didn't testify, because there hadn't been a trial. Bloody Goering got a bloody trial, but not Black?

So, allegedly, Black killed thirteen people with a single spell in broad daylight, with twelve of them dead by explosion and one of them dead by spontaneous existential failure. Then, he was caught bloody-handed (so to speak) by the Minister showing every symptom of shock before being thrown into a prison whose guards steal happy memories (such as those of being, for example, completely innocent) before being given a chance to testify, which was bizarre, given that he was apparently the only surviving witness to Pettigrew's accusations of guilt, which, as they were not happy memories, did enter the historical record.

And all of this happened on the wizard equivalent of bloody V-E Day, with the Death Eater leader dead and his followers defeated or dispersed. Nobody was even close to paying attention to what was happening with Black and Pettigrew (other than the twelve dead Muggles, who were rather too close) given that news cycle. It was little wonder that nobody noticed the laughably thin case against him.

The question wasn't whether Sirius was framed. It wasn't even who was in on framing him. It was who wasn't in on it.

Fiona slammed shut the book, A History of the Wizarding War, and roughly reshelved it.

This wasn't even a bloody miscarriage of bloody justice. It hadn't even had the chance to get that far. This was a bloody contraception of bloody justice.

Secret communities and secret laws and secret prisons for secret crimes. It rankled.

Fiona glanced at her watch. She'd debated leaving it behind, being unsure if witches and wizards wore them, but decided it didn't really matter—even the magical community must have a few weirdoes. She'd just play it off as something her 'Muggleborn' friend got her for Christmas. (Did Wizards do Christmas? There was so much to learn.)

3:43. Damn. She'd missed another of her mandatory therapy sessions. Oh well; she'd deal with the fallout when this whole thing blew over. She wasn't quite sure what this 'whole thing' entailed, but it had something to do with Black, something to do with Malfoy, and something to do with Milo.

Fiona Smythe, Master Detective, she thought ruefully. She was pretty sure she knew whodunit, though she wasn't entirely clear on what they dun, or why they dunit. Which was exactly the opposite of the way you're supposed to investigate a crime.

She turned to leave, and accidentally bumped into an unknown witch and wizard. They looked vaguely like each other, with similar dark brown hair and heavy cheekbones. The wizard walked with a cane and had close-cropped black hair and a slightly surprised expression on his face. The witch was a stocky little woman with a mean look to her. She'd never seen them before (at least, she didn't think she had. Having a repeatedly-wiped memory could create all kinds of anxieties that her therapist was itching to discuss.), but something in her gut didn't like them.

"'Scuse me," Fiona murmured, looking down to avoid showing her face and trying to step around them.

"Watch where you're going," the witch snapped, then turned back to the wizard. "Now, where were we, Amycus?"

Amycus… Fiona thought, trying to walk casually out of the store. Why does that name ring a bell?

"Did that witch look familiar to you, Alecto?" Amycus asked.

Bollocks. Fiona remembered where she'd last heard the names Amycus and Alecto before. The Carrows. They'd been some of that Volder-fellow's most violent supporters during the so-called 'Wizarding War' back in the eighties, but had got off claiming they were bewitched. More recently, Amycus had been the bait that had led a lot of good people to their deaths in the London Massacre last year. She picked up the pace, navigating her way through the winding aisles.

"Yeah," Alecto said. "She looks a mite like Ash, doesn't she?"

"Who?"

"You know, our cousin, Ashley." Evidently, Amycus didn't know, because Alecto felt the need to clarify further. "The fat one." Fiona clenched her teeth slightly, despite herself. Fat?!

"Oh, Fat Ash!" Amycus said as Fiona reached the door. "No… she looked more like… tip of my tongue…" Fiona pushed the glass door open, causing the bell hanging above the door to sound out. She wasn't sure if it was the bell attracting his attention, or just bad luck, but just as she left the shop, Amycus and Fiona locked eyes. His narrowed in what Fiona prayed was not recognition. "…that Muggle Auror lady what shot me."

Now that was hardly fair. Fiona had no memory of the events of that disastrous raid, but it was on the record that her own firearm hadn't been discharged that night. The only 'Muggle' (Fiona hated that word) lady who had been doing any shooting that night had been Lyndon. It wasn't just that he'd made her; he'd made her as the wrong copper.

Fiona flung herself into a roll onto the muddy street as a pair of red bolts of magic smashed through the storefront's window after her. They went over her head and took an unsuspecting young witch in the street full in the chest. The witch went down without a word, unconscious. Well, Fiona hoped she was unconscious. She'd read that killing spells were supposed to be green, but Fiona wasn't willing to bet her life that just because a spell wasn't green didn't mean it wasn't dangerous. Also, for all she knew, wizards and witches just straight-up saw magic differently. Maybe red magic looked green to them. Or maybe the author of the spellbook she'd read was colourblind. On top of that, as a cop, she was well aware of the difference between 'nonlethal' and 'safe'.

She picked herself up off the ground and sprinted down the street as more spells flew after her. Just when she thought she'd lost them among the panicking crowd, they simply appeared directly in front of her. As in, one moment there was open space, and the next, bam. Two dark wizards. Or a witch and wizard, to be more accurate. It was bloody inconvenient not having a common, gender-neutral collective noun for persons of a magical persuasion.

"Shit!" Fiona debated turning around and running away, but she'd never make it—the street was starting to thin out, and the witchards would have a clear shot at her. Instead, she did the last thing anyone—including herself—would expect.

She charged them.

"Waaaaaaaagh!" She screamed. To distract them, of course, and not because she was terrified. She was a stone-cold fighting machine. Margaret Thatcher reincarnated in copper form. The Copper Lady. Totally.

Fiona collided bodily with Amycus, whose injured leg crumpled beneath him. She grabbed him by the hair and robes and rolled him over, to get her between him and his sister.

"Bloody hell!" Amycus shouted as Fiona wrenched at his hair. "Get her!"

"I can't get a clear shot!" Alecto protested.

Amycus awkwardly threw a punch at her chest, but winced as his knuckles hit her stab vest through the robes. Fiona seized the opportunity and slammed her forehead into Amycus's nose with a very satisfying crunch.

"So use a bloody Stunner, you stupid cow!" Amycus shouted at his sister, blood pouring from both nostrils.

"Right!" Alecto said. "Stupe—" Not wanting to risk the chance of getting hit, Fiona instead worked her feet under Amycus's torso and kicked him off her in Alecto's general direction. He slammed into Alecto's shins, not quite knocking her over, but definitely ruining the aim of her spell.

As Alecto was distracted, Fiona reached into her pocket, grabbed the tiny can of not-strictly-legal pepper spray she had concealed there, aimed it at the witch, and held down the button.

"Merlin's beard!" she screamed, clawing at her eyes. "It burns! She hexed me! She hexed me! She's a witch! It's the wrong bloody woman!"

"It's a ruddy potion, Alecto!" Amycus shouted, pulling himself to his feet. "She doesn't have a wand!" Amycus tried to aim his wand at Fiona, wiping blood out of his eyes.

The little pepper spray bottle ran dry, so Fiona whipped it as fast as she could over her shoulder and released her grip. It hit Amycus square in his already-broken nose at about Mach three. The dark wizard screamed and fell to his knees, then gasped again as he was reminded, painfully, that he'd recently been shot in one of them. His wand fell from his hands, and Fiona snatched it off the ground before it could be used against her again.

"Scourgify," Alecto muttered behind her. Fiona spun, trying to remember what that was a spell for. Hadn't she seen it in One Thousand and One Household Charms? It was the Scouring Charm. It was harmless. But why would Alecto cast a cleaning spell now?

A cleaning spell.

Fiona turned to find Alecto's wand held straight at her face. Alecto's eyes were perfectly clear.

Bloody magic, Fiona grumbled inwardly. It's not bloody fair. With that much spray to the face, she should have been incapacitated for ten or twelve minutes at least.

"Who the hell are you?" Alecto snarled, her wand hand trembling with anger. "How did you get here?"

Fiona had to supress an urge to roll her eyes. Alecto was carrying a tool that could act as a 100%-effective non-lethal incapacitant. There was no reason to threaten someone with it. Alecto could simply have stunned her, warped her somewhere dark and quiet using magic, and then threatened or ensorcelled answers out of her.

Something that had been drilled into Fiona during training was that disarming someone with a gun pointed at you is extremely risky. Someone shaking, scared, and amped up on adrenaline can pull the trigger in milliseconds. Technique was important, as was speed, because you had to do it perfectly on your first try, or you were probably dead. More important, though, was distraction. You needed your assailant's brain focussed on something other than you and their gun. Even something small, like talking or listening, could make a huge difference in their reaction time at the scales involved.

But wands weren't like guns. Guns, already aimed and loaded, were an instant away from firing. Fiona was willing to bet that in trained hands, a wand could be used to cast spells about as quickly as a gun could be accurately aimed and fired. But all of that time was on the leadup to the attack, with the incantations and whatnot, whereas, firing a gun, most of the time was after the bullet was fired, stabilizing the weapon and re-aiming after the recoil. Guns could even be fired after you'd grabbed it with both hands and still kill you, as long as the other person's trigger finger was still in place. But wands? Wands needed fancy gestures and twirls and swishes and the like. Precision, concentration, and grace. From what she understood, it was borderline impossible for a wand to 'go off' in a struggle and hurt somebody.

Fiona grabbed Alecto's wrist with her left hand and twisted, forcing her to drop it. Then she wrenched Alecto's arm behind her back, kicked her legs out from underneath her, and pinned her to the ground with her knee in the small of her back. Her right hand instinctively reached for her handcuffs, before remembering she hadn't had any since she'd been removed from active duty—and they'd be inaccessible under her robes, even if she was.

Even if she did, she couldn't very well arrest them in Diagon Alley—she'd never get them into London proper before the wizard police, or whatever they called themselves, arrived. Speaking of, Fiona wondered how long she did have before they got here. On the one hand, lack of phones would slow down communication, but on the other hand, they could simply beam over here Star Trek-style, which would more than make up for that. Fiona needed to make herself scarce.

Fiona reminded herself that Alecto was a hardened killer who had access to fancy magical healing besides, then lifted her head up by her hair and slammed it into the cobblestones. Unlike in the movies, people don't often conveniently fall asleep after moderate trauma to the head, so Fiona let her go and, using both hands, snapped her wand in half like a twig.

By this point, Amycus was still whimpering on the ground and clutching his nose, so Fiona decided to take the better part of valour and made a runner.

It wasn't until she'd sped through the Leaky Cauldron, earning a bunch of startled looks, out onto the busy London street, gotten several blocks away (almost getting hit by a city bus in the process) and into a crowded shopping mall that she let herself stop. She sagged against a wall, panting for breath and trembling as the adrenaline coursed through her system. Her bad leg spasmed wildly and she nearly collapsed.

"Jesus, Mary and Joseph," she muttered. That was way too close. She hadn't expected to see a bunch of Death Eaters in the middle of a book store, but, on thinking about it, why the heck hadn't she? Bad guys needed something to read now and then, too, and they'd already been exonerated by what passed for the wizarding world's justice system, so they were free to wander in public. She hoped nobody'd snapped a photo of her face, though, for all she knew, Alecto could just use magic to produce lifelike pictures of her from memory.

"Are you all right, ma'am?"

Fiona's eyes jolted open, and she reached reflexively for where her nightclub would have been hanging in normal circumstances.

A middle-aged woman with a heavy French accent pushing a baby carriage looked at her in concern. Fiona realized that she was still wearing her robes, and dozens of people were staring at her. She'd chosen the public place so that the wizards wouldn't follow her there, but hadn't fully considered how strange she'd look to the nonmagical residents in the city.

She swallowed, tasting adrenaline, muttered something about a fancy dress party, and staggered back into the street. She had to lean against walls and streetlights to compensate for her bad leg.

Stupid. She'd been stupid. She should have worn a mask in the raid on London like the Firearms unit had. She should have a better disguise when she went to Diagon Alley. She shouldn't have made such a scene when they found her, but instead denied it until the authorities arrived. She shouldn't have looked back into the bookstore as she'd left. She should have worn less conspicuous clothing under her robes, so she could take them off and blend in with the rest of the city. She should have had a getaway car waiting for her outside the Cauldron.

Fiona tried to hail a cab, hoping that all this wouldn't come back to bite her later.

o—o—o—o

"Then she bloody well broke my bloody wand!" Alecto practically shrieked. "I want her flayed, Malfoy! I want her skin!"

"You're certain it was the same woman?" Lucius asked calmly. "It was dark that night, in London. There was a lot going on. It would be easy to make mistakes."

"It was her," Amycus said, holding a bloody handkerchief to his nose. "Remember those fancy kung-fu moves she pulled on Selwyn? She did the same to us."

"This was right before Alecto accidentally killed him, was it?" Lucius asked. Merlin, but that whole night had been a string of fiascos.

Alecto bristled. "She threw him in the way of my spell. It wasn't my fault."

"So you're saying that an unarmed Muggle woman managed to best both of you, and get your wands?" Lucius asked. "Were I in your position, I would strongly reconsider what you 'remember' happening before telling the Dark Lord. He is not as… merciful as I."

"I was injured," Amycus said. "My leg."

"I was informed that the best healers in the country had given you a clean bill of health," Lucius said. "There's nothing wrong with your leg, Amycus. Any pain you feel is purely imaginary."

Amycus scowled, but said nothing.

Lucius leaned back in his chair. "I had been lead to believe that Lockhart had taken care of the Muggles that survived that encounter," he said. He'd been as surprised as anyone to see Lockhart taking credit for the Muggles' actions, but had decided to play along with it at the time. "But I now see that I was… mistaken to leave this matter in the hands of one outside of our little family."

"I want her, Malfoy," Alecto said again.

The Ministry made detailed reports of any incident that their personnel were involved in that resulted in violence, particularly when there were deaths. He felt certain that the Muggle law enforcement would do similarly. The records would be kept in a reasonably secure location, but that was no matter. A few threats here and Imperiuses there, and he could get through any amount of security. After that, it would be a simple matter to find out which Muggle personnel had been involved in the raid and track them down at their homes.

"You'll get her," Lucius said.

Chapter 17: Stones and Windows

It was evening, just after the Sorting Ceremony, and Milo lay against a tree by the lake. Milo had arrived at the tailing end of it, missing most of the actual Sorting, but hearing what passed for Snape's speech.

Milo heard soft footsteps approaching, making quiet crunching noises in the frosty earth. He didn't look up; he knew who it was.

"I thought I might find you out here," Hannah said. "Your hidden classroom was blown to pieces at some point. I'm guessing it was a surprise left for you by… the other you?"

Milo nodded. At some point last year, Riddle had apparently left Explosive Runes on the door to the classroom behind the giant tree that Milo usually used when he needed a secret area. Frankly, with his hit points being the way they were, Milo was lucky to have survived.

"Mind if I sit down?"

Milo shrugged, fingering a smooth, round stone in his hand.

"Whacha got there?"

Despite his mood, Milo flashed a quick grin. "Halfling skipping rock."

"Ooookay…"

"Halfling culture is inexplicably built around throwing rocks," Milo said. "They get all kinds of random racial bonuses to it, and a handful of race-specific feats. I bet, if I looked long enough, I could find a Halfling-only Prestige Class built entirely around throwing rocks."

Hannah settled into the grass. She'd learned that there was no point interrupting him when he was doing one of his Milo-y things.

"All of this is to say that when Halflings say that a rock is a good skipping rock, they know what they're about." Milo held the rock up into the light. "This one was probably ground down into an aerodynamically-perfect shape by Halfling children over the course of six months, or something. I found it in my sister's Belt of Hidden Pouches."

He gave it one last look, then flung it out over the lake at a shallow angle. It hit the water heavily and sank with an anti-climactic splash.

"Or maybe it was just an ordinary pebble Relkin picked up one day," Milo said. He coughed awkwardly. "I probably should have checked if that was magical before I threw it," he said ruefully. "For all I know, that was a Philosopher's Stone."

"Look, Milo," Hannah said. "I know sometimes that when I'm in a lousy mood, I want nothing more than to sit by myself and throw rocks into a lake. But late as you were, you heard what Headmaster Snape said at the Sorting Ceremony: we're not supposed to leave the castle. There's Dementors patrolling the grounds. That one on the Hogwarts Express did a real number on you. I think it focused on us because…" she lowered her voice. "I think they could… smell, or sense or whatever… him on us."

"Who says I'm in a lousy mood?" Milo asked, throwing another rock, this time an ordinary one, into the lake. It didn't skip, either. "Who says I even get moods? And if a Dementor does try something, I'll kick its shrouded ass from here back to Azkaban. I'm a Wizard. Not just any Wizard—a Conjurer. Of cheap tricks, no less."

"Right," Hannah said. "Because you never compensate for your own insecurities with reckless bravado."

Milo didn't have much to say to that, so he threw another rock into the lake instead without any more success than the others.

"Fine," Hannah said. She sat there silently next to him for a few minutes, watching him ineffectually throw rocks into the water. "You need to give it more spin," she said, finally.

"What?" Milo asked.

"Spin. Use your index finger to spin it as you throw." She picked up a rock, seemingly at random, and flung it effortlessly into the lake. It skipped three times. "I actually like my skipping rocks slightly oblong, because it's easier to spin them."

Milo shook his head. "Technique won't make any difference for me." He paused. "Well, that's not true. It's more accurate to say that I can't improve my technique without fighting and increasing in level. It's just a die roll, my Dexterity bonus, and half my level."

"Just try it," Hannah said. "Here, use this one." She passed him a muddy, irregular rock. The ancient Halfling rock-skipping gurus of old would roll in their graves looking at it.

Milo rolled his eyes, but took it.

"Get down low, close to the water. You want it to hit as close to parallel to the surface as you can."

"I know, I know," Milo said. "It's not like it's grapple mechanics."

"And spin it," Hannah reminded him.

"I was spinning it," Milo lied. He adjusted his grip the way Hannah showed him, bent down low, and flung it out over the water.

It skipped once, half-heartedly, then dropped into the water without ceremony.

But it did skip.

Milo could only see one side of Hannah's face, but he felt it safe to extrapolate, using his arcane knowledge and unparalleled intellect, that she was smirking on the other side, too. "Could have just been that I rolled a 20," Milo muttered.

"Uh-huh," Hannah said. "So, do you want to talk about it?"

"Talk about what?" Milo asked. "I'm a soulless construct. A collection of bonuses and penalties. I am without emotion." He skipped another rock. "And they'd only hold me back, even if I had them."

"You know that's not true," Hannah said. "So I'm not going to dignify the point with an argument."

Once more, Milo didn't have a heck of a lot to say, so he threw another rock into the lake. This time, he skipped twice. Hannah did the same, though her rock didn't so much skip as glide along the surface of the lake for a few meters before finally sinking.

"They thought I summoned the Basilisk," Milo said eventually. He didn't need to say who 'they' were.

"Yeah," Hannah said.

"They thought that maybe the Prophet got a few things right."

Hannah simply nodded.

"They think I'm dangerous," Milo said.

Hannah smiled. "All of those things are true, you realize. You did summon the Basilisk—unwillingly. The Prophet was right about a few things—again, mostly things you did unwillingly or accidentally. And you are dangerous." Milo had a brief memory of blood-red snow, but pushed it away. "You're among the most dangerous people in the world—top ten, top hundred at the least—to the bad guys. To people that want to destabilize the world, to persecute Muggles, Muggleborns, half-bloods, and anyone else who gets in their way. To people who hurt innocents because it's convenient. You're so dangerous, I bet you keep them up at night with a cold sweat."

"Didn't stop You-Know-Who from killing me," Milo muttered. "After using my power for evil. Maybe Hermione was right."

"You came back," Hannah said. "You conquered death. Nobody's done that before. Ever. You-Know-Who tried to do that his entire life, and it didn't work. Not really. And that probably scares him more than anything. But that's not what this is about, is it?"

Milo sighed. "They didn't trust me, Hannah. Harry, Ron, Hermione. They didn't talk to me. They didn't even look at me." He picked up a rock to skip, but set it back down instead. "It's so stupid. Why should I care? My friends believed the overwhelming mountain of evidence over… I don't know. Their unfounded, vague feelings of faith in me. Why should I be surprised by that? It's perfectly rational." He laughed grimly. "Wait till they find out I'm harbouring—" he glanced around, remembering Hannah's warning about Dementors. "Well, you know." He sighed. "Gods, I sound like such a Hufflepuff."

"There's worse things in life than Hufflepuffs," Hannah said. "You want a piece of advice?"

"No," Milo said.

Hannah ignored him. "Don't stew on it. Hermione tends to follow her brain over her gut, and she's had half a year to convince Harry and Ron. She can be very persuasive. But even she'll come around eventually, and they'll follow. You're not a bad person, and they'll see that."

"You're probably right," Milo agreed, though he knew it would probably take a while for that to sink in completely.

"Now, we should probably go inside," Hannah said. "Snape's just looking for excuses to dock points from Gryffindors, and that's not even getting to the fact that a Dementor could stumble across us at any minute."

"Good idea," Milo agreed. Just as he turned to leave, however, a thought struck him. "One second," Milo said. He picked up the most ungainly rock he could find—it was almost as big as his head, and lumpier than a troll's nose. It was probably the least aerodynamically-sound shape possible. "True Strike," he muttered, then flung it over his shoulder behind him as he walked towards the castle.

Splash-splash-splash-splash-splash-splash-splash…

"Cheater," Hannah laughed, and followed him.

o—o—o—o

Fiona couldn't sleep.

She was back in her own flat and out of cheap motels, but somehow, the normality of her own bed seemed unfamiliar. Sprocket, her enormously fat calico cat, was cutting off circulation to her lower body and purring like a chainsaw. Sprocket had no conception of the secret wizarding underground community that flagrantly flouted the laws of the land, with its secret laws and secret courts and secret police. And its own secret underground criminal organization of black-robed, Ringwraith-wannabe, 'dark' wizards and witches. As if the regular, memory-stealing witches and wizards weren't bad enough.

Her answering machine had been full of messages when she'd returned. The higher-ups down at the station wanted to talk about how she missed her mandatory counselling. Her mother wanted to know what she'd been up to lately, and why she hadn't called. Her landlord said her rent was past due.

Fiona rolled over, sending a disgruntled Sprocket rolling onto her back. The cat shot her a dirty look and sauntered off out of the bedroom, likely in search of any food Fiona might have left lying around the evening before.

None of it made any sense. She wasn't even sure why she was still digging at this. Once, she might have harboured illusions that she could simply find whoever was at the top of the little wizard community, cuff them, bring them round to the station, and be rid of all of this. But there didn't seem to be any one person who was the lynchpin of the secret underground magical world. It was systemic. Undefeatable.

Even if she did manage to arrest the people responsible for taking her memories, she couldn't very well charge them with anything. Nothing that would stand up in court, anyway. And if it miraculously did, no prison could hold a wizard or witch, anyway. Even without a wand, there was nothing stopping one of their mates from just popping in, snatching them, and popping out again with no-one the wiser. Or mind-controlling the prison guards. Or the judge and jury, for that matter.

Not that it would ever get that far, because this whole Sirius Black thing revealed that the Muggle government was co-operating with the wizarding one at some level. God, she hated that word. Muggle. Why did non-magical people need a special name? They were just ordinary people.

Fiona rolled over again to try to get comfortable, but only succeeded in tangling her face in her hair, which was getting way too long. When was the last time she'd got it cut? For that matter, when was the last time she'd washed it?

A faint creak pulled her out of her reverie, followed by a sort of quiet mechanical noise that Fiona didn't immediately recognize. She frowned, and pulled herself out of bed.

"Sprocket?" she murmured.

"—certain this is the correct hovel?" asked a voice like silk slick with oil. Fiona froze—someone was in her flat. The sound earlier must have been her lock being jimmied.

(And they called it a hovel. Who the heck does that?)

"Number 36, master. Just as it says in the Muggles' file," said a second voice, this one low and raspy. Well, that settled any doubt in her mind about who it might be: wizards. Were they here to take her memories again?

Fiona thought about her options. There were only two ways out of her bedroom—the door to her little living room-slash-kitchen, and the window to the street, three storeys below.

"What was that?" said a third voice, this one she did recognize: Alecto Carrow. The witch who'd spotted her in Diagon Alley earlier.

Meaning these weren't Ministry goons, and they weren't after her memories. Fiona crept towards the window. She'd only barely got away from these guys last time, and she didn't want to risk it again—especially not with anyone who they deemed worth calling 'master.' Probably this Malfoy guy that that kid told me about, she thought to herself. Was this revenge for the taxman thing?

"It was just a cat," said the oily voice.

The faint light shining through the crack in her bedroom door flashed red, and for a moment, Fiona's blood turned to ice.

Sprocket. She'd gone into the living room.

Red means stun, right?

She thought of her stupid, fat, needy cat in the hands of those lunatics turned her fear into anger.

It'd better mean stun.

"There's a second room," said the one with the oily voice. "She must be in there. Alecto, stay here and cover the door."

Fiona frantically fiddled with her window's latch, trying to get it to open. The blasted thing was older than dirt, and had been painted over at some point in the past.

She heard footsteps approach her door.

Finally, the latch gave, and Fiona shoved the window open. The nighttime chill cut through her flannel pajamas

"Did you hear that?"

Fiona practically leapt through the open window, grabbing the brick sill with her cold hands. She'd originally intended to climb down to the street, or even jump, but one glance downwards put paid to that plan. It was solid concrete below her (save for a spiky, ironwork-and-brick fence, which was less than heartening) and, aside from the little decorative brick rim running between the windows of her flat, there was nothing to grab onto to climb down. Besides, she wasn't about to leave her cat in the hands of these psychos. Instead, she shimmied along the crumbly brick sill towards the window in her living room. Behind her, she heard the door to her bedroom open fully as the two wizards entered.

She risked a glance up through the window, and saw a robed, masked witch—presumably Alecto—holding a still Sprocket by one paw, poking her with her wand.

Fiona took a deep breath, shifted her weight entirely onto one quickly-numbing hand, and knocked once on the window with the other before grabbing the sill again. She heard a soft thump that she guessed was Sprocket being put down (Fiona winced internally at her poor choice of words), before realizing that she'd staked her entire chances of survival on a move inspired by a comic book she'd read when she was thirteen, and was just contemplating how mind-bogglingly stupid that was, and if it was too late to risk the fall, when the window opened.

Alecto stuck her head out with her wand held out in front of her, which just went to show that dark witches didn't read nearly enough Batman as kids.

Fiona shifted her left hand into a more secure position by reaching through the now-open window and grabbing the ledge on the other side, then yanked Alecto by the front of her robes with her right hand and pulled as hard as she could, transferring as much of her weight as she could to the masked witch.

Alecto yelped as she tumbled out the window. Fiona let her drop—not that she had a lot of choice; if she'd held on she'd just get pulled down with her—and climbed herself up into her living room.

She sprinted forwards, scooping Sprocket up from where she lay on the floor, and out into the hall. Out of the corner of her eye, she saw a bright green flash, but seeing as how she didn't immediately die, she ignored it and kept running. She heard footsteps behind her, but didn't waste time looking around. Either they'd catch her or they wouldn't, but either way, she had no intention of slowing down.

On her way to the stairs—there wasn't a snowball's chance that she was going to wait for a lift with a pair of bloody evil sorcerers after her—she pulled the fire alarm.

Stale water poured down around her to put out the imaginary fires as she ran down the spiralling stairs. More importantly for her plans, however, were the dozens of panicked Muggles (there was that word again—it was creeping into her own mind) who came running out of their rooms in varying states of undress, some clutching valuables, others still pulling on dressing gowns. Fiona wasn't the only one with a pet—one couple was trying to get their confused golden retriever to follow them outside—though she was the only one with twenty-five pounds of soaking wet, catatonic cat clutched to her chest.

By the time Fiona reached the exit, she was already part of a growing mob of people fleeing the building. Secrecy seemed to be pretty important to these wizarding types, so she guessed her pursuers wouldn't try to make a move on her while she was in such a public gathering.

There was no sign of Alecto on the ground outside, so Fiona guessed she'd either landed in such a way as to be able to walk away, or had used magic somehow to slow her descent.

From there, it was a simple matter to disappear into the night, cat held tight to her chest, shivering in her soaked clothes.

o—o—o—o

Milo sat by himself in the Gryffindor Common Room with Thamior's really incredibly gross, bound-in-human-flesh spellbook in front of him. Everyone else had long since gone to sleep, but Milo still had work to do. Mordy sat across from him on the table, listening intently.

"This is going to be a problem," Milo said. "The spells in this book are, with a few exceptions, pretty much garbage. And touching it makes my Alignment shiver."

"So why don't you make a new one?" Mordy asked. He already knew the answer, of course, but he understood that his job right now was to be a sounding board (without sounding bored). This was by far better than most jobs wizards found for their familiars (which tended to be triggering traps from afar, or delivering close-range spells to dangerous monsters), so he decided to throw himself at it wholeheartedly.

Milo shuddered. "It takes a solid twenty-four hours to copy a spell from one book to another," he said. "And a hundred pieces of gold per spell level. And it takes weeks to research spells not present in the book. I don't have time for that."

"But you get two free spells added to your book every time you level up," Mordy said. "There's always the—"

"Ugh," Milo said. "Not the Dementor plan." Keeping a trapped Dementor to bump Milo down to just below the level up threshold in a controlled environment, so he could repeatedly level and de-level, was just too dangerous for the payoff. Not to mention that it would be hellish to experience.

"I don't see what the big problem is," Mordy said. "As long as your old spellbook still exists—which it does, wherever it is—you can just use your Uncanny Forethought to cast spells from it spontaneously. And there's always Spontaneous Divination, which lets you switch any spell you have prepared for a Divination spell, whether or not it's in your book."

"Divination spells won't fight off dark wizards," Milo said. "And Uncanny Forethought only works a handful of times per day. It's not enough." No villain Milo had ever before encountered had been low enough to take his spellbook away from him, so he hadn't really had any precautions in place for this event. It just wasn't done. "Maybe I should start tattooing spells to my body," Milo said. "I think there were rules for that somewhere."

"Complete Arcane, if I'm not mistaken," Mordy added helpfully.

"Right," Milo said. What were the rules for that again? He really should have taken the opportunity to drop by a bookstore in Myra (city of Light! City of Magic!) to purchase the most recent set of splatbooks available. The great western coasts near the City were dotted with colleges and towers full of Wizards working round-the-clock to push back the limits of the known rules of the universe. One of them, somewhere, was probably working hard to publish an updated version of the way tower shields, hiding, and cover interacted after Milo forced the hand of the gods in his raid on the palace.

"But you probably don't want to do that," Mordy cautioned.

"Why not?" Milo asked.

"Werrrrrllllll," Mordy said. "Let's just say, for the sake of argument, that You-Know-Who, having lived in your brain and knowing your weaknesses, chose to find and destroy your spellbook to keep you from refreshing your spells every day. If the spells were in a book, well, he'd just burn the book. But if it was written into your own skin…"

"…ugh," Milo said. "Consider your point made. Any day in which no-one tries to flay me is a good day." He sighed. "If only I could figure out how Riddle made that sentient book thingy. Then I could have a spellbook that could reconfigure itself into whatever spells I wanted. That would be so cool."

"Might as well wish to be able to do magic with a wand," Mordy said. "I think you'll just have to live with Thamior's spellbook for now, until you can figure out a way to locate what he did with your old one."

Milo resisted the urge to bash his forehead against the table. De-levelled and without a spellbook? "Maybe I had it backwards," he said. "Maybe this is the afterlife. I died, and I'm in Wizard Hell."

"Cheer up, boss," Mordy said. "Look at the silver lining. You can take this opportunity to more carefully think about your choices you made when you levelled up. How many people can say they got to hit Level Nine twice?"

Milo shrugged. "I guess I could probably rethink my choice of Feat," he admitted.

"…and Prestige Class?" Mordy suggested.

"Why would I do that?" Milo asked. "Rainbow Servant is fantastic. No prerequisites worth noting, no lost caster levels—remember, the text overrides the table, and despite what the table says (and the designers intended), the text clearly states you get spellcasting every level—and I get a couple random abilities. Nothing fantastic until tenth level, of course, but practically anything is better than going straight Wizard. A bonus Item Creation or Metamagic Feat every five levels does not count as a Class Feature. Wizards don't get anything else."

Mordy coughed, which was quite a feat in-and-of-itself, seeing as how rats, generally speaking, can't. "Nothing?"

"Nope," Milo shrugged. "Nothing."

Mordy rolled his eyes. "Oh, come on. Your Familiar—i.e., me—gets new abilities if you level up in Wizard!"

"Pffft," Milo said. "Better armour class? If it seriously comes down to that, we're already both dead. And what else—oh, yeah. Spell Resistance. Need I remind you that I'm the only person in this entire universe that your Spell Resistance would protect you against? Which conflicts with the only other thing, that being the ability for me to cast Scrying on you for free now and then."

"Don't forget the ability to talk to other rats," Mordy added.

Milo rolled his eyes in a manner eerily similar to how Mordy had done a moment ago. "The only other rat around here is Scabbers," Milo said. "And I can't imagine you'd want to hear anything he has to say."

"But—"

"Don't make me order you to go patrolling for remaining hidden Explosive Runes," Milo threatened. Mordy sighed, and dropped the issue.

o—o—o—o

"She got away," Lucius Malfoy said. It wasn't a question.

He surveyed the crowd outside. In a few minutes, the Muggles authorities would arrive, and they'd search the building.

"I bloody well know she bloody well bloody got a-bloody-way," Alecto muttered. "She threw me out the bloody window!"

"She took her cat with her, too," Avery added.

"Shame," Alecto said, hefting an iron poker from the fireplace. "Amycus's guitar—" As she spoke, she smashed a china teapot sitting on the mantle on the off chance that it was an antique. "—needs new strings."

"I think it may be safe to say that we underestimated her," Lucius admitted. "Amycus—"

"I'm Alecto," Alecto corrected, gathering as many treasured family photos as she could find and dumping them into the fireplace, which she lit with her wand.

"Actually, I meant to say Avery. My apologies." Lucius said. Why must all of my followers have names that begin with the same letter? I'd bet Dumbledore never has this problem. "Would you search this… residence… for anything that looks like a diary or notebook?" Lucius frowned. The Ministry would have done that the last time they'd erased her memory, as would Lockhart. "Actually, instead, locate any Muggle device that has a purpose you don't recognize and pile it somewhere out of the water. We'll Apparate it out with us when we're done." It stood to reason that the usual tricks to keep her memory erased hadn't worked. She had to have done something that was beyond the capabilities of the Obliviators to understand.

"Er… of course," Avery said, clearly not understanding, but complying nevertheless.

Alecto located a filing cabinet full of what she guessed was critically important, difficult-to-replace documentation—things like tax records, insurance information, identification, a birth certificate—and set that on fire, too.

"Oh, Alecto, do stop that," Lucius said. "It's unprofessional."

"I'm going to skin her alive," Alecto muttered, smashing some sort of martial arts trophy into dust with the iron rod. "Then I'll give her Polyjuice and turn her back into herself so I can do it again."

"Alecto—" Lucius frowned. Did Polyjuice work that way? He'd have to write Snape and ask.

"She threw me out a window!" Alecto snarled. "So don't tell me not to have a little revenge!"

Lucius rolled his eyes. "Alecto, there's no point in destroying her possessions—"

Alecto rounded on Lucius, teeth clenched, ready to fight.

"—because we're burning this place to the ground when we're done," Lucius finished. There were a few marginally pragmatic reasons for this, such as covering their tracks and inconveniencing his enemy. But none of those were the reason why he was doing this.

"Oh," Alecto paused. A series of emotions flashed across her face, not all of which Lucius recognized, and, of those, some of which he wished he had not. "Good."

The simple fact of it was that, with Bellatrix around again, he needed the Death Eaters on his side. An occasional act of arson now and again was a small price to pay to ensure Alecto's loyalty.

"We'll find her," Lucius said. "But for now, we'll go to the next Muggle on the list."

Chapter 18: A Better Story

A beat-up brown sedan pulled up next to the glass phonebooth, and Fiona practically leapt at the door. She found herself unable to manage even the simple mechanism with her numb fingers, however, and would have screamed in frustration had her chattering teeth not prevented her.

The man inside reached over and opened the door for her, and Fiona crawled inside, holding the still-unmoving Sprocket close to her chest.

"Jesus, Fiona," Travis said, stifling a yawn. "You look like Hell. What happened?"

"One m-m-m-minute," Fiona said, closing the door behind her and turning the car's heater to max. She tried breathing on her hands to warm them up, but couldn't tell if it was working.

"That dial hasn't worked since the mid-eighties," Travis said, passing her a brown paper bag and a thermos.

"W-what's this?" Fiona shivered.

"Coffee and a donut," Travis said. He reached over and unscrewed the thermos's lid for her.

"M-m-marry me," Fiona said, attacking the coffee in a way not unlike a grayscale Dracula might go after some screaming maiden's neck. She was starting to regain feeling in her extremities, and almost wished she wasn't. Her bare feet, especially, were so cold they hurt.

Travis simply chuckled. "So what's going on?" he asked. "And where are we going?"

"Ringwraiths jumped me in my sleep," she said between sips. "Barely got away. Not Batman fans. Begged 20p from a homeless woman to use the payphone. Aware of irony."

"It's finally happening, isn't it?" Travis said. "They're coming after us."

Fiona nodded. "They made me in London this afternoon," she said. Glancing at the car's clock, she corrected herself. "Yesterday afternoon." She buckled on her seatbelt. "Swing by my place," she said. "I think they'll have cleared out."

"Why's that?" Travis asked.

"One of them had the police file on the London incident," Fiona said. "I wasn't the only one who was there that night. I think they're going after the others. We need to make some calls."

They sat in silence as Travis drove. Fiona absently stroked Sprocket's fur, and glanced at the rear-view mirrors every few moments. She wasn't sure what she expected to see—as far as she knew, wizards and witches didn't drive—but it made her feel better. Marginally.

Sprocket flicked her ears on her own accord, which was encouraging.

It was while Fiona was looking for pursuers that she noticed something odd. "Hey, Travis—"

"I think anyone on the run from supernatural forces with me is allowed to call me Evan," Travis said.

Fiona rolled her eyes. "It's not my fault you have two first names," she said. They were partners for three months before she learned Travis wasn't his first name. It's how she thought of him, and it was far too late to change it. "Seriously, though. Doesn't something strike you as odd about the tops of those buildings?" She pointed at the row of closed, single-storey shops they drove past, silhouetted by a vaguely sooty orange glow.

Travis frowned, looking past Fiona out the side window. "Dunno," he said. "Same as ever."

"Yeah, but…" Fiona frowned. "We can see them. We shouldn't be able to; it's past midnight. It's almost as if…" She glanced out the other window; the rooftops were invisible in the darkness. There was only one thing that Fiona could think of that would backlight the skyline like that at this time of night.

As they approached her flat, her worst suspicions were realized.

The fire department was already on-site, of course—Fiona had pulled the alarm the better part of an hour ago, after all—but they should have left after they realized it was a false alarm.

Of course, at the time Fiona had triggered the alarm, there hadn't actually been a fire.

The street was cordoned off a safe distance in every direction as the firemen and women desperately tried to put out the inferno. Flames poured out of every window of what was once Fiona's apartment building, apparently unhindered by the efforts of the emergency services.

The buildings on either side of hers, which were so close they practically shared a wall, were, in defiance of all logic, completely untouched. It may have been Fiona's imagination, but she thought she saw the occasional green or purple spark among the fires.

Bloody wizards.

"Fiona, I…" Travis said hesitantly. "I'm so sorry."

She'd lived in that flat since she'd first come to Staines as a probationary constable almost five years ago. It was cramped, the rent was exorbitant, and the plumbing was unreliable, but it had been the first place that was really hers.

And now it was gone.

Fiona took a deep breath and tried to still her emotions. She could yell and scream and cry about this later, but for now, she needed to focus.

"Get us away from here," she said. "We'll go to your place and call Hannigan; tell him to warn the others. Neither of you were in the actual raid, so I don't think they'll be coming after you. At least not at first."

"Well, that's bloody reassuring," Travis muttered, putting his car into reverse.

The drive to Travis's home was uneventful. Fiona attempted to bite her nails, but was greeted with little success; at some point in the last few days, she'd chewed them to the quick without realizing.

She felt like her mind was running in circles. What was she going to do? She'd lost her home and, likely, her job. And, knowing the wizarding world was out there, she doubted she'd be able to hold down another one. How were you supposed to work a nine-to-five knowing what she did? Not to mention her ID, birth certificate, passport, credit cards. She shuddered at the nightmare she would have to go through to get those back… you needed a birth certificate to get a passport, and you needed ID to get a replacement birth certificate… ugh.

Also—and this was quite a big 'also'—scary people were trying to kill her. What could she possibly do to prevent that from happening? She wanted to live, dammit. She couldn't arrest them; they'd just magic their way out. She couldn't offer them anything they couldn't just use magic to get for themselves. She couldn't even go full vigilante and kill them—even if she had it in her, which she didn't—because she wasn't even sure who 'they' were, save that there were a heck of a lot of them. A fight was out of the question. In London last year, they'd managed to fight the wizards and witches to a draw, at best, and it had been at a terrible cost. Almost everyone who was 'in the know' had either sought an early retirement, like Hannigan, or moved on with their life, like Travis. Or died fighting, like Buckley, McTavish, Gibson, and Rose.

To Fiona's surprise, Travis pulled up in front of a cute little two-storey house in Little Whinging.

"Try to keep quiet," Travis said, opening the door and climbing out.

Quiet? Why would… oh. Fiona couldn't help it; the corners of her mouth quirked up involuntarily. "You live with your parents?" She blinked. "No wonder you always tried to get out of doing the night shift!" she laughed as she closed the door behind her. "You're on a curfew."

Travis pulled himself up to his full height, and declared in his most dignified voice, "For your information, it was lifted when I made sergeant."

"Well," Fiona said with a perfectly straight face, following him to the door. "As the man said: 'With great power, comes great responsibility.' But I'm sure you're up to it."

Travis rolled his eyes and unlocked the door. Standing just on the other side of the door, with her hand held out as if she was just about to turn the knob, was a middle-aged woman wearing a baby blue dressing gown. Travis's mother, presumably. She peered at the two of them through what were, quite possibly, the thickest glasses Fiona had ever seen.

"Evan?" she asked. "What…"

Travis coughed. "This is Fiona, Mum," he said. "Police Sergeant Fiona Smythe, that is. Fiona, this is my mum."

Travis's mother gasped. "This is Fiona?" she asked. She gave Travis a conspiratorial look. "That Fiona?"

Travis's cheeks coloured slightly, and Fiona found herself wondering what, exactly was entailed in being 'that Fiona.' "I have to make a phone call, Mum," Travis said. "It's urgent."

"Oh, of course, don't mind me," Travis's mother said. "Just try to keep your voice down—your father is still in bed. I'll just have a chat with Fiona here while you do." A look of horror dawned on Travis's face at this prospect, but he evidently chose flight over fight, and, in the blink of an eye, he'd vanished.

"Would you like a cup of tea, dear?" Travis's mother asked, leading her to the kitchen. "Or, ah, something stronger?"

"Tea would be fantastic…" Fiona found herself in the impossible situation familiar to all twenty-somethings, and the odd late teen: what on God's green Earth do you call your friends' parents? As a child, of course, the answer was obvious: Mr. and Mrs. Last Name, respectively. But now, as an adult, you were expected to call a fellow adult by their first name in familiar situations. Did this count as a familiar situation? Moreover, what was her first name? But it felt wrong claiming to be on equal terms both with a friend and their parents. And could she really call Travis's mother by her first name while she habitually called Travis himself by his last? Fiona took a stab at it, hoping she'd made the right call. "…Mrs. Travis."

"Oh, call me Olive," she replied, fishing out a pair of orange pekoe tea bags from a cupboard. Damn, Fiona thought. Swing and a miss. "So," Olive said with exaggerated casualness, "what brings you to our house? I hope I wasn't, ah, getting in the way of something."

Fiona felt her cheeks heat up. "No, no!" she protested. "Nothing like that!"

"Right, sorry, 'course," she said. "It's just that Evan talks about you all the time, and he's never brought home a lady before, so, I sort of figured…"

"Oh, god…" Fiona ran her fingers through her hair. "Probably nothing good."

"On the contrary," Olive said. The kettle whistled—it must have already been on before Fiona and Travis had got here. "He says you're the reason he made sergeant."

"'Course," Fiona said. "By getting sacked." As good as, anyway. Olive put a cup of tea in front of her, and Fiona took a sip, enjoying the feeling as the warmth from the mug spread through her hands. She was beginning to feel like she might, one day in the future, possibly feel warm again.

"He says you were his inspiration," Olive said. "He says you're the most dedicated person he's ever met."

Fiona choked on her tea. "He said what?"

"Mmm-hmmm," Olive said. "And more, besides. But if you're not, you know, together, then what… well…"

"What am I doing here in the middle of the night in my jammies?" Fiona suggested.

"Well. Yes."

Fiona took another sip of tea. "My flat burned down," she said. "Just me and my cat that got out. Travis—er, Evan—was kind enough to come pick me up."

Olive gasped. "That's terrible! Do you have anywhere to stay? We have an extra bedroom, ever since our Julie ran off with that Frenchman."

"I thought Tr—Evan said that his sister lives in Montreal?"

"Aye," Olive said.

"Montreal, where her husband is from."

"Aye."

"Montreal in Quebec."

"Aye."

Fiona dropped the issue. "I'm not staying," she said. She couldn't put this family at risk any longer. She might already have stayed too long. "I have to go to London."

"Well, then, at least let me give you some clothes," Olive said. "We can't have you running around like that. Julie was about your size, anyway."

Despite distantly recalling politely declining Olive's kind offer, Fiona nevertheless found herself, a few minutes later, in a practical, if unfashionable, wool sweater and jeans that were only a little oversized. A moment later, and Sprocket had been fetched from the car, wrapped in warm towels, and put on a sofa next to an open can of tuna and a bowl of water.

"Is she… quite all right?" Olive asked, poking the catatonic (cat-atonic?) cat.

"Just sleeping," Fiona said.

"Of course," Olive said, failing to conceal her skepticism.

Travis returned, having finished his phone call. His face was ashen, and he had a black backpack slung across his shoulder. "Er, Mum, mind if Fiona and I—"

"Say no more, say no more," Olive said, giving Fiona a wink. "I'll just be heading to bed, then. Got an early morning tomorrow."

As Olive left, Travis sat down at the table across from Fiona. His look said everything Fiona needed to know.

"It didn't go well," she said.

Travis shook his head. "I managed to reach Hannigan," he said. "And he said he'd keep trying to reach the others. But…"

"No answer from Lyndon, Baldwin, or Cooper?"

By way of answer, Travis only sighed.

"They could just be asleep," Fiona said.

"Yeah," Travis answered. "I called them each about a dozen times, but it's possible."

"Or they could have got away, like me," Fiona said.

"Possible," Travis said.

Fiona sighed. "I suppose we'll read about it in the papers tomorrow if not."

Travis nodded.

Fiona stared into her teacup. Could this have been avoided if she'd asked Travis to start calling the others before coming to pick her up? Or would it already have been too late? She hadn't been thinking clearly. It felt like it had been ages since she had been thinking clearly. If she'd let this whole issue alone, and hadn't ventured into Diagon Alley yesterday—was it yesterday?—would the London police have been safe?

For that matter, if she'd simply ignored that fantastical digital police report so many months ago, or written it off as a prank, how many would still be alive?

Travis reached his hand across the table and placed it on hers.

"Hey," he said. "We don't know what happened. We don't know if they're out for blood, or taking hostages. We don't know if they succeeded. We don't know if they're even going after the other coppers at all."

"But what if they did?" Fiona asked in a small voice. "I could have just left this alone. This is all my—"

"Hey," Travis said, more firmly. "Do I look like a child to you?"

Fiona blinked. "No," she said. "Of course n—"

"What about McTavish?"

"N—"

"Did you cuff Lyndon and drag her into that London flat with you?"

"Obviously not."

"Everyone who was there in London that day knew the risks," Travis said. "They knew what they were going up against. They knew that even if it was successful, it could get them sacked. They knew what would happen if they weren't. Hell, the London blokes were Authorized Firearms Officers. They knew from day one that there would be danger."

Fiona swirled her tea around. "Nobody knew, really knew, what was going to happen that night," she said. "Heck, they took our memories. We still don't. So don't tell me they knew the risks."

"We got those kids back," Travis said. "We know that. Who knows what would have happened to them if you hadn't kept picking at this."

Fiona continued staring into her slowly-cooling teacup for several silent minutes.

"So," Travis said, finally. "What do we do now?"

Fiona shrugged. "How should I know?"

"You always know. We've followed your lead, right from the start. I don't intend to stop now."

"Fat lot of good it did us."

"Don't give me that, Fiona. You already have a plan, and you know it."

Travis was right. She wasn't certain when she'd devised it, but she did have a plan—she'd even told Olive the first step in it.

"It's dangerous," Fiona said.

Travis rolled his eyes. "Tell me something new."

"And I'll have to ask you to do something really hard," Fiona said. "You won't like it."

"Anything," Travis said without a moment of hesitation.

Fiona took a deep breath. "You need to sit this one out," she said.

"Absolutely not," Travis said. "We're in this together."

"But we're not," Fiona said. "I went into that tenement, not you. They saw me, not you. They came after me, not you. They know my name, not yours."

Travis recoiled as if she'd slapped him in the face.

"You're out of it for now," Fiona said. "There's no reason not to keep it that way."

"I can make my own choices," Travis said. "I'm not afraid."

"You live with your family, Travis," Fiona said. "You'd be putting them at risk, too. Please. I won't let anyone else die because of me."

Travis stared intently at the surface of the table, visibly wrestling with himself.

"Fine," he said. "I won't get involved. Personally. But I'm still helping. This is non-negotiable."

Fiona blinked.

"Even if it's only manning the phone, or looking after Sprocket, or keeping an ear to the ground. Here," he said, passing her the black backpack. "I kept this packed in case I had to leave in a hurry. It's got a first-aid kit, flashlight, a couple of meal replacement bars apparently made by sadists, and a few other knick-knacks. Some money. Not a lot. Bit of wizard gold, too. I don't know what you're planning, but I doubt you can do it without lunch and petrol money."

"Thank you," Fiona said, and she meant it. She blinked again. "Petrol money? I don't have a car."

"Keys are in the bag," Travis said. "Bring it back when you're done. Er. And get a good running start before going up a hill. But be gentle with it otherwise, just in case you need a lot of car in a hurry. And don't try to turn on the radio unless you have a fire extinguisher on hand."

"Thanks," Fiona said again, putting down her teacup. "Best not get pulled over," she flashed a grin. "My license is likely ash on some bloke's roof now." She slung the bag over one shoulder. "I should go," she said, standing up. "Staying here will only put your family in danger."

Travis nodded, following her to the front door. He opened his mouth as if to say something, but hesitated. "Good hunting," he said eventually.

"Um," Fiona said, standing awkwardly on the porch. "I'm probably going to get sacked," she said.

"Nothing is certain," Travis said a touch too quickly.

"No, it's fine. I've earned it. The point is…" She looked away. She was no good at this. Joint locks and truncheons were much more her thing. "The point is, we won't be co-workers. And even if we are, I don't outrank you anymore."

Travis cocked his head sideways, clearly not following where this conversation was going.

"So, um," she said.

Travis blinked. Bloody useless, Fiona thought to herself.

"So, when I get back… do you want to, maybe, I dunno…" Just suck it up and do it already. "Grab a drink sometime?"

"We do that all the time," Travis said. "We did that last Wednesday, actually."

"No, I mean…" Arghhhhh. Fiona ran her fingers through her hair again. She felt like a bloody teenager. "You know. You and me."

"Sure," Travis said. "Only next Wednesday I can't; told Mum I'd look after my nephew."

"Jesus bloody Christ in bloody Heaven," Fiona muttered to herself. She raised her voice. "Look. I'm, damn well asking you out, you great lout."

Travis' eyes bulged practically out of their sockets. "Out? Like, out-out?"

"Yes, bloody out-out. Life's short and I'll probably be killed by Tim the ruddy Enchanter before then anyway. So what'll it be?"

"Um. Yes. Absolutely."

"Good," Fiona said. She stood there for a minute, feeling awkward. "I'll, um, be going now."

"Okay," Travis said. He looked like a person whose grip on reality was becoming increasingly shaky. "Um. Bye, then."

"Bye," Fiona said, and double-timed it to the car. In all the chaos, confusion, and fear, one thing was for certain: she was never, ever, ever telling another living soul about how that particular conversation went down. Fortunately, she'd have a long, solitary drive to London to work out a better story, or at least a less embarrassing one, in case any of her mates on the force asked.

Chapter 20: Auld Reeky

One might assume that, as quite possibly the wealthiest man in magical Britain, Lucius Malfoy would have a very large vault of gold, silver, and possibly even jewels at Gringotts. The goblin bank was the safest place in the world, bar none, to keep items of value, such as gold, silver, and possibly even jewels. After all, many of the wealthiest families possessed (or in many cases, used to possess) such hoards.

Lucius Malfoy had many dealings with the goblins of Gringotts, and in fact, he did retain a very large vault in their establishment. They provided many useful services for a nominal fee, such as handling the tricky business of converting wizarding gold into Muggle fiat currencies and transferring money safely and conveniently between different accounts.

Lucius had been told that the Malfoy vault was cavernous, that it boasted the greatest protections, both magical and mundane, that the world had ever seen. That any would-be burglar would find themselves in a state of nature with a delightfully Hobbesian flavour. All of that might even be true, though Lucius couldn't care less. He'd not once visited the Malfoy vault, and had no intention of wasting precious time doing so. None of it mattered, as the goblins' promised security was an illusion. Not that they lied—goblins never lie—but rather they were truthfully and earnestly answering the wrong questions. Lucius had no doubt that any erstwhile thieves of his vault would be burned by dragon fire, poisoned by deadly darts, drowned in acid, or befall some similar nasty, brutish and short existence. That much was true. Nevertheless, only a fool would keep any amount of gold, silver, and especially jewels there. Before doubting, first consider the example of Lily and James Potter.

The Potters, as Lucius understood, had one such vault, replete with requisite gold, silver, and, yes, jewels. They had hidden away their vast fortunes in the goblin bank to provide for their son in case of the worst. This, simply put, was idiocy. When William the Conqueror sailed to England, did King Harold lock up all of his swords and spears to keep them safe from the Normans? When the Luftwaffe poured fire and ruin on London, did Churchill squirrel away his Muggle flying machines for a rainy day?

The Potters viewed Gringotts as a parking garage; Malfoy as a superhighway. If it held so much as a single stationary galleon, it was because the rail carts, piled high with goblin gold, had dropped a coin or two as they zoomed straight through the cavernous, empty Malfoy vault and straight into the vaults of his backers, cronies, and investments.

The sort of idiot who thought that wars were fought by dangerous wizards and legendary wands probably thought themselves clever for thinking that every part of Quidditch was a distraction, save for the seekers and the Golden Snitch. In truth, Quidditch had very little to do with Quaffles, the Snitch, or even with the players themselves. Quidditch, like wars, was fought with money. The best managers and owners were those that bought the best broomsticks and the best players. They paid for these advantages by pressuring taxpayers to build bigger Quidditch arenas by which to further squeeze hapless fans of both teams. Whether the game was won or lost, tickets were bought.

Prior to the Wizarding War, Lucius had bought the land in Diagon Alley upon which Ollivanders' wand shop was built. The previous owner was a delightful old Squib who owed Amycus Carrow a king's ransom in gambling debts. Amycus had complained to Lucius over drinks one day about his difficulty in getting the money out of this destitute old man, so Lucius, ever the hero, swooped in to save the day. He bought the land for a thousand galleons, thus allowing the Squib to pay Amyucus and further cementing his loyalty to the Malfoys. More importantly, Lucius now had de facto control over the greatest wandmaker in magical Britain.

When people started disappearing in the night and the Dark Mark appeared over their houses, the wizards and witches of Britain got nervous. And, as is only natural, nervous people tend to arm themselves. The Ministry, under Lucius's urging, recommended in the name of public safety that all adults purchase two or three extra wands and keep them around their house in case of attack. Wand sales skyrocketed, so Lucius simply raised Ollivanders' rent accordingly. The eccentric wandmaker worked three hours for every one he had before the war, but it was Lucius who reaped the rewards. Lucius made some seven thousand galleons from this investment over the course of the war, with which he bought a pair of Italian leather loafers and a controlling interest in each of Wizarding Weekly, the Diagon Times, and the Owl News. Lucius shuttered all three the next morning, leaving the Daily Prophet as the only major newspaper left in the country, which he also controlled. With a monopoly on all sources of information, he hiked subscription fees while also doing everything he could to use the outlet to spread fear and confusion (which incidentally sold very well).

The good people of magical Britain—each one now sufficiently armed to fight all the hordes of Genghis Khan—were too scared to leave their homes, giving Lucius' masked colleagues free run of the streets. If it weren't for the Dark Lord's surprise disappearance after the Potters' deaths, victory would have been assured. As it stood, Lucius Malfoy came out of the war as one of the most powerful men in the world. The part of the world that mattered, at least. With this one project, a small example of Lucius's overall contributions to the war, he'd used his money to buy loyalty from the Carrows, spread fear and misinformation, and profit from his enemies' attempts to protect themselves.

All of this to say, Lucius was very, very angry as he signed the money order to divert funds from essential graft and bribery to instead convert to Muggle pounds with which to pay the leeches at the Revenue. Such was the force of his anger that the tip of his quill nearly penetrated the thin parchment as he dotted the 'i' in his signature. Taking a deep breath to calm himself, he folded the envelope and tied it to the waiting owl.

Someone would pay for this, and it wouldn't be in pounds or galleons.

Lucius glanced at the ticking grandfather clock and cursed under his breath. He was late for another ridiculous, late-night woodland meeting. He took one more breath, mentally said goodbye to such civilized conveniences as indoor heating and insulation, then Disapparated.

o-o-o-o-o

Their table was next to an enormous floor-to-ceiling window underlooking the imposing hill upon which Castle Edinburgh sat. It was far and away the best table in the house, and Fiona had to give an elderly couple a Look to prevent them from stealing it while she put in their order. Cops, on the whole, were quite well-suited to giving such Looks.

The children, Milo and Hannah, sat facing the window, their feet barely touching the ground. Fiona placed a steel card with the number '8' on the table and sat across from them.

When Fiona was even younger than they were now, her dad used to sit her right where Milo now sat after school while he worked on his book. She would read over his shoulder and complain that if she were in his story she'd do things very differently from his heroine, who seemed not to have read the parts where the villain told his minions his evil plot.

Fiona realized she'd never seen the castle from this angle outside of winter; her dad, she suspected, came here on chilly days to save on heating.

Fiona's smile faded.

"Lucius Malfoy tried to kill me last night," she said bluntly. "And he's been gunning for my co-workers." It felt wrong talking about such a serious subject with children, but Fiona was at her wit's end. It was Milo who had sent her chasing Lucius Malfoy in the first place—in fact, it was Milo who had clued her into the magical world at all for that matter.

To her surprise, rather than reacting with fear, Milo's face broke into a broad grin.

"First thing that happened when I came here is that Lucius tried to kill me," he said. "I think we have a lot in common."

Fiona frowned. "Came here? From where?"

Hannah interjected. "As a half-blood, I think I can explain this one best. I've got one foot in each world, so to speak."

"Fair point," Milo nodded, gesturing for her to continue.

"You're a Muggle," Hannah said bluntly.

Fiona nodded. "So I've come to understand," she said.

"I'm a wizard," Hannah said. "It seems to me that you know about the secret wizarding world, which people like me, but also people like Lucius Malfoy, are part of. Milo here… he's different. He's as different from me as you are."

Fiona narrowed her eyes. "Different how?"

"He's from another world," Hannah said. "But not another planet, as far as we can tell. More like… another universe. More Narnia than Star Trek, if that makes sense. Lucius Malfoy brought him here, but we think it was by mistake. We aren't sure why or how he did it."

Milo coughed. "Actually, I have some theories on that," he said. "I can share them with you later."

Fiona frowned. "So… Milo's not a wizard, then? I distinctly remember—okay, well, technically, my memory was erased, but I read a report of him doing magic at me. Which I wrote."

"Wellllllll," Hannah said. "That's where it gets… complicated. He actually is a wizard, but of a different kind. In much the same way that he's a human, but of a different kind. For example: I would be willing to bet that you could pull out a gun and shoot him in the chest and he'd barely even notice the first two or three bullets—but he's nevertheless physically incapable of swinging a punch more than once every six seconds. You should see him try to swat a mosquito; it's embarrassing. He just… stands there as it flutters about him shouting 'attack of opportunity!' whenever it tries to get away. Anyway, the details of how any why he's different aren't especially important; what matters is that ever since he got here, he's been fighting to take people like Lucius Malfoy down for good."

"But he's a child," Fiona protested, her mind still reeling from the discovery that there were different kinds of wizards, as if she wasn't already struggling to keep up. "As are you. How did you get caught up in this mess? Why aren't there adults to take on this responsibility?"

"This is war," Hannah said coolly. "We don't have the luxury of sitting on the sidelines just because we're underage. You-Know-Who—well, I'm assuming you know who—was brought down by a two-year-old. When we're talking about magic, there's more important things than age. There's still a lot we don't know about how Milo works, and Lucius knows even less. Our chief advantage is surprise."

Fiona nodded. "That at least I can understand," she said. "The three of us—Muggle, wizard, and… different wizard—have very little idea about each other's' capabilities. So this Malfoy guy," Fiona said slowly, "why don't the wizard police just bring him in?"

"He's rich and powerful," Hannah said bluntly. "Things aren't so different in the Muggle world."

Milo nodded. "But he's taking a backseat now," he said. "The new BBEG is Tom Riddle. He's a clone or something of the spirit of You-Know-Who who was kept in a book, possessed me for most of last year, and eventually killed me with my own wand, which I mostly just kept around for show. Keeping a powerful weapon that everyone but you can use is kind of a liability, it turns out. Now he's on the loose, killing people left-and-right, and bossing around his old gang. He only looks a few years older than me," he added helpfully, "but in book years, he's fifty or sixty years older."

Fiona spent awhile trying to process everything that Milo had just told him, and eventually capitulated. "Is this kind of thing normal for you?" she asked Hannah.

"No," she said. "Strange things, even by wizard standards, tend to happen when Milo is involved."

Fiona nodded. Eventually killed me with my own wand… what a world she'd dived head-first into.

Someone placed two hot chocolates, an espresso, and a handful of pastries on the table. Milo's hand immediately shot for the almond croissant, and Fiona couldn't help but smile. Most of the time the strange boy more closely reminded her of a child soldier than anything else, but every now and again his age showed.

"Oh!" Milo said suddenly. "Before I forget." He slipped a brown paper package across the table. "This is for you."

Fiona reached for the package dubiously and pulled at the twine holding it together. Inside was a monogrammed napkin ('HW,' presumably stolen from Hogwarts) wrapped around something small and hard—a necklace, as it turned out, with a tiny silver shield dangling on it.

"What's this?" she asked. "It looks expensive."

"Amulet of Protection," Milo said. "Best not ask what exactly it protects against; I couldn't be picky with alignments."

"…Alignments?" Fiona asked, eyeing the thing a little cautiously.

"It protects against all mental-based magical attacks," he said. "Also, it provides minor defensive benefits against, er, angels."

"Angels?" Fiona choked. Hannah showed no reaction to Milo's casual confirmation of the existence of angels; whether this was because such knowledge was common among wizards or she was simply inured to Milo's strangeness was unclear.

"Anyone Good, really. The important thing is the mental attacks. That means charms, enchantments, memory-affecting stuff, mind-control, you name it. Total immunity against all that trash. This particular one is guaranteed backdoor-free, accept no substitutes. Especially from the Ministry, because of, uh, reasons best not elaborated but that are definitely not my fault."

Fiona felt her eyes widen. "Immunity against memory charms?" she asked.

Milo nodded.

"What about past attacks?"

"Depends," Milo said. "I'm not sure if wizarding memory charms are 'instantaneous' or 'permanent' duration—if they even have a duration."

Fiona had the thing around her neck before Milo had finished his sentence.

She sighed. "Nothing," she said. "It didn't come back."

Milo shrugged. "Still, it'll help for next time."

"So…" Fiona said, fiddling with the silver shield. She didn't want to let on how disappointed she was. For a moment, just a moment, she thought she'd get her memories back. As impossible as it was, it seemed like with those memories, she might be able to return to her old life. "What do we do about it?" She felt decidedly uncomfortable deferring to someone less than half her age, but if she were brutally honest, she'd been in this alone for far too long. She needed someone to share as much of this burden with as she could.

"Do about what?" Milo asked.

"Malfoy. You-Know-Who."

Milo shrugged. "Fight our way up his ranks one-by-one, defeating ever more powerful cronies and henchmen as we ourselves increase in capabilities until we bring down the Big Bad Evil Guy himself in a climactic showdown? Preferably in a volcano caldera or a collapsing tower. Or a big underwater crystal dome thingy, that's a classic."

Fiona blinked. Once you scratched the surface, that wasn't too different from common police tactics. Well, if what scratched said surface was Narsil. "Start at the street level and work our way up," she mused. "Get them to flip in exchange for a sweetheart deal."

"I was envisioning searching their pockets for clues after the fact," Milo said in-between bites of croissant. "But I'm willing to compromise on the sequence of events."

Fiona shook her head. "But we don't have any leverage," she said. "We don't have the jurisdiction to make an arrest, much less a plea bargain."

Milo snapped his fingers, and a small flame appeared in the air just above his thumb. It didn't have any visible wick or fuel. "Where we're going, we don't need jurisdiction," he said darkly. The fire vanished as quickly as it'd appeared.

Fiona shook her head. "We play by the rules or I do this alone."

Milo scoffed. "The wizarding government's in the palm of Riddle's hands. I should know, I put them there. And your Muggle government is, frankly, way out of its depth."

Hannah coughed politely, having apparently been content to be silent to this point. "Milo, of all people, you should know that every rule provides an opportunity. Miss Smythe, we might not have the Muggle government behind us, but the bad guys don't know that. They know even less about how your rules work than I do, and I'm thirteen."

Fiona nodded. "I can work with this."

"Where do we start?" Hannah asked. "You said from the bottom. Who's the bottom? Draco?"

"Not with the kind of screen time he's gotten," Milo said. "I'd bet gold to copper that Draco's going down second-to-last. Probably after getting a never-explained eyepatch in a timeskip, and some black leather. Gotta have black leather."

"Alecto," Fiona said. It was almost a growl. "She stunned my cat. We take her first."

"Sounds good," Milo said. "I can find her with magic, but I'm already running a little light on spells. Maybe tomorrow?"

"We, uh, have a History of Magic quiz tomorrow," Hannah said.

"Right, school. Saturday, then?"

"She could be anywhere," Fiona objected. "I can't just magic my way to London or Hogwarts or wherever at the drop of a hat."

"Hrm. Neither can we," Milo said. "And I doubt we can fit all three of us on Hannah's broomstick."

"I have an idea," Hannah said slowly. "But I'm not sure you'll like it…"

o-o-o-o-o

There were eleven of them in all, standing in a frosty copse. Dark creepers and branches concealed them from the wider world and moonlit shadows of bare branches reached over them like skeletal branches. Puffs of breath escaped the narrow slits of their masks from beneath fur-lined hoods.

Lucius was certain that they were a menacing sight, though he was uncertain who, exactly, they were intending to menace given the secretive nature of their meeting. They'd been standing in the cold autumn night for nearly fifteen minutes, feet and fingers slowly going numb, when the final members of their group arrived, making a total of thirteen.

"Gentlemen," the all-too-familiar voice said.

Tom Riddle, barely a teenager, wore only a light school uniform despite the cold. Others were rubbing their hands together or holding their arms close to their body for warmth, but Riddle had his hood thrown back and his hands bare like it was a breezy spring morning. The weather didn't seem to touch him at all.

Behind him, Bellatrix Lestrange leaned against a tree twirling her wand between her fingers. She wore a heavy leather satchel at her side, a new affectation.

Lucius hated theatrics, but he gave credit where it was due: Riddle knew how to make an entrance. Whatever charm or potion he used to keep warm highlighted the difference between them, as mere mortals, and him, who had one foot in the door of immortality. Bellatrix's little wand trick was an unsubtle reminder that she had quite possibly the fastest wand hand in the modern world, and given that she was firmly on his side, they'd best not try anything.

Lestrange, returned from her imprisonment and later banishment, was a problem once thought solved. She represented something that was anathema to Lucius: true, selfless devotion. She had no levers, no weaknesses, no secrets and no higher ambitions beyond serving her master. In short, she, unlike the rest of the bunch, could never be bought. She was priceless to Riddle; worthless to Lucius.

"You don't have to all look so dour," Riddle smiled. "You should be joyous; we are on the eve of our final victory. The long war is nearing an end." It might have been a trick of the light, such as it was, or of Lucius' imagination, but Riddle's eyes seemed to flash red. "All I need now is the boy."

"The boy, Harry Potter?" suggested Amycus Carrow.

"No, you fool! The boy, Milo!"

"He'll be hiding in Hogwarts, my Lord," Bellatrix said. "Give me five expendable Death Eaters and I'll burn the place to cinders."

"And what of the professors?" Riddle asked. Lucius couldn't believe he was even entertaining such an absurd suggestion.

"That's why I need five Death Eaters," Bellatrix said, sounding slightly exasperated. "With sufficient expendable distraction, I can kill them all, one-by-one. None will survive to protect the boy."

"My lord," Lucius said as politely as he could, "Severus Snape is Headmaster."

Bellatrix rolled her eyes. "Fine, fine; I'll kill the rest and leave Severus. You're such a killjoy, Lucius."

"I mean, perhaps a subtler touch will suffice," Lucius said. "Through Snape, we have significant leverage over the school. Perhaps we can arrange for the children to be left vulnerable." Lucius gave Amycus a gentle kick, his movements obscured by the darkness and his robes.

"Hogsmeade," Amycus said on cue. "The kids go on field trips to the village. We can lie in wait, then boom. Grab them. No Hogwarts, no professors; there will be nothing to stop us."

"Hold up," objected Crabbe senior. "I had to sign a, what's it called, content form for my son to go."

"Yeah," said Goyle senior. "A contempt form."

"And that freak's got no parents," said Crabbe.

"Yeah," said Goyle. "He's got no mum or dad."

"That is a problem," Lucius mused.

"Snape!" said Alecto. "As Headmaster, he can make such concerns go away."

"What a great idea, Alecto," Lucius said. "What say you, my lord?"

"Do it," Riddle said.

"Consider it done, my lord," Lucius bowed. When he looked up, Riddle was gone.

"You've all lost your edge," Bellatrix snarled. "Except you, Lucius. You never had one to begin with." With a flash, she too, left, followed by other Death Eaters, one by one.

In the end, all who were left were Lucius, Crabbe, Goyle, and the Carrows.

"Excellently done, all of you," Lucius said.

"Boss…" Goyle said slowly. "You know, the other day, my basement pipe burst and flooded the house. I wouldn't bother you with it, but the missus says the carpets were ruined—you know, the nice Persian ones you got me? And the missus loves her Persian carpets…"

Alecto coughed. "And I've been going through wands at an alarming rate, and they don't come cheap, you know…"

"…and Junior wants a new broomstick," added Crabbe.

"Consider it taken care of," Lucius said. "All of you. Await instructions for the Hogsmeade raid. Your money is coming."

Without waiting for a reply, Lucius Apparated back to his manor. Confidence. That's what mattered. Nobody needed to know how thin he was stretched. Confidence.